<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cybertraining – DevOps</title><link>/modules/devops/</link><description>Recent content in DevOps on Cybertraining</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/modules/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Modules: DevOps - Continuous Improvement</title><link>/modules/devops/devop-ci/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/modules/devops/devop-ci/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Deploying enterprise applications has been always challenging. Without
consistent and reliable processes and practices, it would be
impossible to track and measure the deployment artifacts, which
code-files and configuration data have been deployed to what servers
and what level of unit and integration tests have been done among
various components of the enterprise applications. Deploying software
to cloud is much more complex, given &lt;em>Dev-Op&lt;/em> teams do not have
extensive access to the infrastructure and they are forced to follow
the guidelines and tools provided by the cloud companies. In recent
years, Continuous Integration (&lt;em>CI&lt;/em>) and Continuous Deployment
(&lt;em>CD&lt;/em>) are the &lt;em>Dev-Op&lt;/em> mantra for delivering software reliably
and consistently.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While &lt;em>CI/CD&lt;/em> process is, as difficult as it gets, monitoring the
deployed applications is emerging as new challenge, especially, on an
infrastructure that is sort of virtual with VMs in combination with
containers. Continuous Monitoring (&lt;em>CM&lt;/em>) is somewhat new concept,
that has gaining rapid popularity and becoming integral part of the
overall &lt;em>Dev-Op&lt;/em> functionality. Based on where the software has been
deployed, continuous monitoring can be as simple as, monitoring the
behavior of the applications to as complex as, end-to-end visibility
across infrastructure, heart-beat and health-check of the deployed
applications along with dynamic scalability based on the usage of
these applications. To address this challenge, building robust
monitoring pipeline process, would be a necessity. Continuous
Monitoring aspects get much better control, if they are thought as
early as possible and bake them into the software during the
development. We can provide much better tracking and analyze metrics
much closer to the application needs, if these aspects are considered
very early into the process. Cloud companies aware of this necessity,
provide various &lt;em>Dev-Op&lt;/em> tools to make &lt;em>CI/CD&lt;/em> and continuous
monitoring as easy as possible. While, some of these tools and
aspects are provided by the cloud offerings, some of them must be
planned and planted into our software.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At high level, we can think of a simple pipeline to achieve consistent
and scalable deployment process. &lt;em>CI/CD&lt;/em> and Continuous Monitoring
Pipeline:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Step 1 - Continuous Development - Plan, Code, Build and Test:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Planning, Coding, building the deployable artifacts - code,
configuration, database, etc. and let them go through the various
types of tests with all the dimensions - technical to business and
internal to external, as automated as possible. All these aspects
come under Continuous Development.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Step 2 - Continuous Improvement - Deploy, Operate and Monitor:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once deployed to production, how these applications get operated -
bug and health-checks, performance and scalability along with
various high monitoring - infrastructure and cold delays due to
on-demand VM/container instantiations by the cloud offerings due to
the nature of the dynamic scalability of the deployment and selected
hosting options. Making necessary adjustments to improve the overall
experience is essentially called Continuous Improvement.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Modules: Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>/modules/devops/devops-iac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/modules/devops/devops-iac/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="learning-objectives">Learning Objectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/learning.png" alt=""> &lt;strong>Learning Objectives&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Introduction to IaC&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How IaC is related to DevOps&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How IaC differs from Configuration Management Tools, and how is it
related&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Listing of IaC Tools&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Further Reading&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="introduction-to-iac">Introduction to IaC&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>IaC(Infrastructure as Code) is the ability of code to generate, maintain
and destroy application infrastructure like server, storage and
networking, without requiring manual changes. State of the
infrastructure is maintained in files.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cloud architectures, and containers have forced usage of IaC, as the
amount of elements to manage at each layer are just too many. It is
impractical to keep track with the traditional method of raising tickets
and having someone do it for you. Scaling demands, elasticity during odd
hours, usage-based-billing all require provisioning, managing and
destroying infrastructure much more dynamically.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the book “Amazon Web Services in Action” by Wittig [1], using a
script or a declarative description has the following advantages&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Consistent usage&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dependencies are handled&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Replicable&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Customizable&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Testable&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Can figure out updated state&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Minimizes human failure&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Documentation for your infrastructure&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Sometimes IaC tools are also called Orchestration tools, but that label
is not as accurate, and often misleading.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-iac-is-related-to-devops">How IaC is related to DevOps&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>DevOps has the following key practices&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Automated Infrastructure&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Automated Configuration Management, including Security&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Shared version control between Dev and Ops&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Continuous Build - Integrate - Test - Deploy&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Continuous Monitoring and Observability&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The first practice - Automated Infrastructure can be fulfilled by IaC
tools. By having the code for IaC and Configuration Management in the
same code repository as application code ensures adhering to the
practice of shared version control.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Typically, the workflow of the DevOps team includes running
Configuration Management tool scripts after running IaC tools, for
configurations, security, connectivity, and initializations.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-iac-tools-differs-from-configuration-management-tools-and-how-it-is-related">How IaC tools differs from Configuration Management Tools, and how it is related&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There are 4 broad categories of such tools [2], there are&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Ad hoc scripts: Any shell, Python, Perl, Lua scripts that are
written&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Configuration management tools: Chef, Puppet, Ansible, SaltStack&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Server templating tools: Docker, Packer, Vagrant&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Server provisioning tools: Terraform, Heat, CloudFormation, Cloud
Deployment Manager, Azure Resource Manager&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Configuration Management tools make use of scripts to achieve a state.
IaC tools maintain state and metadata created in the past.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, the big difference is the state achieved by running procedural
code or scripts may be different from state when it was created because&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Ordering of the scripts determines the state. If the order changes,
state will differ. Also, issues like waiting time required for
resources to be created, modified or destroyed have to be correctly
dealt with.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Version changes in procedural code are inevitabale, and will lead to
a different state.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Chef and Ansible are more procedural, while Terraform, CloudFormation,
SaltStack, Puppet and Heat are more declarative.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>IaC or declarative tools do suffer from inflexibility related to
expressive scripting language.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="listing-of-iac-tools">Listing of IaC Tools&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>IaC tools that are cloud specific are&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Amazon AWS - AWS CloudFormation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Google Cloud - Cloud Deployment Manager&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Microsoft Azure - Azure Resource Manager&lt;/li>
&lt;li>OpenStack - Heat&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Terraform is not a cloud specific tool, and is multi-vendor. It has got
good support for all the clouds, however, Terraform scripts are not
portable across clouds.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="advantages-of-iac">Advantages of IaC&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>IaC solves the problem of &lt;em>environment drift&lt;/em>, that used to lead to the
infamous “but it works on my machine” kind of errors that are difficult
to trace. According to &lt;span class="citeproc-not-found"
data-reference-id="WhatisIaC002">&lt;strong>???&lt;/strong>&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>IaC guarantees Idempotence – known/predictable end state –
irrespective of starting state. Idempotency is achieved by either
automatically configuring an existing target or by discarding the
existing target and recreating a fresh environment.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="further-reading">Further Reading&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Please see books and resources like the “Terraform Up and Running” [2]
for more real-world advice on IaC, structuring Terraform code and good
deployment practices.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A good resource for IaC is the book “Infrastructure as Code” [3].&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="refernces">Refernces&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>[1] M. Wittig Andreas; Wittig, &lt;em>Amazon web services in action&lt;/em>, 1st
ed. Manning Press, 2015.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[2] Y. Brikman, &lt;em>Terraform: Up and running&lt;/em>, 1st ed. O’Reilly Media
Inc, 2017.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[3] K. Morris, &lt;em>Infrastructure as code&lt;/em>, 1st ed. O’Reilly Media Inc,
2015.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Modules: Ansible</title><link>/modules/devops/ansible/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/modules/devops/ansible/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="introduction-to-ansible">Introduction to Ansible&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Ansible is an open-source IT automation DevOps engine allowing you to manage
and configure many compute resources in a scalable, consistent and
reliable way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ansible to automates the following tasks:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Provisioning:&lt;/strong> It sets up the servers that you will use as part
of your infrastructure.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Configuration management:&lt;/strong> You can change the configuration of an
application, OS, or device. You can implement security policies and
other configuration tasks.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Service management:&lt;/strong> You can start and stop services, install
updates&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Application deployment:&lt;/strong> You can conduct application deployments
in an automated fashion that integrate with your DevOps strategies.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="prerequisite">Prerequisite&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We assume you&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>can install Ubuntu 18.04 virtual machine on VirtualBox&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>can install software packages via &amp;lsquo;apt-get&amp;rsquo; tool in Ubuntu
virtual host&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>already reserved a virtual cluster (with at least 1 virtual
machine in it) on some cloud. OR you can use VMs installed in
VirtualBox instead.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>have SSH credentials and can login to your virtual machines.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="setting-up-a-playbook">Setting up a playbook&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Let us develop a sample from scratch, based on the paradigms that
ansible supports. We are going to use Ansible to install Apache server on
our virtual machines.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, we install ansible on our machine and make sure we have an up
to date OS:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ sudo apt-get update
$ sudo apt-get install ansible
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Next, we prepare a working environment for your Ansible example&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ mkdir ansible-apache
$ cd ansible-apache
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>To use ansible we will need a local configuration. When you execute
Ansible within this folder, this local configuration file is always
going to overwrite a system level Ansible configuration. It is in
general beneficial to keep custom configurations locally unless you
absolutely believe it should be applied system wide. Create a file
&lt;code>inventory.cfg&lt;/code> in this folder, add the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>[defaults]
hostfile = hosts.txt
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>This local configuration file tells that the target machines' names
are given in a file named &lt;code>hosts.txt&lt;/code>. Next we will specify hosts in
the file.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You should have ssh login accesses to all VMs listed in this file as
part of our prerequisites. Now create and edit file &lt;code>hosts.txt&lt;/code> with
the following content:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>[apache]
&amp;lt;server_ip&amp;gt; ansible_ssh_user=&amp;lt;server_username&amp;gt;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>The name &lt;code>apache&lt;/code> in the brackets defines a server group name. We will
use this name to refer to all server items in this group. As we intend
to install and run apache on the server, the name choice seems quite
appropriate. Fill in the IP addresses of the virtual machines you
launched in your VirtualBox and fire up these VMs in you VirtualBox.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To deploy the service, we need to create a playbook. A playbook tells
Ansible what to do. it uses YAML Markup syntax. Create and edit a file
with a proper name e.g. &lt;code>apache.yml&lt;/code> as follow:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>---
- hosts: apache #comment: apache is the group name we just defined
become: yes #comment: this operation needs privilege access
tasks:
- name: install apache2 # text description
apt: name=apache2 update_cache=yes state=latest
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>This block defines the target VMs and operations(tasks) need to apply.
We are using the &lt;code>apt&lt;/code> attribute to indicate all software packages that
need to be installed. Dependent on the distribution of the operating
system it will find the correct module installer without your
knowledge. Thus an ansible playbook could also work for multiple
different OSes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ansible relies on various kinds of modules to fulfil tasks on the remote
servers. These modules are developed for particular tasks and take in
related arguments. For instance, when we use &lt;code>apt&lt;/code> module, we
need to tell which package we intend to install. That is why we provide
a value for the &lt;code>name=&lt;/code> argument. The first &lt;code>-name&lt;/code> attribute is just
a comment that will be printed when this task is executed.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="run-the-playbook">Run the playbook&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In the same folder, execute&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>ansible-playbook apache.yml --ask-sudo-pass
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>After a successful run, open a browser and fill in your server IP. you
should see an &amp;lsquo;It works!&amp;rsquo; Apache2 Ubuntu default page. Make sure the
security policy on your cloud opens port 80 to let the HTTP traffic go
through.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ansible playbook can have more complex and fancy structure and syntaxes.
Go explore! This example is based on:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-install-the-apache-web-server-on-ubuntu-18-04">https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-install-the-apache-web-server-on-ubuntu-18-04&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>We are going to offer an advanced Ansible in next chapter.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ansible-roles">Ansible Roles&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Next we install the R package onto our cloud VMs. R is a useful
statistic programing language commonly used in many scientific and
statistics computing projects, maybe also the one you chose for this
class. With this example we illustrate the concept of Ansible Roles,
install source code through Github, and make use of variables. These
are key features you will find useful in your project deployments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are going to use a top-down fashion in this example. We first start
from a playbook that is already good to go. You can execute this
playbook (do not do it yet, always read the entire section first) to
get R installed in your remote hosts. We then further complicate this
concise playbook by introducing functionalities to do the same tasks
but in different ways. Although these different ways are not necessary
they help you grasp the power of Ansible and ease your life when they
are needed in your real projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let us now create the following playbook with the name &lt;code>example.yml&lt;/code>:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>---
- hosts: R_hosts
become: yes
tasks:
- name: install the R package
apt: name=r-base update_cache=yes state=latest
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>The hosts are defined in a file &lt;code>hosts.txt&lt;/code>, which we configured in
a file that we now call &lt;code>ansible.cfg&lt;/code>:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>[R_hosts]
&amp;lt;cloud_server_ip&amp;gt; ansible_ssh_user=&amp;lt;cloud_server_username&amp;gt;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Certainly, this should get the installation job done. But we are going
to extend it via new features called role next&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Role is an important concept used often in large Ansible projects.
You divide a series of tasks into different groups. Each group
corresponds to certain role within the project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, if your project is to deploy a web site, you may need to
install the back end database, the web server that responses HTTP
requests and the web application itself. They are three different roles
and should carry out their own installation and configuration tasks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even though we only need to install the R package in this example, we
can still do it by defining a role &amp;lsquo;r&amp;rsquo;. Let us modify our &lt;code>example.yml&lt;/code> to be:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>---
- hosts: R_hosts
roles:
- r
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Now we create a directory structure in your top project directory as follows&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ mkdir -p roles/r/tasks
$ touch roles/r/tasks/main.yml
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Next, we edit the &lt;code>main.yml&lt;/code> file and include the following content:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>---
- name: install the R package
apt: name=r-base update_cache=yes state=latest
become: yes
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>You probably already get the point. We take the &amp;lsquo;tasks&amp;rsquo; section out of
the earlier &lt;code>example.yml&lt;/code> and re-organize them into roles. Each role
specified in &lt;code>example.yml&lt;/code> should have its own directory under roles/ and
the tasks need be done by this role is listed in a file &amp;lsquo;tasks/main.yml&amp;rsquo;
as previous.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="using-variables">Using Variables&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We demonstrate this feature by installing source code from Github.
Although R can be installed through the OS package manager (apt-get
etc.), the software used in your projects may not. Many research
projects are available by Git instead. Here we are going to show you how
to install packages from their Git repositories. Instead of directly
executing the module &amp;lsquo;apt&amp;rsquo;, we pretend Ubuntu does not provide this
package and you have to find it on Git. The source code of R can be
found at &lt;a href="https://github.com/wch/r-source.git">https://github.com/wch/r-source.git&lt;/a>. We are going to clone it
to a remote VM&amp;rsquo;s hard drive, build the package and install the binary
there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To do so, we need a few new Ansible modules. You may remember from the
last example that Ansible modules assist us to do different tasks
based on the arguments we pass to it. It will come to no surprise that
Ansible has a module &amp;lsquo;git&amp;rsquo; to take care of git-related works, and a
&amp;lsquo;command&amp;rsquo; module to run shell commands. Let us modify
&lt;code>roles/r/tasks/main.yml&lt;/code> to be:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>---
- name: get R package source
git:
repo: https://github.com/wch/r-source.git
dest: /tmp/R
- name: build and install R
become: yes
command: chdir=/tmp/R &amp;quot;{{ item }}&amp;quot;
with_items:
- ./configure
- make
- make install
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>The role &lt;code>r&lt;/code> will now carry out two tasks. One to clone the R source
code into &lt;code>/tmp/R&lt;/code>, the other uses a series of shell commands to build and
install the packages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note that the commands executed by the second task may not be
available on a fresh VM image. But the point of this example is to
show an alternative way to install packages, so we conveniently assume
the conditions are all met.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To achieve this we are using variables in a separate file.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We typed several string constants in our Ansible scripts so far. In
general, it is a good practice to give these values names and use them
by referring to their names. This way, you complex Ansible project can
be less error prone. Create a file in the same directory, and name it
&lt;code>vars.yml&lt;/code>:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>---
repository: https://github.com/wch/r-source.git
tmp: /tmp/R
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Accordingly, we will update our &lt;code>example.yml&lt;/code>:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>---
- hosts: R_hosts
vars_files:
- vars.yml
roles:
- r
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>As shown, we specify a &lt;code>vars_files&lt;/code> telling the script that the file
&lt;code>vars.yml&lt;/code> is going to supply variable values, whose keys are denoted by
Double curly brackets like in &lt;code>roles/r/tasks/main.yml&lt;/code>:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>---
- name: get R package source
git:
repo: &amp;quot;{{ repository }}&amp;quot;
dest: &amp;quot;{{ tmp }}&amp;quot;
- name: build and install R
become: yes
command: chdir=&amp;quot;{{ tmp }}&amp;quot; &amp;quot;{{ item }}&amp;quot;
with_items:
- ./configure
- make
- make install
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Now, just edit the &lt;code>hosts.txt&lt;/code> file with your target VMs' IP addresses and
execute the playbook.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You should be able to extend the Ansible playbook for your
needs. Configuration tools like Ansible are important components to
master the cloud environment.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ansible-galaxy">Ansible Galaxy&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Ansible Galaxy is a marketplace, where developers can share Ansible
Roles to complete their system administration tasks. Roles exchanged
in Ansible Galaxy community need to follow common conventions so that
all participants know what to expect. We will illustrate details in
this chapter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is good to follow the Ansible Galaxy standard during your development
as much as possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="ansible-galaxy-helloworld">Ansible Galaxy helloworld&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Let us start with a simplest case: We will build an Ansible Galaxy
project. This project will install the Emacs software package on your
localhost as the target host. It is a &lt;em>helloworld&lt;/em> project only meant to
get us familiar with Ansible Galaxy project structures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First you need to create a directory. Let us call it &lt;code>mongodb&lt;/code>:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre style="background-color:#f8f8f8;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">$ mkdir mongodb
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Go ahead and create files &lt;code>README.md&lt;/code>, &lt;code>playbook.yml&lt;/code>, &lt;code>inventory&lt;/code> and a
subdirectory &lt;code>roles/&lt;/code> then `playbook.yml is your project playbook. It
should perform the Emacs installation task by executing the
corresponding role you will develop in the folder &amp;lsquo;roles/&amp;rsquo;. The only
difference is that we will construct the role with the help of
ansible-galaxy this time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, let ansible-galaxy initialize the directory structure for you:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ cd roles
$ ansible-galaxy init &amp;lt;to-be-created-role-name&amp;gt;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>The naming convention is to concatenate your name and the role name by a
dot. @fig:ansible shows how it looks like.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/ansible-galaxy-init-structure.png" alt="image">{#fig:ansible}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let us fill in information to our project. There are several &lt;code>main.yml&lt;/code>
files in different folders, and we will illustrate their usages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>defaults and vars:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>These folders should hold variables key-value pairs for your
playbook scripts. We will leave them empty in this example.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>files:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This folder is for files need to be copied to the target
hosts. Data files or configuration files can be specified if
needed. We will leave it empty too.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>templates:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Similar missions to files/, templates is allocated for template
files. Keep empty for a simple Emacs installation.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>handlers:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This is reserved for services running on target hosts. For example,
to restart a service under certain circumstance.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>tasks:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This file is the actual script for all tasks. You can use the role you
built previously for Emacs installation here:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>---
- name: install Emacs on Ubuntu 16.04
become: yes
package: name=emacs state=present
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>meta:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Provide necessary metadata for our Ansible Galaxy project for
shipping:&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> ---
galaxy_info:
author: &amp;lt;you name&amp;gt;
description: emacs installation on Ubuntu 16.04
license:
- MIT
min_ansible_version: 2.0
platforms:
- name: Ubuntu
versions:
- xenial
galaxy_tags:
- development
dependencies: []
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Next let us test it out. You have your Ansible Galaxy role ready
now. To test it as a user, go to your directory and edit the other
two files &lt;code>inventory.txt&lt;/code> and &lt;code>playbook.yml&lt;/code>, which are already generated
for you in directory &lt;code>tests&lt;/code> by the script:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ ansible-playbook -i ./hosts playbook.yml
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>After running this playbook, you should have Emacs installed on
localhost.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="a-complete-ansible-galaxy-project">A Complete Ansible Galaxy Project&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We are going to use ansible-galaxy to setup a sample project. This
sample project will:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>use a cloud cluster with multiple VMs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>deploy Apache Spark on this cluster&lt;/li>
&lt;li>install a particular HPC application&lt;/li>
&lt;li>prepare raw data for this cluster to process&lt;/li>
&lt;li>run the experiment and collect results&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="ansible-write-a-playbooks-for-mongodb">Ansible: Write a Playbooks for MongoDB&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Ansible Playbooks are automated scripts written in YAML data format.
Instead of using manual commands to setup multiple remote machines, you
can utilize Ansible Playbooks to configure your entire systems. YAML
syntax is easy to read and express the data structure of certain Ansible
functions. You simply write some tasks, for example, installing
software, configuring default settings, and starting the software, in a
Ansible Playbook. With a few examples in this section, you will
understand how it works and how to write your own Playbooks.&lt;/p>
&lt;dl>
&lt;dt>There are also several examples of using Ansible &lt;a href="http://docs.ansible.com/playbooks.html">Playbooks&lt;/a> from the official site. It covers&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>
&lt;p>from basic usage of Ansible Playbooks to advanced usage such as
applying patches and updates with different roles and groups.&lt;/p>
&lt;/dd>
&lt;/dl>
&lt;p>We are going to write a basic playbook of Ansible
software. Keep in mind that &lt;code>Ansible&lt;/code> is a main program and &lt;code>playbook&lt;/code>
is a template that you would like to use. You may have several playbooks
in your Ansible.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="first-playbook-for-mongodb-installation">First playbook for MongoDB Installation&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>As a first example, we are going to write a playbook which installs
MongoDB server. It includes the following tasks:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Import the public key used by the package management system&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create a list file for MongoDB&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reload local package database&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Install the MongoDB packages&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Start MongoDB&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The material presented here is based on the manual installation of MongoDB from the
official site:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://docs.mongodb.org/manual/tutorial/install-mongodb-on-ubuntu/*">http://docs.mongodb.org/manual/tutorial/install-mongodb-on-ubuntu/*&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>We also assume that we install MongoDB on Ubuntu 15.10.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="enabling-root-ssh-access">Enabling Root SSH Access&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Some setups of managed nodes may not allow you to log in as root. As
this may be problematic later, let us create a playbook to resolve this.
Create a &lt;code>enable-root-access.yaml&lt;/code> file with the following contents:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>---
- hosts: ansible-test
remote_user: ubuntu
tasks:
- name: Enable root login
shell: sudo cp ~/.ssh/authorized_keys /root/.ssh/
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Explanation:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;code>hosts&lt;/code> specifies the name of a group of machines in the inventory&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;code>remote_user&lt;/code> specifies the username on the managed nodes to log in
as&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;code>tasks&lt;/code> is a list of tasks to accomplish having a &lt;code>name&lt;/code> (a
description) and modules to execute. In this case we use the &lt;code>shell&lt;/code>
module.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>We can run this playbook like so:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ ansible-playbook -i inventory.txt -c ssh enable-root-access.yaml
PLAY [ansible-test] ***********************************************************
GATHERING FACTS ***************************************************************
ok: [10.23.2.105]
ok: [10.23.2.104]
TASK: [Enable root login] *****************************************************
changed: [10.23.2.104]
changed: [10.23.2.105]
PLAY RECAP ********************************************************************
10.23.2.104 : ok=2 changed=1 unreachable=0 failed=0
10.23.2.105 : ok=2 changed=1 unreachable=0 failed=0
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;h4 id="hosts-and-users">Hosts and Users&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>First step is choosing hosts to install MongoDB and a user account to
run commands (tasks). We start with the following lines in the example
filename of &lt;code>mongodb.yaml&lt;/code>:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>---
- hosts: ansible-test
remote_user: root
become: yes
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>In a previous section, we setup two machines with &lt;code>ansible-test&lt;/code> group
name. We use two machines for MongoDB installation.
Also, we use &lt;code>root&lt;/code> account to complete Ansible tasks.&lt;/p>
&lt;dl>
&lt;dt>Indentation is important in YAML format. Do not ignore spaces start&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>
&lt;p>with in each line.&lt;/p>
&lt;/dd>
&lt;/dl>
&lt;h4 id="tasks">Tasks&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>A list of tasks contains commands or configurations to be executed on
remote machines in a sequential order. Each task comes with a &lt;code>name&lt;/code> and
a &lt;code>module&lt;/code> to run your command or configuration. You provide a
description of your task in &lt;code>name&lt;/code> section and choose a &lt;code>module&lt;/code> for
your task. There are several modules that you can use, for example,
&lt;code>shell&lt;/code> module simply executes a command without considering a return
value. You may use &lt;code>apt&lt;/code> or &lt;code>yum&lt;/code> module which is one of the packaging
modules to install software. You can find an entire list of modules
here: &lt;a href="http://docs.ansible.com/list_of_all_modules.html">http://docs.ansible.com/list_of_all_modules.html&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="module-apt_key-add-repository-keys">Module apt_key: add repository keys&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>We need to import the MongoDB public GPG Key. This is going to be a
first task in our playbook.:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>tasks:
- name: Import the public key used by the package management system
apt_key: keyserver=hkp://keyserver.ubuntu.com:80 id=7F0CEB10 state=present
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;h4 id="module-apt_repository-add-repositories">Module apt_repository: add repositories&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Next add the MongoDB repository to apt:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>- name: Add MongoDB repository
apt_repository: repo='deb http://downloads-distro.mongodb.org/repo/ubuntu-upstart dist 10gen' state=present
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;h4 id="module-apt-install-packages">Module apt: install packages&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>We use &lt;code>apt&lt;/code> module to install &lt;code>mongodb-org&lt;/code> package. &lt;code>notify&lt;/code> action is
added to start &lt;code>mongod&lt;/code> after the completion of this task. Use the
&lt;code>update_cache=yes&lt;/code> option to reload the local package database.:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>- name: install mongodb
apt: pkg=mongodb-org state=latest update_cache=yes
notify:
- start mongodb
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;h4 id="module-service-manage-services">Module service: manage services&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>We use &lt;code>handlers&lt;/code> here to start or restart services. It is similar to
&lt;code>tasks&lt;/code> but will run only once.:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>handlers:
- name: start mongodb
service: name=mongod state=started
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;h4 id="the-full-playbook">The Full Playbook&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Our first playbook looks like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>---
- hosts: ansible-test
remote_user: root
become: yes
tasks:
- name: Import the public key used by the package management system
apt_key: keyserver=hkp://keyserver.ubuntu.com:80 id=7F0CEB10 state=present
- name: Add MongoDB repository
apt_repository: repo='deb http://downloads-distro.mongodb.org/repo/ubuntu-upstart dist 10gen' state=present
- name: install mongodb
apt: pkg=mongodb-org state=latest update_cache=yes
notify:
- start mongodb
handlers:
- name: start mongodb
service: name=mongod state=started
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;h4 id="running-a-playbook">Running a Playbook&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>We use &lt;code>ansible-playbook&lt;/code> command to run our playbook:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ ansible-playbook -i inventory.txt -c ssh mongodb.yaml
PLAY [ansible-test] ***********************************************************
GATHERING FACTS ***************************************************************
ok: [10.23.2.104]
ok: [10.23.2.105]
TASK: [Import the public key used by the package management system] ***********
changed: [10.23.2.104]
changed: [10.23.2.105]
TASK: [Add MongoDB repository] ************************************************
changed: [10.23.2.104]
changed: [10.23.2.105]
TASK: [install mongodb] *******************************************************
changed: [10.23.2.104]
changed: [10.23.2.105]
NOTIFIED: [start mongodb] *****************************************************
ok: [10.23.2.105]
ok: [10.23.2.104]
PLAY RECAP ********************************************************************
10.23.2.104 : ok=5 changed=3 unreachable=0 failed=0
10.23.2.105 : ok=5 changed=3 unreachable=0 failed=0
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>If you rerun the playbook, you should see that nothing changed:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ ansible-playbook -i inventory.txt -c ssh mongodb.yaml
PLAY [ansible-test] ***********************************************************
GATHERING FACTS ***************************************************************
ok: [10.23.2.105]
ok: [10.23.2.104]
TASK: [Import the public key used by the package management system] ***********
ok: [10.23.2.104]
ok: [10.23.2.105]
TASK: [Add MongoDB repository] ************************************************
ok: [10.23.2.104]
ok: [10.23.2.105]
TASK: [install mongodb] *******************************************************
ok: [10.23.2.105]
ok: [10.23.2.104]
PLAY RECAP ********************************************************************
10.23.2.104 : ok=4 changed=0 unreachable=0 failed=0
10.23.2.105 : ok=4 changed=0 unreachable=0 failed=0
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;h4 id="sanity-check-test-mongodb">Sanity Check: Test MongoDB&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Let us try to run &amp;lsquo;mongo&amp;rsquo; to enter mongodb shell.:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ ssh ubuntu@$IP
$ mongo
MongoDB shell version: 2.6.9
connecting to: test
Welcome to the MongoDB shell.
For interactive help, type &amp;quot;help&amp;quot;.
For more comprehensive documentation, see
http://docs.mongodb.org/
Questions? Try the support group
http://groups.google.com/group/mongodb-user
&amp;gt;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;h4 id="terms">Terms&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Module: Ansible library to run or manage services, packages, files
or commands.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Handler: A task for notifier.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Task: Ansible job to run a command, check files, or update
configurations.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Playbook: a list of tasks for Ansible nodes. YAML format used.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>YAML: Human readable generic data serialization.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="reference">Reference&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The main tutorial from Ansible is here:
&lt;a href="http://docs.ansible.com/playbooks_intro.html">http://docs.ansible.com/playbooks_intro.html&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can also find an index of the ansible modules here:
&lt;a href="http://docs.ansible.com/modules_by_category.html">http://docs.ansible.com/modules_by_category.html&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="exercise">Exercise&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We have shown a couple of examples of using Ansible tools. Before you
apply it in you final project, we will practice it in this exercise.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>set up the project structure similar to Ansible Galaxy example&lt;/li>
&lt;li>install MongoDB from the package manager (apt in this class)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>configure your MongoDB installation to start the service
automatically&lt;/li>
&lt;li>use default port and let it serve local client connections only&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Modules: Puppet</title><link>/modules/devops/puppet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/modules/devops/puppet/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Configuration management is an important task of IT department in any
organization. It is process of managing infrastructure changes in
structured and systematic way. Manual rolling back of infrastructure to
previous version of software is cumbersome, time consuming and error
prone. Puppet is configuration management tool that simplifies complex
task of deploying new software, applying software updates and rollback
software packages in large cluster. Puppet does this through
Infrastructure as Code (IAC). Code is written for infrastructure on one
central location and is pushed to nodes in all environments (Dev, Test,
Production) using puppet tool. Configuration management tool has two
approaches for managing infrastructure; Configuration push and pull. In
push configuration, infrastructure as code is pushed from centralized
server to nodes whereas in pull configuration nodes pulls infrastructure
as code from central server as shown in fig. 1.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="../images/IAC.jpg" id="fig:InfrastructureAsCode" alt="Figure 1: Infrastructure As Code [1]" />&lt;figcaption aria-hidden="true">Figure 1: Infrastructure As Code &lt;span class="citation" data-cites="hid-sp18-523-puppet../images">[1]&lt;/span>&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Puppet uses push and pull configuration in centralized manner as shown
in fig. 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="../images/push-pull-configuration.jpg" id="fig:push-pull-config" alt="Figure 2: push-pull-config Image [1]" />&lt;figcaption aria-hidden="true">Figure 2: push-pull-config Image &lt;span class="citation" data-cites="hid-sp18-523-puppet../images">[1]&lt;/span>&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Another popular infrastructure tool is Ansible. It does not have master
and client nodes. Any node in Ansible can act as executor. Any node
containing list of inventory and SSH credential can play master node
role to connect with other nodes as opposed to puppet architecture where
server and agent software needs to be setup and installed. Configuring
Ansible nodes is simple, it just requires python version 2.5 or greater.
Ansible uses push architecture for configuration.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="master-slave-architecture">Master slave architecture&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Puppet uses master slave architecture as shown in fig. 3. Puppet server
is called as master node and client nodes are called as puppet agent.
Agents poll server at regular interval and pulls updated configuration
from master. Puppet Master is highly available. It supports multi master
architecture. If one master goes down backup master stands up to serve
infrastructure.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="workflow">Workflow&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>nodes (puppet agents) sends information (for e.g IP, hardware
detail, network etc.) to master. Master stores such information in
manifest file.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Master node compiles catalog file containing configuration
information that needs to be implemented on agent nodes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Master pushes catalog to puppet agent nodes for implementing
configuration.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Client nodes send back updated report to Master. Master updates its
inventory.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>All exchange between master and agent is secured through SSL
encryption (see fig. 3)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="../images/master-slave.jpg" id="fig:master-slave" alt="Figure 3: Master and Slave Architecture [1]" />&lt;figcaption aria-hidden="true">Figure 3: Master and Slave Architecture &lt;span class="citation" data-cites="hid-sp18-523-puppet../images">[1]&lt;/span>&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>fig. 4, shows flow between master and slave.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="../images/master-slave1.jpg" id="fig:master-slave1" alt="Figure 4: Master Slave Workflow 1 [1]" />&lt;figcaption aria-hidden="true">Figure 4: Master Slave Workflow 1 &lt;span class="citation" data-cites="hid-sp18-523-puppet../images">[1]&lt;/span>&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>fig. 5 shows SSL workflow between master and slave.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="../images/master-slave-connection.jpg" id="fig:master-slave-connection" alt="Figure 5: Master Slave SSL Workflow [1]" />&lt;figcaption aria-hidden="true">Figure 5: Master Slave SSL Workflow &lt;span class="citation" data-cites="hid-sp18-523-puppet../images">[1]&lt;/span>&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Puppet comes in two forms. Open source Puppet and Enterprise In this
tutorial we will showcase installation steps of both forms.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="install-opensource-puppet-on-ubuntu">Install Opensource Puppet on Ubuntu&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We will demonstrate installation of Puppet on Ubuntu&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Prerequisite - Atleast 4 GB RAM, Ubuntu box ( standalone or VM )&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, we need to make sure that Puppet master and agent is able to
communicate with each other. Agent should be able to connect with master
using name.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>configure Puppet server name and map with its ip address&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ sudo nano /etc/hosts
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>contents of the &lt;code>/etc/hosts&lt;/code> should look like&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>&amp;lt;ip_address&amp;gt; my-puppet-master
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>my-puppet-master is name of Puppet master to which Puppet agent would
try to connect&lt;/p>
&lt;p>press &lt;code>&amp;lt;ctrl&amp;gt; + O&lt;/code> to Save and &lt;code>&amp;lt;ctrl&amp;gt; + X&lt;/code> to exit&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next, we will install Puppet on Ubuntu server. We will execute the
following commands to pull from official Puppet Labs Repository&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ curl -O https://apt.puppetlabs.com/puppetlabs-release-pc1-xenial.deb
$ sudo dpkg -i puppetlabs-release-pc1-xenial.deb
$ sudo apt-get update
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Intstall the Puppet server&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ sudo apt-get install puppetserver
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Default instllation of Puppet server is configured to use 2 GB of RAM.
However, we can customize this by opening puppetserver configuration
file&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ sudo nano /etc/default/puppetserver
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>This will open the file in editor. Look for JAVA_ARGS line and change
the value of &lt;code>-Xms&lt;/code> and &lt;code>-Xmx&lt;/code> parameters to 3g if we wish to configure
Puppet server for 3GB RAM. Note that default value of this parameter is
2g.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>JAVA_ARGS=&amp;quot;-Xms3g -Xmx3g -XX:MaxPermSize=256m&amp;quot;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>press &lt;code>&amp;lt;ctrl&amp;gt; + O&lt;/code> to Save and &lt;code>&amp;lt;ctrl&amp;gt; + X&lt;/code> to exit&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By default Puppet server is configured to use port 8140 to communicate
with agents. We need to make sure that firewall allows to communicate on
this port&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ sudo ufw allow 8140
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>next, we start Puppet server&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ sudo systemctl start puppetserver
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Verify server has started&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ sudo systemctl status puppetserver
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>we would see “active(running)” if server has started successfully&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ sudo systemctl status puppetserver
● puppetserver.service - puppetserver Service
Loaded: loaded (/lib/systemd/system/puppetserver.service; disabled; vendor pr
Active: active (running) since Sun 2019-01-27 00:12:38 EST; 2min 29s ago
Process: 3262 ExecStart=/opt/puppetlabs/server/apps/puppetserver/bin/puppetser
Main PID: 3269 (java)
CGroup: /system.slice/puppetserver.service
└─3269 /usr/bin/java -Xms3g -Xmx3g -XX:MaxPermSize=256m -Djava.securi
Jan 27 00:11:34 ritesh-ubuntu1 systemd[1]: Starting puppetserver Service...
Jan 27 00:11:34 ritesh-ubuntu1 puppetserver[3262]: OpenJDK 64-Bit Server VM warn
Jan 27 00:12:38 ritesh-ubuntu1 systemd[1]: Started puppetserver Service.
lines 1-11/11 (END)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>configure Puppet server to start at boot time&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ sudo systemctl enable puppetserver
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Next, we will install Puppet agent&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ sudo apt-get install puppet-agent
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>start Puppet agent&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ sudo systemctl start puppet
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>configure Puppet agent to start at boot time&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ sudo systemctl enable puppet
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>next, we need to change Puppet agent config file so that it can connect
to Puppet master and communicate&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ sudo nano /etc/puppetlabs/puppet/puppet.conf
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>configuration file will be opened in an editor. Add following sections
in file&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>[main]
certname = &amp;lt;puppet-agent&amp;gt;
server = &amp;lt;my-puppet-server&amp;gt;
[agent]
server = &amp;lt;my-puppet-server&amp;gt;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Note: my-puppet-server is the name that we have set up in /etc/hosts
file while installing Puppet server. And certname is the name of the
certificate&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Puppet agent sends certificate signing request to Puppet server when it
connects first time. After signing request, Puppet server trusts and
identifies agent for managing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>execute following command on Puppet Master in order to see all incoming
cerficate signing requests&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ sudo /opt/puppetlabs/bin/puppet cert list
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>we will see something like&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ sudo /opt/puppetlabs/bin/puppet cert list
&amp;quot;puppet-agent&amp;quot; (SHA256) 7B:C1:FA:73:7A:35:00:93:AF:9F:42:05:77:9B:
05:09:2F:EA:15:A7:5C:C9:D7:2F:D7:4F:37:A8:6E:3C:FF:6B
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Note that puppet-agent is the name that we have configured for
certname in puppet.conf file*&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>After validating that request is from valid and trusted agent, we sign
the request&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ sudo /opt/puppetlabs/bin/puppet cert sign puppet-agent
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>we will see message saying certificate was signed if successful&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ sudo /opt/puppetlabs/bin/puppet cert sign puppet-agent
Signing Certificate Request for:
&amp;quot;puppet-agent&amp;quot; (SHA256) 7B:C1:FA:73:7A:35:00:93:AF:9F:42:05:77:9B:05:09:2F:
EA:15:A7:5C:C9:D7:2F:D7:4F:37:A8:6E:3C:FF:6B
Notice: Signed certificate request for puppet-agent
Notice: Removing file Puppet::SSL::CertificateRequest puppet-agent
at '/etc/puppetlabs/puppet/ssl/ca/requests/puppet-agent.pem'
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Next, we will verify installation and make sure that Puppet server is
able to push configuration to agent. Puppet uses domian specific
language code written in manifests ( .pp ) file&lt;/p>
&lt;p>create default manifest site.pp file&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ sudo nano /etc/puppetlabs/code/environments/production/manifests/site.pp
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>This will open file in edit mode. Make following changes to this file&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>file {'/tmp/it_works.txt': # resource type file and filename
ensure =&amp;gt; present, # make sure it exists
mode =&amp;gt; '0644', # file permissions
content =&amp;gt; &amp;quot;It works!\n&amp;quot;, # Print the eth0 IP fact
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>domain specific language is used to create it_works.txt file inside
/tmp directory on agent node. ensure directive make sure that file is
present. It creates one if file is removed. mode directive specifies
that process has write permission on file to make changes. content
directive is used to define content of the changes applied
[hid-sp18-523-open]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>next, we test the installation on single node&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>sudo /opt/puppetlabs/bin/puppet agent --test
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>successfull verification will display&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>Info: Using configured environment 'production'
Info: Retrieving pluginfacts
Info: Retrieving plugin
Info: Caching catalog for puppet-agent
Info: Applying configuration version '1548305548'
Notice: /Stage[main]/Main/File[/tmp/it_works.txt]/content:
--- /tmp/it_works.txt 2019-01-27 02:32:49.810181594 +0000
+++ /tmp/puppet-file20190124-9628-1vy51gg 2019-01-27 02:52:28.717734377 +0000
@@ -0,0 +1 @@
+it works!
Info: Computing checksum on file /tmp/it_works.txt
Info: /Stage[main]/Main/File[/tmp/it_works.txt]: Filebucketed /tmp/it_works.txt
to puppet with sum d41d8cd98f00b204e9800998ecf8427e
Notice: /Stage[main]/Main/File[/tmp/it_works.txt]/content: content
changed '{md5}d41d8cd98f00b204e9800998ecf8427e' to '{md5}0375aad9b9f3905d3c545b500e871aca'
Info: Creating state file /opt/puppetlabs/puppet/cache/state/state.yaml
Notice: Applied catalog in 0.13 seconds
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;h2 id="installation-of-puppet-enterprise">Installation of Puppet Enterprise&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>First, download &lt;code>ubuntu-&amp;lt;version and arch&amp;gt;.tar.gz&lt;/code> and CPG signature
file on Ubuntu VM&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Second, we import Puppet public key&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ wget -O - https://downloads.puppetlabs.com/puppet-gpg-signing-key.pub | gpg --import
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>we will see ouput as&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>--2019-02-03 14:02:54-- https://downloads.puppetlabs.com/puppet-gpg-signing-key.pub
Resolving downloads.puppetlabs.com
(downloads.puppetlabs.com)... 2600:9000:201a:b800:10:d91b:7380:93a1
, 2600:9000:201a:800:10:d91b:7380:93a1, 2600:9000:201a:be00:10:d91b:7380:93a1, ...
Connecting to downloads.puppetlabs.com (downloads.puppetlabs.com)
|2600:9000:201a:b800:10:d91b:7380:93a1|:443... connected.
HTTP request sent, awaiting response... 200 OK
Length: 3139 (3.1K) [binary/octet-stream]
Saving to: ‘STDOUT’
- 100%[===================&amp;gt;] 3.07K --.-KB/s in 0s
2019-02-03 14:02:54 (618 MB/s) - written to stdout [3139/3139]
gpg: key 7F438280EF8D349F: &amp;quot;Puppet, Inc. Release Key
(Puppet, Inc. Release Key) &amp;lt;release@puppet.com&amp;gt;&amp;quot; not changed
gpg: Total number processed: 1
gpg: unchanged: 1
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Third, we print fingerprint of used key&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ gpg --fingerprint 0x7F438280EF8D349F
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>we will see successful output as&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>pub rsa4096 2016-08-18 [SC] [expires: 2021-08-17]
6F6B 1550 9CF8 E59E 6E46 9F32 7F43 8280 EF8D 349F
uid [ unknown] Puppet, Inc. Release Key
(Puppet, Inc. Release Key) &amp;lt;release@puppet.com&amp;gt;
sub rsa4096 2016-08-18 [E] [expires: 2021-08-17]
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Fourth, we verify release signature of installed package&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ gpg --verify puppet-enterprise-VERSION-PLATFORM.tar.gz.asc
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>successful output will show as&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>gpg: assuming signed data in 'puppet-enterprise-2019.0.2-ubuntu-18.04-amd64.tar.gz'
gpg: Signature made Fri 25 Jan 2019 02:03:23 PM EST
gpg: using RSA key 7F438280EF8D349F
gpg: Good signature from &amp;quot;Puppet, Inc. Release Key
(Puppet, Inc. Release Key) &amp;lt;release@puppet.com&amp;gt;&amp;quot; [unknown]
gpg: WARNING: This key is not certified with a trusted signature!
gpg: There is no indication that the signature belongs to the owner.
Primary key fingerprint: 6F6B 1550 9CF8 E59E 6E46 9F32 7F43 8280 EF8D 349
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Next, we need to unpack installation tarball. Store location of path in
&lt;code>$TARBALL&lt;/code> variable. This variable will be used in our installation.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ export TARBALL=path of tarball file
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>then, we extract tarball&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ tar -xf $TARBALL
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Next, we run installer from installer directory&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ sudo ./puppet-enterprise-installer
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>This will ask us to chose installation option; we could chose from
guided installation or text based installation&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>~/pe/puppet-enterprise-2019.0.2-ubuntu-18.04-amd64
$ sudo ./puppet-enterprise-installer
~/pe/puppet-enterprise-2019.0.2-ubuntu-18.04-amd64
~/pe/puppet-enterprise-2019.0.2-ubuntu-18.04-amd64
=============================================================
Puppet Enterprise Installer
=============================================================
## Installer analytics are enabled by default.
## To disable, set the DISABLE_ANALYTICS environment variable and rerun
this script.
For example, &amp;quot;sudo DISABLE_ANALYTICS=1 ./puppet-enterprise-installer&amp;quot;.
## If puppet_enterprise::send_analytics_data is set to false in your
existing pe.conf, this is not necessary and analytics will be disabled.
Puppet Enterprise offers three different methods of installation.
[1] Express Installation (Recommended)
This method will install PE and provide you with a link at the end
of the installation to reset your PE console admin password
Make sure to click on the link and reset your password before proceeding
to use PE
[2] Text-mode Install
This method will open your EDITOR (vi) with a PE config file (pe.conf)
for you to edit before you proceed with installation.
The pe.conf file is a HOCON formatted file that declares parameters
and values needed to install and configure PE.
We recommend that you review it carefully before proceeding.
[3] Graphical-mode Install
This method will install and configure a temporary webserver to walk
you through the various configuration options.
NOTE: This method requires you to be able to access port 3000 on this
machine from your desktop web browser.
=============================================================
How to proceed? [1]:
-------------------------------------------------------------------
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Press 3 for web based Graphic-mode-Install&lt;/p>
&lt;p>when successfull, we will see output as&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>## We're preparing the Web Installer...
2019-02-02T20:01:39.677-05:00 Running command:
mkdir -p /opt/puppetlabs/puppet/share/installer/installer
2019-02-02T20:01:39.685-05:00 Running command:
cp -pR /home/ritesh/pe/puppet-enterprise-2019.0.2-ubuntu-18.04-amd64/*
/opt/puppetlabs/puppet/share/installer/installer/
## Go to https://&amp;lt;localhost&amp;gt;:3000 in your browser to continue installation.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>By default Puppet Enterprise server uses 3000 port. Make sure that
firewall allows communication on port 3000&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ sudo ufw allow 3000
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Next, go to &lt;code>https://localhost:3000&lt;/code> url for completing installation&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;code>get started&lt;/code> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chose install on this server&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Enter &lt;code>&amp;lt;mypserver&amp;gt;&lt;/code> as DNS name. This is our Puppet Server name. This
can be configured in confile file also.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Enter console admin password&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click continue&lt;/p>
&lt;p>we will get confirm the plan screen with following information&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>The Puppet master component
Hostname
ritesh-ubuntu-pe
DNS aliases
&amp;lt;mypserver&amp;gt;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>click continue and verify installer validation screen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>click &lt;code>Deploy Now&lt;/code> button&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Puppet enterprise will be installed and will display message on screen&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>Puppet agent ran sucessfully
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>login to console with admin password that was set earlier and click on
nodes links to manage nodes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Installing Puppet Enterprise as Text mode monolithic installation&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ sudo ./puppet-enterprise-installer
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Enter 2 on &lt;code>How to Proceed&lt;/code> for text mode monolithic installation.
Following message will be displayed if successfull.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>2019-02-02T22:08:12.662-05:00 - [Notice]: Applied catalog in 339.28 seconds
2019-02-02T22:08:13.856-05:00 - [Notice]:
Sent analytics: pe_installer - install_finish - succeeded
* /opt/puppetlabs/puppet/bin/puppet infrastructure configure
--detailed-exitcodes --environmentpath /opt/puppetlabs/server/data/environments
--environment enterprise --no-noop --install=2019.0.2 --install-method='repair'
* returned: 2
## Puppet Enterprise configuration complete!
Documentation: https://puppet.com/docs/pe/2019.0/pe_user_guide.html
Release notes: https://puppet.com/docs/pe/2019.0/pe_release_notes.html
If this is a monolithic configuration, run 'puppet agent -t' to complete the
setup of this system.
If this is a split configuration, install or upgrade the remaining PE components,
and then run puppet agent -t on the Puppet master, PuppetDB, and PE console,
in that order.
~/pe/puppet-enterprise-2019.0.2-ubuntu-18.04-amd64
2019-02-02T22:08:14.805-05:00 Running command: /opt/puppetlabs/puppet/bin/puppet
agent --enable
~/pe/puppet-enterprise-2019.0.2-ubuntu-18.04-amd64$
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>This is called as monolithic installation as all components of Puppet
Enterprise such as Puppet master, PuppetDB and Console are installed on
single node. This installation type is easy to install. Troubleshooting
errors and upgrading infrastructure using this type is simple. This
installation type can easily support infrastructure of up to 20,000
managed nodes. Compiled master nodes can be added as network grows. This
is recommended installation type for small to mid size organizations
[2].&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>pe.conf&lt;/code> configuration file will be opened in editor to configure
values. This file contains parameters and values for installing,
upgrading and configuring Puppet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some important parameters that can be specified in &lt;code>pe.conf&lt;/code> file are&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>console_admin_password
puppet_enterprise::console_host
puppet_enterprise::puppetdb_host
puppet_enterprise::puppetdb_database_name
puppet_enterprise::puppetdb_database_user
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Lastly, we run puppet after installation is complete&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ puppet agent -t
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Text mode split installation is performed for large networks. Compared
to monolithic installation split installation type can manage large
infrastucture that requires more than 20,000 nodes. In this type of
installation different components of Puppet Enterprise (master, PuppetDB
and Console) are installed on different nodes. This installation type is
recommended for organizations with large infrastructure needs [3].&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this type of installation, we need to install componenets in specific
order. First master then puppet db followed by console.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Puppet Enterprise master and agent settings can be configured in
&lt;code>puppet.conf&lt;/code> file. Most configuration settings of Puppet Enterprise
componenets such as Master, Agent and security certificates are all
specified in this file.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Config section of Agent Node&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>[main]
certname = &amp;lt;http://your-domain-name.com/&amp;gt;
server = puppetserver
environment = testing
runinterval = 4h
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Config section of Master Node&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>[main]
certname = &amp;lt;http://your-domain-name.com/&amp;gt;
server = puppetserver
environment = testing
runinterval = 4h
strict_variables = true
[master]
dns_alt_names = puppetserver,puppet, &amp;lt;http://your-domain-name.com/&amp;gt;
reports = pupated
storeconfigs_backend = puppetdb
storeconfigs = true
environment_timeout = unlimited
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Comment lines, Settings lines and Settings variables are main components
of puppet configuration file. Comments in config files are specified by
prefixing hash character. Setting line consists name of setting followed
by equal sign, value of setting are specified in this section. Setting
variable value generally consists of one word but multiple can be
specified in rare cases [4].&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="refernces">Refernces&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>[1] Edureka, “Puppet tutorial – devops tool for configuration
management.” Web Page, May-2017 [Online]. Available:
&lt;a href="https://www.edureka.co/blog/videos/puppet-tutorial/">https://www.edureka.co/blog/videos/puppet-tutorial/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[2] Puppet, “Text mode installation: Monolithic.” Web Page, Nov-2017
[Online]. Available:
&lt;a href="https://puppet.com/docs/pe/2017.1/install_text_mode_mono.html">https://puppet.com/docs/pe/2017.1/install_text_mode_mono.html&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[3] Puppet, “Text mode installation : Split.” Web Page, Nov-2017
[Online]. Available:
&lt;a href="https://puppet.com/docs/pe/2017.1/install_text_mode_split.html">https://puppet.com/docs/pe/2017.1/install_text_mode_split.html&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[4] Puppet, “Config files: The main config files.” Web Page, Apr-2014
[Online]. Available:
&lt;a href="https://puppet.com/docs/puppet/5.3/config_file_main.html">https://puppet.com/docs/puppet/5.3/config_file_main.html&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Modules: Travis</title><link>/modules/devops/travis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/modules/devops/travis/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Travis CI is a continuous integration tool that is often used as part
of DevOps development. It is a hosted service that enables users to
test their projects on GitHub.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once travis is activated in a GitHub project, the developers can place
a &lt;code>.travis&lt;/code> file in the project root. Upon checkin the travis
configuration file will be interpreted and the commands indicated in
it will be executed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In fact this book has also a travis file that is located at&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/.travis.yml">https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/.travis.yml&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Please inspect it as we will illustrate some concepts of
it. Unfortunately travis does not use an up to date operating system
such as ubuntu 18.04. Therefore it contains outdated
libraries. Although we would be able to use containers, we have
elected for us to chose mechanism to update the operating system as we
need.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is done in the &lt;code>install&lt;/code> phase that in our case installs a new
version of pandoc, as well as some additional libraries that we use.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>in the &lt;code>env&lt;/code> we specify where we can find our executables with the
&lt;code>PATH&lt;/code> variable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The last portion in our example file specifies the script that is
executed after the install phase has been completed. As our
installation contains convenient and sophisticated makefiles, the
script is very simple while executing the appropriate make command in
the corresponding directories.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="exercises">Exercises&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>E.travis.1:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Develop an alternative travis file that in conjunction uses a
preconfigured container for ubuntu 18.04&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>E.travis.2:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Develop an travis file that checks our books on multiple operating
systems such as macOS, and ubuntu 18.04.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="resources">Resources&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.travis-ci.com/">https://docs.travis-ci.com/&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Modules: DevOps with AWS</title><link>/modules/devops/devop-aws/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/modules/devops/devop-aws/</guid><description>
&lt;p>AWS cloud offering comes with end-to-end scalable and most performant
support for DevOps, all the way from automatic deployment and monitoring
of infrastructure-as-code to our cloud-applications-code. AWS provides
various DevOp tools to make the deployment and support automation as
simple as possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="aws-devop-tools">AWS DevOp Tools&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Following is the list of DevOp tools for CI/CD workflows.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;colgroup>
&lt;col style="width: 28%" />
&lt;col style="width: 71%" />
&lt;/colgroup>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr class="header">
&lt;th>AWS DevOp Tool&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr class="odd">
&lt;td>CodeStar&lt;/td>
&lt;td>AWS CodeStar provides unified UI to enable simpler deployment automation.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr class="even">
&lt;td>CodePipeline&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CI/CD service for faster and reliable application and infrastructure updates.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr class="odd">
&lt;td>CodeBuild&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Fully managed build service that complies, tests and creates software packages that are ready to deploy.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr class="even">
&lt;td>CodeDeploy&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Deployment automation tool to deploy to on-premise and on-cloud EC2 instances with near-to-zero downtime during the application deployments.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="infrastructure-automation">Infrastructure Automation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>AWS provides services to make micro-services easily deployable onto
containers and serverless platforms.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;colgroup>
&lt;col style="width: 28%" />
&lt;col style="width: 71%" />
&lt;/colgroup>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr class="header">
&lt;th>AWS DevOp Infrastructure Tool&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr class="odd">
&lt;td>Elastic Container Service&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Highly scalable container management service.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr class="even">
&lt;td>CodePipeline&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CI/CD service for faster and reliable application and infrastructure updates.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr class="odd">
&lt;td>AWS Lambda&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Serverless Computing using Function-as-service (FaaS) methodologies .&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr class="even">
&lt;td>AWS CloudFormation&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Tool to create and manage related AWS resources.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr class="odd">
&lt;td>AWS OpsWorks&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Server Configuration Management Tool.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="monitoring-and-logging">Monitoring and Logging&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;colgroup>
&lt;col style="width: 28%" />
&lt;col style="width: 71%" />
&lt;/colgroup>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr class="header">
&lt;th>AWS DevOp Monitoring Tool&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr class="odd">
&lt;td>Amazon CloudWatch&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Tool to monitor AWS resources and cloud applications to collect and track metrics, logs and set alarms.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr class="even">
&lt;td>AWS X-Ray&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Allows developers to analyze and troubleshoot performance issues of their cloud applications and micro-services.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>For more information, please visit Amazon AWS [1].&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="refernces">Refernces&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>[1] Amazon AWS, &lt;em>DevOps and AWS&lt;/em>. Amazon, 2019 [Online]. Available:
&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/devops/">https://aws.amazon.com/devops/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Modules: DevOps with Azure Monitor</title><link>/modules/devops/devop-azure-monitor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/modules/devops/devop-azure-monitor/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Microsoft provides unified tool called Azure Monitor for end-to-end
monitoring of the infrastructure and deployed applications. Azure
Monitor can greatly help Dev-Op teams by proactively and reactively
monitoring the applications for bug tracking, health-check and provide
metrics that can hint on various scalability aspects.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="../images/devops-azure-monitor.jpg" id="fig:azuremonitor" alt="Figure 1: Azure Monitor [1]" />&lt;figcaption aria-hidden="true">Figure 1: Azure Monitor &lt;span class="citation" data-cites="azure-monitor">[1]&lt;/span>&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Azure Monitor accommodates applications developed in various programming
languages - .NET, Java, Node.JS, Python and various others. With Azure
Application Insights telematics API incorporated into the applications,
Azure Monitor can provide more detailed metrics and analytics around
specific tracking needs - usage, bugs, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Azure Monitor can help us track the health, performance and scalability
issues of the infrastructure - VMs, Containers, Storage, Network and all
Azure Services by automatically providing various platform metrics,
activity and diagnostic logs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Azure Monitor provides programmatic access through Power Shell scripts
to access the activity and diagnostic logs. It also allows querying them
using powerful querying tools for advanced in-depth analysis and
reporting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Azure Monitor proactively monitors and notifies us of critical
conditions - reaching quota limits, abnormal usage, health-checks and
recommendations along with making attempts to correct some of those
aspects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Azure Monitor Dashboards allow visualize various aspects of the data -
metrics, logs, usage patterns in tabular and graphical widgets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Azure Monitor also facilitates closer monitoring of micro-services if
they are provided through Azure Serverless Function-As-Service.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more information, please visit Microsoft Azure Website [1].&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="refernces">Refernces&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>[1] Microsoft Azure, &lt;em>Azure Monitor Overview&lt;/em>. Microsoft, 2018
[Online]. Available:
&lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-monitor/overview">https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-monitor/overview&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>