<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cybertraining – Applications</title>
    <link>/modules/bigdataapplications/2020/applications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Applications on Cybertraining</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	  <atom:link href="/modules/bigdataapplications/2020/applications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Modules: Big Data Use Cases Survey</title>
      <link>/modules/bigdataapplications/2020/applications/usecases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/bigdataapplications/2020/applications/usecases/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;This section covers 51 values of X and an overall study of Big data that
emerged from a NIST (National Institute for Standards and Technology)
study of Big data. The section covers the NIST Big Data Public Working
Group (NBD-PWG) Process and summarizes the work of five subgroups:
Definitions and Taxonomies Subgroup, Reference Architecture Subgroup,
Security and Privacy Subgroup, Technology Roadmap Subgroup and the
Requirements andUse Case Subgroup. 51 use cases collected in this
process are briefly discussed with a classification of the source of
parallelism and the high and low level computational structure. We
describe the key features of this classification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;nist-big-data-public-working-group&#34;&gt;NIST Big Data Public Working Group&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This unit covers the NIST Big Data Public Working Group (NBD-PWG)
Process and summarizes the work of five subgroups: Definitions and
Taxonomies Subgroup, Reference Architecture Subgroup, Security and
Privacy Subgroup, Technology Roadmap Subgroup and the Requirements and
Use Case Subgroup. The work of latter is continued in next two units.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B8936_ytjfjmODIxNGttU1pveWc&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/presentation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Presentation&#34;&gt; Overview
(45)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction-to-nist-big-data-public-working&#34;&gt;Introduction to NIST Big Data Public Working&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The focus of the (NBD-PWG) is to form a community of interest from
industry, academia, and government, with the goal of developing a
consensus definitions, taxonomies, secure reference architectures, and
technology roadmap. The aim is to create vendor-neutral, technology and
infrastructure agnostic deliverables to enable big data stakeholders to
pick-and-choose best analytics tools for their processing and
visualization requirements on the most suitable computing platforms and
clusters while allowing value-added from big data service providers and
flow of data between the stakeholders in a cohesive and secure manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3oKdmuH0N3k&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Introduction
(13:02)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;definitions-and-taxonomies-subgroup&#34;&gt;Definitions and Taxonomies Subgroup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The focus is to gain a better understanding of the principles of Big
Data. It is important to develop a consensus-based common language and
vocabulary terms used in Big Data across stakeholders from industry,
academia, and government. In addition, it is also critical to identify
essential actors with roles and responsibility, and subdivide them into
components and sub-components on how they interact/ relate with each
other according to their similarities and differences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Definitions: Compile terms used from all stakeholders regarding the
meaning of Big Data from various standard bodies, domain applications,
and diversified operational environments. For Taxonomies: Identify key
actors with their roles and responsibilities from all stakeholders,
categorize them into components and subcomponents based on their
similarities and differences. In particular data Science and Big Data
terms are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7eOtuBV8udo&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Taxonomies
(7:42)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;reference-architecture-subgroup&#34;&gt;Reference Architecture Subgroup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The focus is to form a community of interest from industry, academia,
and government, with the goal of developing a consensus-based approach
to orchestrate vendor-neutral, technology and infrastructure agnostic
for analytics tools and computing environments. The goal is to enable
Big Data stakeholders to pick-and-choose technology-agnostic analytics
tools for processing and visualization in any computing platform and
cluster while allowing value-added from Big Data service providers and
the flow of the data between the stakeholders in a cohesive and secure
manner. Results include a reference architecture with well defined
components and linkage as well as several exemplars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h4ylW0vztDw&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Architecture
(10:05)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;security-and-privacy-subgroup&#34;&gt;Security and Privacy Subgroup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The focus is to form a community of interest from industry, academia,
and government, with the goal of developing a consensus secure reference
architecture to handle security and privacy issues across all
stakeholders. This includes gaining an understanding of what standards
are available or under development, as well as identifies which key
organizations are working on these standards. The Top Ten Big Data
Security and Privacy Challenges from the CSA (Cloud Security Alliance)
BDWG are studied. Specialized use cases include Retail/Marketing, Modern
Day Consumerism, Nielsen Homescan, Web Traffic Analysis, Healthcare,
Health Information Exchange, Genetic Privacy, Pharma Clinical Trial Data
Sharing, Cyber-security, Government, Military and Education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dHrHk-GvruY&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Security (9:51)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;technology-roadmap-subgroup&#34;&gt;Technology Roadmap Subgroup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The focus is to form a community of interest from industry, academia,
and government, with the goal of developing a consensus vision with
recommendations on how Big Data should move forward by performing a good
gap analysis through the materials gathered from all other NBD
subgroups. This includes setting standardization and adoption priorities
through an understanding of what standards are available or under
development as part of the recommendations. Tasks are gather input from
NBD subgroups and study the taxonomies for the actors&amp;rsquo; roles and
responsibility, use cases and requirements, and secure reference
architecture; gain understanding of what standards are available or
under development for Big Data; perform a thorough gap analysis and
document the findings; identify what possible barriers may delay or
prevent adoption of Big Data; and document vision and recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=va0UCR5gMTA&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Technology
(4:14)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;interfaces-subgroup&#34;&gt;Interfaces Subgroup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This subgroup is working on the following document: &lt;em&gt;NIST Big Data
Interoperability Framework: Volume 8, Reference Architecture Interface&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This document summarizes interfaces that are instrumental for the
interaction with Clouds, Containers, and HPC systems to manage virtual
clusters to support the NIST Big Data Reference Architecture (NBDRA).
The Representational State Transfer (REST) paradigm is used to define
these interfaces allowing easy integration and adoption by a wide
variety of frameworks. . This volume, Volume 8, uses the work performed
by the NBD-PWG to identify objects instrumental for the NIST Big Data
Reference Architecture (NBDRA) which is introduced in the NBDIF: Volume
6, Reference Architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation was given at the &lt;em&gt;2nd NIST Big Data Public Working
Group (NBD-PWG) Workshop&lt;/em&gt; in Washington DC in June 2017. It explains our
thoughts on deriving automatically a reference architecture form the
Reference Architecture Interface specifications directly from the
document.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workshop Web page is located at&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bigdatawg.nist.gov/workshop2.php&#34;&gt;https://bigdatawg.nist.gov/workshop2.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The agenda of the workshop is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bigdatawg.nist.gov/2017_NIST_Big_Data_PWG_WorkshopAgenda_with_Speakers_Bio.pdf&#34;&gt;https://bigdatawg.nist.gov/2017_NIST_Big_Data_PWG_WorkshopAgenda_with_Speakers_Bio.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Web cas of the presentation is given bellow, while you need to fast
forward to a particular time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Webcast: Interface subgroup:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nist.gov/news-events/events/2017/06/2nd-nist-big-data-public-working-group-nbd-pwg-workshop&#34;&gt;https://www.nist.gov/news-events/events/2017/06/2nd-nist-big-data-public-working-group-nbd-pwg-workshop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;see: Big Data Working Group Day 1, part 2 Time start: 21:00 min,
Time end: 44:00&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cloudmesh/cloudmesh.rest/blob/master/docs/NBDPWG-vol8.pptx?raw=true&#34;&gt;https://github.com/cloudmesh/cloudmesh.rest/blob/master/docs/NBDPWG-vol8.pptx?raw=true&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Document:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cloudmesh/cloudmesh.rest/raw/master/docs/NIST.SP.1500-8-draft.pdf&#34;&gt;https://github.com/cloudmesh/cloudmesh.rest/raw/master/docs/NIST.SP.1500-8-draft.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are welcome to view other presentations if you are interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;requirements-and-use-case-subgroup&#34;&gt;Requirements and Use Case Subgroup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The focus is to form a community of interest from industry, academia,
and government, with the goal of developing a consensus list of Big Data
requirements across all stakeholders. This includes gathering and
understanding various use cases from diversified application
domains.Tasks are gather use case input from all stakeholders; derive
Big Data requirements from each use case; analyze/prioritize a list of
challenging general requirements that may delay or prevent adoption of
Big Data deployment; develop a set of general patterns capturing the
&lt;em&gt;essence&lt;/em&gt; of use cases (not done yet) and work with Reference
Architecture to validate requirements and reference architecture by
explicitly implementing some patterns based on use cases. The progress
of gathering use cases (discussed in next two units) and requirements
systemization are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f_vxmx3CmMU&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Requirements
(27:28)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;51-big-data-use-cases&#34;&gt;51 Big Data Use Cases&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This units consists of one or more slides for each of the 51 use cases -
typically additional (more than one) slides are associated with
pictures. Each of the use cases is identified with source of parallelism
and the high and low level computational structure. As each new
classification topic is introduced we briefly discuss it but full
discussion of topics is given in following unit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B8936_ytjfjmYUlKckhLSUQxMUk&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/presentation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Presentation&#34;&gt; 51 Use Cases
(100)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;government-use-cases&#34;&gt;Government Use Cases&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This covers Census 2010 and 2000 - Title 13 Big Data; National Archives
and Records Administration Accession NARA, Search, Retrieve,
Preservation; Statistical Survey Response Improvement (Adaptive Design)
and Non-Traditional Data in Statistical Survey Response Improvement
(Adaptive Design).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e0ks_BuYUVM&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Government Use Cases
(17:43)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;commercial-use-cases&#34;&gt;Commercial Use Cases&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This covers Cloud Eco-System, for Financial Industries (Banking,
Securities &amp;amp; Investments, Insurance) transacting business within the
United States; Mendeley - An International Network of Research; Netflix
Movie Service; Web Search; IaaS (Infrastructure as a Service) Big Data
Business Continuity &amp;amp; Disaster Recovery (BC/DR) Within A Cloud
Eco-System; Cargo Shipping; Materials Data for Manufacturing and
Simulation driven Materials Genomics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=URy9u8_34ww&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Commercial Use Cases
(17:43)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;defense-use-cases&#34;&gt;Defense Use Cases&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This covers Large Scale Geospatial Analysis and Visualization; Object
identification and tracking from Wide Area Large Format Imagery (WALF)
Imagery or Full Motion Video (FMV) - Persistent Surveillance and
Intelligence Data Processing and Analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FXFfE8zcco8&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Defense Use Cases
(15:43)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;healthcare-and-life-science-use-cases&#34;&gt;Healthcare and Life Science Use Cases&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This covers Electronic Medical Record (EMR) Data; Pathology
Imaging/digital pathology; Computational Bioimaging; Genomic
Measurements; Comparative analysis for metagenomes and genomes;
Individualized Diabetes Management; Statistical Relational Artificial
Intelligence for Health Care; World Population Scale Epidemiological
Study; Social Contagion Modeling for Planning, Public Health and
Disaster Management and Biodiversity and LifeWatch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uGeYrXENlpU&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Healthcare and Life Science Use Cases
(30:11)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;deep-learning-and-social-networks-use-cases&#34;&gt;Deep Learning and Social Networks Use Cases&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This covers Large-scale Deep Learning; Organizing large-scale,
unstructured collections of consumer photos; Truthy: Information
diffusion research from Twitter Data; Crowd Sourcing in the Humanities
as Source for Bigand Dynamic Data; CINET: Cyberinfrastructure for
Network (Graph) Science and Analytics and NIST Information Access
Division analytic technology performance measurement, evaluations, and
standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bdWyhT8bvE4&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Deep Learning and Social Networks Use Cases
(14:19)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;research-ecosystem-use-cases&#34;&gt;Research Ecosystem Use Cases&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DataNet Federation Consortium DFC; The &amp;lsquo;Discinnet process&amp;rsquo;, metadata
-big data global experiment; Semantic Graph-search on Scientific
Chemical and Text-based Data and Light source beamlines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jjyv4RmMIUU&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Research Ecosystem Use Cases
(9:09)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;astronomy-and-physics-use-cases&#34;&gt;Astronomy and Physics Use Cases&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This covers Catalina Real-Time Transient Survey (CRTS): a digital,
panoramic, synoptic sky survey; DOE Extreme Data from Cosmological Sky
Survey and Simulations; Large Survey Data for Cosmology; Particle
Physics: Analysis of LHC Large Hadron Collider Data: Discovery of Higgs
particle and Belle II High Energy Physics Experiment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MPEe8yDVwAo&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Astronomy and Physics Use Cases
(17:33)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;environment-earth-and-polar-science-use-cases&#34;&gt;Environment, Earth and Polar Science Use Cases&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EISCAT 3D incoherent scatter radar system; ENVRI, Common Operations of
Environmental Research Infrastructure; Radar Data Analysis for CReSIS
Remote Sensing of Ice Sheets; UAVSAR Data Processing, DataProduct
Delivery, and Data Services; NASA LARC/GSFC iRODS Federation Testbed;
MERRA Analytic Services MERRA/AS; Atmospheric Turbulence - Event
Discovery and Predictive Analytics; Climate Studies using the Community
Earth System Model at DOE&amp;rsquo;s NERSC center; DOE-BER Subsurface
Biogeochemistry Scientific Focus Area and DOE-BER AmeriFlux and FLUXNET
Networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YJGk-uvaUCg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Environment, Earth and Polar Science Use Cases
(25:29)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;energy-use-case&#34;&gt;Energy Use Case&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This covers Consumption forecasting in Smart Grids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5y_O-a8_Fbg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Energy Use Case
(4:01)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;features-of-51-big-data-use-cases&#34;&gt;Features of 51 Big Data Use Cases&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This unit discusses the categories used to classify the 51 use-cases.
These categories include concepts used for parallelism and low and high
level computational structure. The first lesson is an introduction to
all categories and the further lessons give details of particular
categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B8936_ytjfjmREJTMHhjMktXRHc&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/presentation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Presentation&#34;&gt; Features
(43)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary-of-use-case-classification&#34;&gt;Summary of Use Case Classification&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This discusses concepts used for parallelism and low and high level
computational structure. Parallelism can be over People (users or
subjects), Decision makers; Items such as Images, EMR, Sequences;
observations, contents of online store; Sensors &amp;ndash; Internet of Things;
Events; (Complex) Nodes in a Graph; Simple nodes as in a learning
network; Tweets, Blogs, Documents, Web Pages etc.; Files or data to be
backed up, moved or assigned metadata; Particles/cells/mesh points. Low
level computational types include PP (Pleasingly Parallel); MR
(MapReduce); MRStat; MRIter (Iterative MapReduce); Graph; Fusion; MC
(Monte Carlo) and Streaming. High level computational types include
Classification; S/Q (Search and Query); Index; CF (Collaborative
Filtering); ML (Machine Learning); EGO (Large Scale Optimizations); EM
(Expectation maximization); GIS; HPC; Agents. Patterns include Classic
Database; NoSQL; Basic processing of data as in backup or metadata; GIS;
Host of Sensors processed on demand; Pleasingly parallel processing; HPC
assimilated with observational data; Agent-based models; Multi-modal
data fusion or Knowledge Management; Crowd Sourcing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X0vEmbn1Ld8&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Summary of Use Case Classification
(23:39)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;databasesql-use-case-classification&#34;&gt;Database(SQL) Use Case Classification&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This discusses classic (SQL) database approach to data handling with
Search&amp;amp;Query and Index features. Comparisons are made to NoSQL
approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jIVdQID11Q4&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Database (SQL) Use Case Classification
(11:13)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;nosql-use-case-classification&#34;&gt;NoSQL Use Case Classification&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This discusses NoSQL (compared in previous lesson) with HDFS, Hadoop and
Hbase. The Apache Big data stack is introduced and further details of
comparison with SQL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uGL8cFPrhoE&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; NoSQL Use Case Classification
(11:20)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-use-case-classifications&#34;&gt;Other Use Case Classifications&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This discusses a subset of use case features: GIS, Sensors. the support
of data analysis and fusion by streaming data between filters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=79IwNCNjVWU&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Use Case Classifications I
(12:42)&lt;/a&gt; This discusses a
subset of use case features: Pleasingly parallel, MRStat, Data
Assimilation, Crowd sourcing, Agents, data fusion and agents, EGO and
security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=b-olNbWCJyg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Use Case Classifications II
(20:18)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This discusses a subset of use case features: Classification, Monte
Carlo, Streaming, PP, MR, MRStat, MRIter and HPC(MPI), global and local
analytics (machine learning), parallel computing, Expectation
Maximization, graphs and Collaborative Filtering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ewqoFGxyQmc&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Use Case Classifications III
(17:25)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\TODO{These resources have not all been checked to see if they still
exist this is currently in progress}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nist.gov/el/cyber-physical-systems/big-data-pwg&#34;&gt;NIST Big Data Public Working Group (NBD-PWG)
Process&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.6028/NIST.SP.1500-1&#34;&gt;Big Data Definitions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.6028/NIST.SP.1500-2&#34;&gt;Big Data Taxonomies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.6028/NIST.SP.1500-3&#34;&gt;Big Data Use Cases and
Requirements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.6028/NIST.SP.1500-4&#34;&gt;Big Data Security and
Privacy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.6028/NIST.SP.1500-5&#34;&gt;Big Data Architecture White Paper
Survey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.6028/NIST.SP.1500-6&#34;&gt;Big Data Reference
Architecture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.6028/NIST.SP.1500-7&#34;&gt;Big Data Standards
Roadmap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the links bellow may be outdated. Please let us know the new
links and notify us of the outdated links.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l4Qii7T8zeg&#34;&gt;DCGSA Standard Cloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bigdatawg.nist.gov/usecases.php&#34;&gt;On line 51 Use Cases&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bigdatawg.nist.gov/_uploadfiles/M0245_v5_6066621242.docx&#34;&gt;Summary of Requirements
Subgroup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mendeley.com%20http//dev.mendeley.com&#34;&gt;Use Case 6 Mendeley&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(this link does not exist any longer)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/xamat/building-largescale-realworld-recommender-systems-recsys2012-tutoria&#34;&gt;Use Case 7 Netflix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use Case 8 Search&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/kleinerperkins/kpcb-internet-trends-2013&#34;&gt;http://www.slideshare.net/kleinerperkins/kpcb-internet-trends-2013&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://webcourse.cs.technion.ac.il/236621/Winter2011-2012/en/ho_Lectures.html&#34;&gt;http://webcourse.cs.technion.ac.il/236621/Winter2011-2012/en/ho_Lectures.html&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ifis.cs.tu-bs.de/teaching/ss-11/irws&#34;&gt;http://www.ifis.cs.tu-bs.de/teaching/ss-11/irws&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/beechung/recommender-systems-tutorialpart1intro&#34;&gt;http://www.slideshare.net/beechung/recommender-systems-tutorialpart1intro&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.worldwidewebsize.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.worldwidewebsize.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.disasterrecovery.org/&#34;&gt;Use Case 9 IaaS (Infrastructure as a Service) Big Data Business
Continuity &amp;amp; Disaster Recovery (BC/DR) Within A Cloud Eco-System
provided by Cloud Service Providers (CSPs) and Cloud Brokerage
Service Providers (CBSPs)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.materialsproject.org/&#34;&gt;Use Case 11 and Use Case 12 Simulation driven Materials
Genomics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use Case 13 Large Scale Geospatial Analysis and Visualization&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opengeospatial.org/standards&#34;&gt;http://www.opengeospatial.org/standards&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://geojson.org/&#34;&gt;http://geojson.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://earth-info.nga.mil/publications/specs/printed/CADRG/cadrg.html&#34;&gt;http://earth-info.nga.mil/publications/specs/printed/CADRG/cadrg.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use Case 14 Object identification and tracking from Wide Area Large
Format Imagery (WALF) Imagery or Full Motion Video (FMV) -
Persistent Surveillance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.militaryaerospace.com/topics/m/video/79088650/persistent-surveillance-relies-on-extracting-relevant-data-points-and-connecting-the-dots.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.militaryaerospace.com/topics/m/video/79088650/persistent-surveillance-relies-on-extracting-relevant-data-points-and-connecting-the-dots.htm&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.defencetalk.com/wide-area-persistent-surveillance-revolutionizes-tactical-isr-45745/&#34;&gt;http://www.defencetalk.com/wide-area-persistent-surveillance-revolutionizes-tactical-isr-45745/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use Case 15 Intelligence Data Processing and Analysis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.afcea-aberdeen.org/files/presentations/AFCEAAberdeen_DCGSA_COLWells_PS.pdf&#34;&gt;http://www.afcea-aberdeen.org/files/presentations/AFCEAAberdeen_DCGSA_COLWells_PS.pdf&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://stids.c4i.gmu.edu/STIDS2011/papers/STIDS2011_CR_T1_SalmenEtAl.pdf&#34;&gt;http://stids.c4i.gmu.edu/STIDS2011/papers/STIDS2011_CR_T1_SalmenEtAl.pdf&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://stids.c4i.gmu.edu/papers/STIDSPapers/STIDS2012/_T14/_SmithEtAl/_HorizontalIntegrationOfWarfighterIntel.pdf&#34;&gt;http://stids.c4i.gmu.edu/papers/STIDSPapers/STIDS2012/_T14/_SmithEtAl/_HorizontalIntegrationOfWarfighterIntel.pdf&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l4Qii7T8zeg&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l4Qii7T8zeg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dcgsa.apg.army.mil/&#34;&gt;http://dcgsa.apg.army.mil/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use Case 16 Electronic Medical Record (EMR) Data:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.regenstrief.org/&#34;&gt;Regenstrief Institute&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://loinc.org/&#34;&gt;Logical observation identifiers names and
codes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ihie.org/&#34;&gt;Indiana Health Information Exchange&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iom.edu/Activities/Quality/LearningHealthcare.aspx&#34;&gt;Institute of Medicine Learning Healthcare
System&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use Case 17&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.cci.emory.edu/confluence/display/PAIS%3E&#34;&gt;Pathology Imaging/digital
pathology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.cci.emory.edu/confluence/display/HadoopGIS&#34;&gt;https://web.cci.emory.edu/confluence/display/HadoopGIS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use Case 19 Genome in a Bottle Consortium:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bigdatacoursespring2015.appspot.com/www.genomeinabottle.org&#34;&gt;www.genomeinabottle.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://img.jgi.doe.gov/&#34;&gt;Use Case 20 Comparative analysis for metagenomes and
genomes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use Case 25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.biodiversitycatalogue.org/&#34;&gt;Biodiversity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lifewatch.eu/web/guest/home&#34;&gt;LifeWatch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use Case 26 Deep Learning: Recent popular press coverage of deep
learning technology:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2012/11/24/science/scientists-see-advances-in-deep-learning-a-part-of-artificial-intelligence.html&#34;&gt;http://www.nytimes.com/2012/11/24/science/scientists-see-advances-in-deep-learning-a-part-of-artificial-intelligence.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2012/06/26/technology/in-a-big-network-of-computers-evidence-of-machine-learning.html&#34;&gt;http://www.nytimes.com/2012/06/26/technology/in-a-big-network-of-computers-evidence-of-machine-learning.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wired.com/2013/06/andrew_ng/&#34;&gt;http://www.wired.com/2013/06/andrew_ng/&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stanford.edu/~acoates/papers/CoatesHuvalWangWuNgCatanzaro_icml2013.pdf&#34;&gt;A recent research paper on HPC for Deep
Learning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Widely-used tutorials and references for Deep Learning:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ufldl.stanford.edu/wiki/index.php/Main_Page&#34;&gt;http://ufldl.stanford.edu/wiki/index.php/Main_Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://deeplearning.net/&#34;&gt;http://deeplearning.net/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vision.soic.indiana.edu/projects/disco/&#34;&gt;Use Case 27 Organizing large-scale, unstructured collections of
consumer photos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use Case 28&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://truthy.indiana.edu/&#34;&gt;Truthy: Information diffusion research from Twitter
Data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cnets.indiana.edu/groups/nan/truthy/&#34;&gt;http://cnets.indiana.edu/groups/nan/truthy/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cnets.indiana.edu/groups/nan/despic/&#34;&gt;http://cnets.indiana.edu/groups/nan/despic/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cinet.vbi.vt.edu/cinet_new/&#34;&gt;Use Case 30 CINET: Cyberinfrastructure for Network (Graph) Science
and Analytics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nist.gov/itl/iad/&#34;&gt;Use Case 31 NIST Information Access Division analytic technology
performance measurement, evaluations, and
standards&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use Case 32&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DataNet Federation Consortium DFC: &lt;a href=&#34;http://datafed.org/&#34;&gt;The DataNet Federation
Consortium&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://irods.org/&#34;&gt;iRODS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use Case 33 The &amp;lsquo;Discinnet process&amp;rsquo;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.discinnet.org/&#34;&gt;big data global
experiment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use Case 34 Semantic Graph-search on Scientific Chemical and
Text-based Data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2013-07/aiop-ffm071813.php&#34;&gt;http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2013-07/aiop-ffm071813.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://xpdb.nist.gov/chemblast/pdb.pl&#34;&gt;http://xpdb.nist.gov/chemblast/pdb.pl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use Case 35 Light source beamlines&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www-als.lbl.gov/&#34;&gt;http://www-als.lbl.gov/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www1.aps.anl.gov/&#34;&gt;https://www1.aps.anl.gov/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use Case 36&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://crts.caltech.edu/&#34;&gt;CRTS survey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lpl.arizona.edu/css/&#34;&gt;CSS survey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For an &lt;a href=&#34;http://arxiv.org/abs/1209.1681&#34;&gt;overview of the classification
challenges&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use Case 37 DOE Extreme Data from Cosmological Sky Survey and
Simulations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lsst.org/lsst/&#34;&gt;http://www.lsst.org/lsst/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nersc.gov/&#34;&gt;http://www.nersc.gov/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nersc.gov/assets/Uploads/HabibcosmosimV2.pdf&#34;&gt;http://www.nersc.gov/assets/Uploads/HabibcosmosimV2.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use Case 38 Large Survey Data for Cosmology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://desi.lbl.gov/&#34;&gt;http://desi.lbl.gov/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.darkenergysurvey.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.darkenergysurvey.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use Case 39 Particle Physics: Analysis of LHC Large Hadron Collider
Data: Discovery of Higgs particle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grids.ucs.indiana.edu/ptliupages/publications/Where%20does%20all%20the%20data%20come%20from%20v7.pdf&#34;&gt;http://grids.ucs.indiana.edu/ptliupages/publications/Where%20does%20all%20the%20data%20come%20from%20v7.pdf&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.es.net/assets/pubs_presos/High-throughput-lessons-from-the-LHC-experience.Johnston.TNC2013.pdf&#34;&gt;http://www.es.net/assets/pubs_presos/High-throughput-lessons-from-the-LHC-experience.Johnston.TNC2013.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://belle2.kek.jp/&#34;&gt;Use Case 40 Belle II High Energy Physics
Experiment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(old link does not exist, new link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.belle2.org&#34;&gt;https://www.belle2.org&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eiscat3d.se/&#34;&gt;Use Case 41 EISCAT 3D incoherent scatter radar
system&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use Case 42 ENVRI, Common Operations of Environmental Research
Infrastructure&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://envri.eu/&#34;&gt;ENVRI Project website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://confluence.envri.eu:8090/display/ERM/Start&#34;&gt;ENVRI Reference Model&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://confluence.envri.eu:8090/download/attachments/327687/D3.3%20Analysis%20of%20Requirements%20V1.0.pdf?version=1&amp;amp;modificationDate=1366965933706&amp;amp;api=v2&#34;&gt;ENVRI deliverable D3.2 : Analysis of common requirements of
Environmental Research
Infrastructures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.icos-ri.eu/&#34;&gt;ICOS&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.euro-argo.eu/&#34;&gt;Euro-Argo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eiscat3d.se/node&#34;&gt;EISCAT 3D&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lifewatch.com/&#34;&gt;LifeWatch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.epos-eu.org/&#34;&gt;EPOS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.emso-eu.org/&#34;&gt;EMSO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cresis.ku.edu/%3E&#34;&gt;Use Case 43 Radar Data Analysis for CReSIS Remote Sensing of Ice
Sheets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use Case 44 UAVSAR Data Processing, Data Product Delivery, and Data
Services&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://uavsar.jpl.nasa.gov/&#34;&gt;http://uavsar.jpl.nasa.gov/&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.asf.alaska.edu/program/sdc&#34;&gt;http://www.asf.alaska.edu/program/sdc&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://geo-gateway.org/main.html&#34;&gt;http://geo-gateway.org/main.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use Case 47 Atmospheric Turbulence - Event Discovery and Predictive
Analytics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://oceanworld.tamu.edu/resources/oceanography-book/teleconnections.htm&#34;&gt;http://oceanworld.tamu.edu/resources/oceanography-book/teleconnections.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forbes.com/sites/toddwoody/2012/03/21/meet-the-scientists-mining-big-data-to-predict-the-weather/&#34;&gt;http://www.forbes.com/sites/toddwoody/2012/03/21/meet-the-scientists-mining-big-data-to-predict-the-weather/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use Case 48 Climate Studies using the Community Earth System Model
at DOE&amp;rsquo;s NERSC center&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www-pcmdi.llnl.gov/&#34;&gt;http://www-pcmdi.llnl.gov/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nersc.gov/&#34;&gt;http://www.nersc.gov/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://science.energy.gov/ber/research/cesd/&#34;&gt;http://science.energy.gov/ber/research/cesd/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.cisl.ucar.edu/&#34;&gt;http://www2.cisl.ucar.edu/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use Case 50 DOE-BER AmeriFlux and FLUXNET Networks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ameriflux.lbl.gov/&#34;&gt;http://ameriflux.lbl.gov/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fluxdata.org/default.aspx&#34;&gt;http://www.fluxdata.org/default.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use Case 51 Consumption forecasting in Smart Grids&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://smartgrid.usc.edu/&#34;&gt;http://smartgrid.usc.edu/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(old link does not exsit, new link: &lt;a href=&#34;http://dslab.usc.edu/smartgrid.php&#34;&gt;http://dslab.usc.edu/smartgrid.php&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ganges.usc.edu/wiki/Smart_Grid&#34;&gt;http://ganges.usc.edu/wiki/Smart_Grid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ladwp.com/ladwp/faces/ladwp/aboutus/a-power/a-p-smartgridla?_afrLoop=157401916661989&amp;amp;_afrWindowMode=0&amp;amp;_afrWindowId=null#%40%3F_afrWindowId%3Dnull%26_afrLoop%3D157401916661989%26_afrWindowMode%3D0%26_adf.ctrl-state%3Db7yulr4rl_17&#34;&gt;https://www.ladwp.com/ladwp/faces/ladwp/aboutus/a-power/a-p-smartgridla?_afrLoop=157401916661989&amp;amp;_afrWindowMode=0&amp;amp;_afrWindowId=null#%40%3F_afrWindowId%3Dnull%26_afrLoop%3D157401916661989%26_afrWindowMode%3D0%26_adf.ctrl-state%3Db7yulr4rl_17&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?arnumber=6475927&#34;&gt;http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?arnumber=6475927&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modules: Cloud Computing</title>
      <link>/modules/bigdataapplications/2020/applications/cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/bigdataapplications/2020/applications/cloud/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;We describe the central role of Parallel computing in Clouds and Big
Data which is decomposed into lots of &lt;em&gt;Little data&lt;/em&gt; running in
individual cores. Many examples are given and it is stressed that issues
in parallel computing are seen in day to day life for communication,
synchronization, load balancing and decomposition. Cyberinfrastructure
for e-moreorlessanything or moreorlessanything-Informatics and the
basics of cloud computing are introduced. This includes virtualization
and the important &lt;em&gt;as a Service&lt;/em&gt; components and we go through several
different definitions of cloud computing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gartner&amp;rsquo;s Technology Landscape includes hype cycle and priority matrix
and covers clouds and Big Data. Two simple examples of the value of
clouds for enterprise applications are given with a review of different
views as to nature of Cloud Computing. This IaaS (Infrastructure as a
Service) discussion is followed by PaaS and SaaS (Platform and Software
as a Service). Features in Grid and cloud computing and data are
treated. We summarize the 21 layers and almost 300 software packages in
the HPC-ABDS Software Stack explaining how they are used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cloud (Data Center) Architectures with physical setup, Green Computing
issues and software models are discussed followed by the Cloud Industry
stakeholders with a 2014 Gartner analysis of Cloud computing providers.
This is followed by applications on the cloud including data intensive
problems, comparison with high performance computing, science clouds and
the Internet of Things. Remarks on Security, Fault Tolerance and
Synchronicity issues in cloud follow. We describe the way users and data
interact with a cloud system. The Big Data Processing from an
application perspective with commercial examples including eBay
concludes section after a discussion of data system architectures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;parallel-computing-outdated&#34;&gt;Parallel Computing (Outdated)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We describe the central role of Parallel computing in Clouds and Big
Data which is decomposed into lots of &amp;lsquo;&amp;lsquo;Little data&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; running in
individual cores. Many examples are given and it is stressed that issues
in parallel computing are seen in day to day life for communication,
synchronization, load balancing and decomposition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B8936_ytjfjmZDRqMldzSVhVem8/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/presentation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Presentation&#34;&gt; Parallel Computing
(33)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;decomposition&#34;&gt;Decomposition&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We describe why parallel computing is essential with Big Data and
distinguishes parallelism over users to that over the data in problem.
The general ideas behind data decomposition are given followed by a few
often whimsical examples dreamed up 30 years ago in the early heady days
of parallel computing. These include scientific simulations, defense
outside missile attack and computer chess. The basic problem of parallel
computing &amp;ndash; efficient coordination of separate tasks processing
different data parts &amp;ndash; is described with MPI and MapReduce as two
approaches. The challenges of data decomposition in irregular problems
is noted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B1Of61fJF7WsWXgtNndQN0Jydkk/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Decomposition
(8:51)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B1Of61fJF7WsQ1pMLWhXQV92OXM/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Examples of Application
(13:22)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B1Of61fJF7WsaVZLOEUzc0VuWjQ/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Decomposition Strategies
(9:22)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;parallel-computing-in-society&#34;&gt;Parallel Computing in Society&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson from the past notes that one can view society as an approach
to parallel linkage of people. The largest example given is that of the
construction of a long wall such as that (Hadrian&amp;rsquo;s wall) between
England and Scotland. Different approaches to parallelism are given with
formulae for the speed up and efficiency. The concepts of grain size
(size of problem tackled by an individual processor) and coordination
overhead are exemplified. This example also illustrates Amdahl&amp;rsquo;s law and
the relation between data and processor topology. The lesson concludes
with other examples from nature including collections of neurons (the
brain) and ants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B1Of61fJF7WsY3hEeTJvTFYtN2s/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Parallel Computing in Society I
(8:24)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B1Of61fJF7WsU1ROMmpNNTlUTUU/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Parallel Computing in Society II
(8:01)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;parallel-processing-for-hadrians-wall&#34;&gt;Parallel Processing for Hadrian&amp;rsquo;s Wall&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson returns to Hadrian&amp;rsquo;s wall and uses it to illustrate advanced
issues in parallel computing. First We describe the basic SPMD &amp;ndash; Single
Program Multiple Data &amp;ndash; model. Then irregular but homogeneous and
heterogeneous problems are discussed. Static and dynamic load balancing
is needed. Inner parallelism (as in vector instruction or the multiple
fingers of masons) and outer parallelism (typical data parallelism) are
demonstrated. Parallel I/O for Hadrian&amp;rsquo;s wall is followed by a slide
summarizing this quaint comparison between Big data parallelism and the
construction of a large wall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B1Of61fJF7WsNEtLOTNNN3dlNjQ/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Processing for Hadrian&amp;rsquo;s Wall
(9:24)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solving Problems in Concurrent Processors-Volume 1, with M.
Johnson, G. Lyzenga, S. Otto, J. Salmon, D. Walker, Prentice Hall,
March 1988.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.netlib.org/utk/lsi/pcwLSI/text/&#34;&gt;Parallel Computing Works!, with P. Messina, R. Williams, Morgan
Kaufman (1994).&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Sourcebook of Parallel Computing book edited by Jack Dongarra,
Ian Foster, Geoffrey Fox, William Gropp, Ken Kennedy, Linda Torczon,
and Andy White, Morgan Kaufmann, November 2002.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grids.ucs.indiana.edu/ptliupages/publications/SpringerEncyclopedia_Fox.pdf&#34;&gt;Geoffrey Fox Computational Sciences and Parallelism to appear in
Encyclopedia on Parallel Computing edited by David Padua and
published by
Springer.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We discuss Cyberinfrastructure for e-moreorlessanything or
moreorlessanything-Informatics and the basics of cloud computing. This
includes virtualization and the important &amp;lsquo;as a Service&amp;rsquo; components and
we go through several different definitions of cloud computing.Gartner&amp;rsquo;s
Technology Landscape includes hype cycle and priority matrix and covers
clouds and Big Data. The unit concludes with two simple examples of the
value of clouds for enterprise applications. Gartner also has specific
predictions for cloud computing growth areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B8936_ytjfjmdmF2Uy1vWS0xTFU/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/presentation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Presentation&#34;&gt; Introduction
(45)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cyberinfrastructure-for-e-applications&#34;&gt;Cyberinfrastructure for E-Applications&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This introduction describes Cyberinfrastructure or e-infrastructure and
its role in solving the electronic implementation of any problem where
e-moreorlessanything is another term for moreorlessanything-Informatics
and generalizes early discussion of e-Science and e-Business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B1Of61fJF7WsbXpEdF8zWFh4aXc/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Cloud Computing Introduction Part1
(13:34)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-cloud-computing-introduction&#34;&gt;What is Cloud Computing: Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cloud Computing is introduced with an operational definition involving
virtualization and efficient large data centers that can rent computers
in an elastic fashion. The role of services is essential &amp;ndash; it underlies
capabilities being offered in the cloud. The four basic aaS&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ndash;
Software (SaaS), Platform (Paas), Infrastructure (IaaS) and Network
(NaaS) &amp;ndash; are introduced with Research aaS and other capabilities (for
example Sensors aaS are discussed later) being built on top of these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B1Of61fJF7WsdDdsYkw0dXdHS1U/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; What is Cloud Computing Intro
(12:01)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-and-why-is-cloud-computing-other-views-i&#34;&gt;What and Why is Cloud Computing: Other Views I&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson contains 5 slides with diverse comments on &amp;lsquo;&amp;lsquo;what is cloud
computing&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; from the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B1Of61fJF7WsNm1jVVJMUVpCUlU/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Other Views I
(5:25)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B1Of61fJF7WsV1RJcldzRlctRlk/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Other Views II
(6:41)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B1Of61fJF7WsOUlxVHZ4MlN0RXc/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Other Views III
(7:27)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gartners-emerging-technology-landscape-for-clouds-and-big-data&#34;&gt;Gartner&amp;rsquo;s Emerging Technology Landscape for Clouds and Big Data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson gives Gartner&amp;rsquo;s projections around futures of cloud and Big
data. We start with a review of hype charts and then go into detailed
Gartner analyses of the Cloud and Big data areas. Big data itself is at
the top of the hype and by definition predictions of doom are emerging.
Before too much excitement sets in, note that spinach is above clouds
and Big data in Google trends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B1Of61fJF7WsaTg5aEZ0cHJuM0k/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Gartners Emerging Technology Landscape
(11:26)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;simple-examples-of-use-of-cloud-computing&#34;&gt;Simple Examples of use of Cloud Computing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This short lesson gives two examples of rather straightforward
commercial applications of cloud computing. One is server consolidation
for multiple Microsoft database applications and the second is the
benefits of scale comparing gmail to multiple smaller installations. It
ends with some fiscal comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B1Of61fJF7WsLTBoM0NpYzVxOHc/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Examples
(3:26)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;value-of-cloud-computing&#34;&gt;Value of Cloud Computing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some comments on fiscal value of cloud computing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B1Of61fJF7WsSFdfZ0hodDlnUGM/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Value of Cloud Computing
(4:20)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;resources-1&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/woorung/trend-and-future-of-cloud-computing&#34;&gt;http://www.slideshare.net/woorung/trend-and-future-of-cloud-computing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/JensNimis/cloud-computing-tutorial-jens-nimis&#34;&gt;http://www.slideshare.net/JensNimis/cloud-computing-tutorial-jens-nimis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://setandbma.wordpress.com/2012/08/10/hype-cycle-2012-emerging-technologies/&#34;&gt;https://setandbma.wordpress.com/2012/08/10/hype-cycle-2012-emerging-technologies/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://insights.dice.com/2013/01/23/big-data-hype-is-imploding-gartner-analyst-2/&#34;&gt;http://insights.dice.com/2013/01/23/big-data-hype-is-imploding-gartner-analyst-2/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://research.microsoft.com/pubs/78813/AJ18_EN.pdf&#34;&gt;http://research.microsoft.com/pubs/78813/AJ18_EN.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://static.googleusercontent.com/media/www.google.com/en//green/pdfs/google-green-computing.pdf&#34;&gt;http://static.googleusercontent.com/media/www.google.com/en//green/pdfs/google-green-computing.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;software-and-systems&#34;&gt;Software and Systems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We cover different views as to nature of architecture and application
for Cloud Computing. Then we discuss cloud software for the cloud
starting at virtual machine management (IaaS) and the broad Platform
(middleware) capabilities with examples from Amazon and academic
studies. We summarize the 21 layers and almost 300 software packages in
the HPC-ABDS Software Stack explaining how they are used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B8936_ytjfjmUHlEVG1wSUhDNnM/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/presentation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Presentation&#34;&gt; Software and Systems
(32)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-cloud-computing&#34;&gt;What is Cloud Computing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson gives some general remark of cloud systems from an
architecture and application perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B1Of61fJF7WsYlRhOHU5ci1seXc/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; What is Cloud Computing
(6:20)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction-to-cloud-software-architecture-iaas-and-paas-i&#34;&gt;Introduction to Cloud Software Architecture: IaaS and PaaS I&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We discuss cloud software for the cloud starting at virtual machine
management (IaaS) and the broad Platform (middleware) capabilities with
examples from Amazon and academic studies. We cover different views as
to nature of architecture and application for Cloud Computing. Then we
discuss cloud software for the cloud starting at virtual machine
management (IaaS) and the broad Platform (middleware) capabilities with
examples from Amazon and academic studies. We summarize the 21 layers
and almost 300 software packages in the HPC-ABDS Software Stack
explaining how they are used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B1Of61fJF7WsUm1XanBaaWtpQWM/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Intro to IaaS and PaaS I
(7:42)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B1Of61fJF7WsMXpfTTlvNDBkbTQ/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Intro to IaaS and PaaS II
(6:42)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We discuss cloud software for the cloud starting at virtual machine
management (IaaS) and the broad Platform (middleware) capabilities with
examples from Amazon and academic studies. We cover different views as
to nature of architecture and application for Cloud Computing. Then we
discuss cloud software for the cloud starting at virtual machine
management (IaaS) and the broad Platform (middleware) capabilities with
examples from Amazon and academic studies. We summarize the 21 layers
and almost 300 software packages in the HPC-ABDS Software Stack
explaining how they are used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/1AnyJYyh490&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Software Architecture:
(7:42)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/hVpFAUHcAd4&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; IaaS and PaaS II: (6:43)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;using-the-hpc-abds-software-stack&#34;&gt;Using the HPC-ABDS Software Stack&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the HPC-ABDS Software Stack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B1Of61fJF7WsUTdlNmlYWDUyTlE/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; ABDS
(27:50)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;resources-2&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/JensNimis/cloud-computing-tutorial-jens-nimis&#34;&gt;http://www.slideshare.net/JensNimis/cloud-computing-tutorial-jens-nimis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://research.microsoft.com/en-us/people/barga/sc09_cloudcomp_tutorial.pdf&#34;&gt;http://research.microsoft.com/en-us/people/barga/sc09_cloudcomp_tutorial.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://research.microsoft.com/en-us/um/redmond/events/cloudfutures2012/tuesday/Keynote_OpportunitiesAndChallenges_Yousef_Khalidi.pdf&#34;&gt;http://research.microsoft.com/en-us/um/redmond/events/cloudfutures2012/tuesday/Keynote_OpportunitiesAndChallenges_Yousef_Khalidi.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cloudonomic.blogspot.com/2009/02/cloud-taxonomy-and-ontology.html&#34;&gt;http://cloudonomic.blogspot.com/2009/02/cloud-taxonomy-and-ontology.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;architectures-applications-and-systems&#34;&gt;Architectures, Applications and Systems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We start with a discussion of Cloud (Data Center) Architectures with
physical setup, Green Computing issues and software models. We summarize
a 2014 Gartner analysis of Cloud computing providers. This is followed
by applications on the cloud including data intensive problems,
comparison with high performance computing, science clouds and the
Internet of Things. Remarks on Security, Fault Tolerance and
Synchronicity issues in cloud follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B8936_ytjfjmTHlzcGN3SzFNTTA/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;scroll: Architectures
(64)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cloud-data-center-architectures&#34;&gt;Cloud (Data Center) Architectures&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some remarks on what it takes to build (in software) a cloud ecosystem,
and why clouds are the data center of the future are followed by
pictures and discussions of several data centers from Microsoft (mainly)
and Google. The role of containers is stressed as part of modular data
centers that trade scalability for fault tolerance. Sizes of cloud
centers and supercomputers are discussed as is &amp;ldquo;green&amp;rdquo; computing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B1Of61fJF7WsYkxKelV2bTlMZ1k/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Coud Architecture
(8:38)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B1Of61fJF7WsRHJhN3VMaDJLTG8/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Cloud Data Center Architecture
(9:59)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;analysis-of-major-cloud-providers&#34;&gt;Analysis of Major Cloud Providers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gartner 2014 Analysis of leading cloud providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B1Of61fJF7WsUXBjRUJpX1BaSjA/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Analysis of Major Cloud Providers
(21:40)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;commercial-cloud-storage-trends&#34;&gt;Commercial Cloud Storage Trends&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use of Dropbox, iCloud, Box etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B1Of61fJF7WsZjR5VHQ2MXFmbjg/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Commercial Storage Trends
(3:07)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cloud-applications-i&#34;&gt;Cloud Applications I&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This short lesson discusses the need for security and issues in its
implementation. Clouds trade scalability for greater possibility of
faults but here clouds offer good support for recovery from faults. We
discuss both storage and program fault tolerance noting that parallel
computing is especially sensitive to faults as a fault in one task will
impact all other tasks in the parallel job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B1Of61fJF7WsYXlKVXk0aG8tZFk/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Cloud Applications I
(7:57)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B1Of61fJF7WseGVUNHhGTHpZbVU/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Cloud Applications II
(7:44)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;science-clouds&#34;&gt;Science Clouds&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Science Applications and Internet of Things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B1Of61fJF7Wsd0lZejhPTkItZEE/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Science Clouds
(19:26)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;security&#34;&gt;Security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This short lesson discusses the need for security and issues in its
implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B1Of61fJF7WsajE4QkljRUExLWM/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Security
(2:34)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments-on-fault-tolerance-and-synchronicity-constraints&#34;&gt;Comments on Fault Tolerance and Synchronicity Constraints&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clouds trade scalability for greater possibility of faults but here
clouds offer good support for recovery from faults. We discuss both
storage and program fault tolerance noting that parallel computing is
especially sensitive to faults as a fault in one task will impact all
other tasks in the parallel job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B1Of61fJF7WsdHRZV1VrTklWYVE/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Comments on Fault Tolerance and Synchronicity Constraints
(8:55)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;resources-3&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/woorung/trend-and-future-of-cloud-computing&#34;&gt;http://www.slideshare.net/woorung/trend-and-future-of-cloud-computing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/c/a/Cloud-Computing/AWS-Innovation-Means-Cloud-Domination-307831&#34;&gt;http://www.eweek.com/c/a/Cloud-Computing/AWS-Innovation-Means-Cloud-Domination-307831&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CSTI General Assembly 2012, Washington, D.C., USA Technical
Activities Coordinating Committee (TACC) Meeting, Data Management,
Cloud Computing and the Long Tail of Science October 2012 Dennis
Gannon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://research.microsoft.com/en-us/um/redmond/events/cloudfutures2012/tuesday/Keynote_OpportunitiesAndChallenges_Yousef_Khalidi.pdf&#34;&gt;http://research.microsoft.com/en-us/um/redmond/events/cloudfutures2012/tuesday/Keynote_OpportunitiesAndChallenges_Yousef_Khalidi.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.datacenterknowledge.com/archives/2011/05/10/uptime-institute-the-average-pue-is-1-8/&#34;&gt;http://www.datacenterknowledge.com/archives/2011/05/10/uptime-institute-the-average-pue-is-1-8/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://loosebolts.wordpress.com/2008/12/02/our-vision-for-generation-4-modular-data-centers-one-way-of-getting-it-just-right/&#34;&gt;https://loosebolts.wordpress.com/2008/12/02/our-vision-for-generation-4-modular-data-centers-one-way-of-getting-it-just-right/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mediafire.com/file/zzqna34282frr2f/koomeydatacenterelectuse2011finalversion.pdf&#34;&gt;http://www.mediafire.com/file/zzqna34282frr2f/koomeydatacenterelectuse2011finalversion.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/JensNimis/cloud-computing-tutorial-jens-nimis&#34;&gt;http://www.slideshare.net/JensNimis/cloud-computing-tutorial-jens-nimis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/botchagalupe/introduction-to-clouds-cloud-camp-columbus&#34;&gt;http://www.slideshare.net/botchagalupe/introduction-to-clouds-cloud-camp-columbus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.venus-c.eu/Pages/Home.aspx&#34;&gt;http://www.venus-c.eu/Pages/Home.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grids.ucs.indiana.edu/ptliupages/publications/Clouds_Technical_Computing_FoxGannonv2.pdf&#34;&gt;Geoffrey Fox and Dennis Gannon Using Clouds for Technical Computing
To be published in Proceedings of HPC 2012 Conference at Cetraro,
Italy June 28
2012&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://berkeleydatascience.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/20120119berkeley.pdf&#34;&gt;https://berkeleydatascience.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/20120119berkeley.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taming The Big Data Tidal Wave: Finding Opportunities in Huge Data
Streams with Advanced Analytics, Bill Franks Wiley ISBN:
978-1-118-20878-6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fisheritcenter.haas.berkeley.edu/Big_Data/index.html&#34;&gt;Anjul Bhambhri, VP of Big Data,
IBM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conquering Big Data with the Oracle Information Model, Helen Sun,
Oracle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://businessinnovation.berkeley.edu/fisher-cio-leadership-program/&#34;&gt;Hugh Williams VP Experience, Search &amp;amp; Platforms,
eBay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%3Chttp://www.nitrd.gov/nitrdgroups/images/7/73/D_Gannon_2025_scientific_computing_environments.pdf&#34;&gt;Dennis Gannon, Scientific Computing
Environments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://research.microsoft.com/en-us/um/redmond/events/cloudfutures2012/tuesday/Keynote_OpportunitiesAndChallenges_Yousef_Khalidi.pdf&#34;&gt;http://research.microsoft.com/en-us/um/redmond/events/cloudfutures2012/tuesday/Keynote_OpportunitiesAndChallenges_Yousef_Khalidi.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.datacenterknowledge.com/archives/2011/05/10/uptime-institute-the-average-pue-is-1-8/&#34;&gt;http://www.datacenterknowledge.com/archives/2011/05/10/uptime-institute-the-average-pue-is-1-8/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://loosebolts.wordpress.com/2008/12/02/our-vision-for-generation-4-modular-data-centers-one-way-of-getting-it-just-right/&#34;&gt;https://loosebolts.wordpress.com/2008/12/02/our-vision-for-generation-4-modular-data-centers-one-way-of-getting-it-just-right/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mediafire.com/file/zzqna34282frr2f/koomeydatacenterelectuse2011finalversion.pdf&#34;&gt;http://www.mediafire.com/file/zzqna34282frr2f/koomeydatacenterelectuse2011finalversion.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://searchcloudcomputing.techtarget.com/feature/Cloud-computing-experts-forecast-the-market-climate-in-2014&#34;&gt;http://searchcloudcomputing.techtarget.com/feature/Cloud-computing-experts-forecast-the-market-climate-in-2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/botchagalupe/introduction-to-clouds-cloud-camp-columbus&#34;&gt;http://www.slideshare.net/botchagalupe/introduction-to-clouds-cloud-camp-columbus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/woorung/trend-and-future-of-cloud-computing&#34;&gt;http://www.slideshare.net/woorung/trend-and-future-of-cloud-computing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.venus-c.eu/Pages/Home.aspx&#34;&gt;http://www.venus-c.eu/Pages/Home.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kpcb.com/internet-trends&#34;&gt;http://www.kpcb.com/internet-trends&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-systems&#34;&gt;Data Systems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We describe the way users and data interact with a cloud system. The
unit concludes with the treatment of data in the cloud from an
architecture perspective and Big Data Processing from an application
perspective with commercial examples including eBay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B1Of61fJF7WsN1RPVFRLUGJLZGs/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/presentation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Presentation&#34;&gt; Data Systems
(49)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-10-interaction-scenarios-access-patterns-i&#34;&gt;The 10 Interaction scenarios (access patterns) I&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next 3 lessons describe the way users and data interact with the
system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B1Of61fJF7WsWldDNm1oNXdPQmc/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; The 10 Interaction scenarios I
(10:26)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-10-interaction-scenarios-science-examples&#34;&gt;The 10 Interaction scenarios. Science Examples&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson describes the way users and data interact with the system
for some science examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B1Of61fJF7WsQTlvLWs4cm5NRE0/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; The 10 Interaction scenarios. Science Examples
(16:34)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;remaining-general-access-patterns&#34;&gt;Remaining general access patterns&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson describe the way users and data interact with the system for
the final set of examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B1Of61fJF7WsYVVRWmdpanV4Vlk/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Access Patterns
(11:36)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-in-the-cloud&#34;&gt;Data in the Cloud&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Databases, File systems, Object Stores and NOSQL are discussed and
compared. The way to build a modern data repository in the cloud is
introduced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B1Of61fJF7WsRzR6eHZwelVuOG8/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Data in the Cloud
(10:24)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;applications-processing-big-data&#34;&gt;Applications Processing Big Data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson collects remarks on Big data processing from several
sources: Berkeley, Teradata, IBM, Oracle and eBay with architectures and
application opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B1Of61fJF7WsUG9UVGFOQXNXbnc/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Processing Big Data
(8:45)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;resources-4&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bigdatawg.nist.gov/_uploadfiles/M0311_v2_2965963213.pdf&#34;&gt;http://bigdatawg.nist.gov/_uploadfiles/M0311_v2_2965963213.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dzone.com/articles/hadoop-t-etl&#34;&gt;https://dzone.com/articles/hadoop-t-etl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://venublog.com/2013/07/16/hadoop-summit-2013-hive-authorization/&#34;&gt;http://venublog.com/2013/07/16/hadoop-summit-2013-hive-authorization/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://indico.cern.ch/event/214784/session/5/contribution/410&#34;&gt;https://indico.cern.ch/event/214784/session/5/contribution/410&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://asd.gsfc.nasa.gov/archive/hubble/a_pdf/news/facts/FS14.pdf&#34;&gt;http://asd.gsfc.nasa.gov/archive/hubble/a_pdf/news/facts/FS14.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.teradata.com/data-points/announcing-teradata-aster-big-analytics-appliance/&#34;&gt;http://blogs.teradata.com/data-points/announcing-teradata-aster-big-analytics-appliance/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wikibon.org/w/images/2/20/Cloud-BigData.png&#34;&gt;http://wikibon.org/w/images/2/20/Cloud-BigData.png&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://hortonworks.com/hadoop/yarn/&#34;&gt;http://hortonworks.com/hadoop/yarn/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://berkeleydatascience.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/20120119berkeley.pdf&#34;&gt;https://berkeleydatascience.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/20120119berkeley.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fisheritcenter.haas.berkeley.edu/Big_Data/index.html&#34;&gt;http://fisheritcenter.haas.berkeley.edu/Big_Data/index.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modules: e-Commerce and LifeStyle</title>
      <link>/modules/bigdataapplications/2020/applications/lifestyle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/bigdataapplications/2020/applications/lifestyle/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Recommender systems operate under the hood of such widely recognized
sites as Amazon, eBay, Monster and Netflix where everything is a
recommendation. This involves a symbiotic relationship between vendor
and buyer whereby the buyer provides the vendor with information about
their preferences, while the vendor then offers recommendations tailored
to match their needs. Kaggle competitions h improve the success of the
Netflix and other recommender systems. Attention is paid to models that
are used to compare how changes to the systems affect their overall
performance. It is interesting that the humble ranking has become such a
dominant driver of the world&amp;rsquo;s economy. More examples of recommender
systems are given from Google News, Retail stores and in depth Yahoo!
covering the multi-faceted criteria used in deciding recommendations on
web sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The formulation of recommendations in terms of points in a space or bag
is given where bags of item properties, user properties, rankings and
users are useful. Detail is given on basic principles behind recommender
systems: user-based collaborative filtering, which uses similarities in
user rankings to predict their interests, and the Pearson correlation,
used to statistically quantify correlations between users viewed as
points in a space of items. Items are viewed as points in a space of
users in item-based collaborative filtering. The Cosine Similarity is
introduced, the difference between implicit and explicit ratings and the
k Nearest Neighbors algorithm. General features like the curse of
dimensionality in high dimensions are discussed. A simple Python k
Nearest Neighbor code and its application to an artificial data set in 3
dimensions is given. Results are visualized in Matplotlib in 2D and with
Plotviz in 3D. The concept of a training and a testing set are
introduced with training set pre labeled. Recommender system are used to
discuss clustering with k-means based clustering methods used and their
results examined in Plotviz. The original labelling is compared to
clustering results and extension to 28 clusters given. General issues in
clustering are discussed including local optima, the use of annealing to
avoid this and value of heuristic algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;s-recommender&#34;&gt;Recommender Systems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We introduce Recommender systems as an optimization technology used in a
variety of applications and contexts online. They operate in the
background of such widely recognized sites as Amazon, eBay, Monster and
Netflix where everything is a recommendation. This involves a symbiotic
relationship between vendor and buyer whereby the buyer provides the
vendor with information about their preferences, while the vendor then
offers recommendations tailored to match their needs, to the benefit of
both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There follows an exploration of the Kaggle competition site, other
recommender systems and Netflix, as well as competitions held to improve
the success of the Netflix recommender system. Finally attention is paid
to models that are used to compare how changes to the systems affect
their overall performance. It is interesting how the humble ranking has
become such a dominant driver of the world&amp;rsquo;s economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B6wqDMIyK2P7YkIwczVfQlJqVG8&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/presentation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Presentation&#34;&gt; Lifestyle Recommender
(45)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;recommender-systems-as-an-optimization-problem&#34;&gt;Recommender Systems as an Optimization Problem&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We define a set of general recommender systems as matching of items to
people or perhaps collections of items to collections of people where
items can be other people, products in a store, movies, jobs, events,
web pages etc. We present this as &amp;ldquo;yet another optimization problem&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kO023BIW2dw&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Recommender Systems I
(8:06)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;recommender-systems-introduction&#34;&gt;Recommender Systems Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We give a general discussion of recommender systems and point out that
they are particularly valuable in long tail of tems (to be recommended)
that are not commonly known. We pose them as a rating system and relate
them to information retrieval rating systems. We can contrast
recommender systems based on user profile and context; the most familiar
collaborative filtering of others ranking; item properties; knowledge
and hybrid cases mixing some or all of these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/KbjBKrzFYKg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Recommender Systems Introduction
(12:56)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;kaggle-competitions&#34;&gt;Kaggle Competitions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look at Kaggle competitions with examples from web site. In
particular we discuss an Irvine class project involving ranking jokes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/DFH7GPrbsJA&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Kaggle Competitions: (3:36)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/warning.png&#34; alt=&#34;Warning&#34;&gt; &lt;em&gt;Please not that we typically do not accept any projects
using kaggle data for this classes. This class is not about winning a
kaggle competition and if done wrong it does not fullfill the minimum
requiremnt for this class. Please consult with the instructor.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;examples-of-recommender-systems&#34;&gt;Examples of Recommender Systems&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We go through a list of 9 recommender systems from the same Irvine
class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/1Eh1epQj-EQ&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Examples of Recommender Systems
(1:00)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;netflix-on-recommender-systems&#34;&gt;Netflix on Recommender Systems&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We summarize some interesting points from a tutorial from Netflix for
whom &lt;em&gt;everything is a recommendation&lt;/em&gt;. Rankings are given in multiple
categories and categories that reflect user interests are especially
important. Criteria used include explicit user preferences, implicit
based on ratings and hybrid methods as well as freshness and diversity.
Netflix tries to explain the rationale of its recommendations. We give
some data on Netflix operations and some methods used in its recommender
systems. We describe the famous Netflix Kaggle competition to improve
its rating system. The analogy to maximizing click through rate is given
and the objectives of optimization are given.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ModhdIT9D24&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Netflix on Recommender Systems
(14:20)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next we go through Netflix&amp;rsquo;s methodology in letting data speak for
itself in optimizing the recommender engine. An example iis given on
choosing self produced movies. A/B testing is discussed with examples
showing how testing does allow optimizing of sophisticated criteria.
This lesson is concluded by comments on Netflix technology and the full
spectrum of issues that are involved including user interface, data, AB
testing, systems and architectures. We comment on optimizing for a
household rather than optimizing for individuals in household.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/B8cjaOQ57LI&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Consumer Data Science (13:04)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-examples-of-recommender-systems&#34;&gt;Other Examples of Recommender Systems&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We continue the discussion of recommender systems and their use in
e-commerce. More examples are given from Google News, Retail stores and
in depth Yahoo! covering the multi-faceted criteria used in deciding
recommendations on web sites. Then the formulation of recommendations in
terms of points in a space or bag is given.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here bags of item properties, user properties, rankings and users are
useful. Then we go into detail on basic principles behind recommender
systems: user-based collaborative filtering, which uses similarities in
user rankings to predict their interests, and the Pearson correlation,
used to statistically quantify correlations between users viewed as
points in a space of items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B6wqDMIyK2P7UVloVElaZ2FXcTg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/presentation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Presentation&#34;&gt; Lifestyle Recommender
(49)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We start with a quick recap of recommender systems from previous unit;
what they are with brief examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PwS8UE4TDS4&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Recap and Examples of Recommender Systems
(5:48)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;examples-of-recommender-systems-1&#34;&gt;Examples of Recommender Systems&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We give 2 examples in more detail: namely Google News and Markdown in
Retail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/og07mH9fU0M&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Examples of Recommender Systems
(8:34)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;recommender-systems-in-yahoo-use-case-example&#34;&gt;Recommender Systems in Yahoo Use Case Example&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We describe in greatest detail the methods used to optimize Yahoo web
sites. There are two lessons discussing general approach and a third
lesson examines a particular personalized Yahoo page with its different
components. We point out the different criteria that must be blended in
making decisions; these criteria include analysis of what user does
after a particular page is clicked; is the user satisfied and cannot
that we quantified by purchase decisions etc. We need to choose
Articles, ads, modules, movies, users, updates, etc to optimize metrics
such as relevance score, CTR, revenue, engagement.These lesson stress
that if though we have big data, the recommender data is sparse. We
discuss the approach that involves both batch (offline) and on-line
(real time) components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/FBn7HpGFNvg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Recap of Recommender Systems II
(8:46)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/VS2Y4lAiP5A&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Recap of Recommender Systems III
(10:48)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/HrRJWEF8EfU&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Case Study of Recommender systems
(3:21)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;user-based-nearest-neighbor-collaborative-filtering&#34;&gt;User-based nearest-neighbor collaborative filtering&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collaborative filtering is a core approach to recommender systems. There
is user-based and item-based collaborative filtering and here we discuss
the user-based case. Here similarities in user rankings allow one to
predict their interests, and typically this quantified by the Pearson
correlation, used to statistically quantify correlations between users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/lsf_AE-8dSk&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; User-based nearest-neighbor collaborative filtering I
(7:20)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/U7-qeX2ItPk&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; User-based nearest-neighbor collaborative filtering II
(7:29)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;vector-space-formulation-of-recommender-systems&#34;&gt;Vector Space Formulation of Recommender Systems&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We go through recommender systems thinking of them as formulated in a
funny vector space. This suggests using clustering to make
recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/IlQUZOXlaSU&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Vector Space Formulation of Recommender Systems new
(9:06)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://pages.cs.wisc.edu/~beechung/icml11-tutorial/&#34;&gt;http://pages.cs.wisc.edu/~beechung/icml11-tutorial/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;item-based-collaborative-filtering-and-its-technologies&#34;&gt;Item-based Collaborative Filtering and its Technologies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We move on to item-based collaborative filtering where items are viewed
as points in a space of users. The Cosine Similarity is introduced, the
difference between implicit and explicit ratings and the k Nearest
Neighbors algorithm. General features like the curse of dimensionality
in high dimensions are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B6wqDMIyK2P7UExxVFc5YlpOZ28&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/presentation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Presentation&#34;&gt; Lifestyle Filtering
(18)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;item-based-collaborative-filtering&#34;&gt;Item-based Collaborative Filtering&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We covered user-based collaborative filtering in the previous unit. Here
we start by discussing memory-based real time and model based offline
(batch) approaches. Now we look at item-based collaborative filtering
where items are viewed in the space of users and the cosine measure is
used to quantify distances. WE discuss optimizations and how batch
processing can help. We discuss different Likert ranking scales and
issues with new items that do not have a significant number of rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HTdYGaOTlFI&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Item Based Filtering
(11:18)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/SM8EJdAa4mw&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; k Nearest Neighbors and High Dimensional Spaces
(7:16)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;s-knn&#34;&gt;k-Nearest Neighbors and High Dimensional Spaces&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We define the k Nearest Neighbor algorithms and present the Python
software but do not use it. We give examples from Wikipedia and describe
performance issues. This algorithm illustrates the curse of
dimensionality. If items were a real vectors in a low dimension space,
there would be faster solution methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/2NqUsDGQDy8&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; k Nearest Neighbors and High Dimensional Spaces
(10:03)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;recommender-systems---k-neighbors&#34;&gt;Recommender Systems - K-Neighbors&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next we provide some sample Python code for the k Nearest Neighbor and its application to
an artificial data set in 3 dimensions. Results are visualized in
Matplotlib in 2D and with Plotviz in 3D. The concept of training and
testing sets are introduced with training set pre-labelled.
This lesson is adapted from the Python k Nearest Neighbor code found on the
web associated with a book by Harrington on Machine Learning [??]. There are
two data sets. First we consider a set of 4 2D vectors divided into two
categories (clusters) and use k=3 Nearest Neighbor algorithm to classify
3 test points. Second we consider a 3D dataset that has already been
classified and show how to normalize. In this lesson we just use
Matplotlib to give 2D plots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lesson goes through an example of using k NN classification
algorithm by dividing dataset into 2 subsets. One is training set with
initial classification; the other is test point to be classified by k=3
NN using training set. The code records fraction of points with a
different classification from that input. One can experiment with
different sizes of the two subsets. The Python implementation of
algorithm is analyzed in detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;plotviz&#34;&gt;Plotviz&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The clustering methods are used and their results examined in
Plotviz. The original labelling is compared to clustering results and
extension to 28 clusters given.  General issues in clustering are
discussed including local optima, the use of annealing to avoid this
and value of heuristic algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;files&#34;&gt;Files&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/knn/kNN.py&#34;&gt;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/knn/kNN.py&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/knn/kNN_Driver.py&#34;&gt;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/knn/kNN_Driver.py&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/knn/dating_test_set2.txt&#34;&gt;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/knn/dating_test_set2.txt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/knn/clusterFinal-M3-C3Dating-ReClustered.pviz&#34;&gt;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/knn/clusterFinal-M3-C3Dating-ReClustered.pviz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/knn/dating_rating_original_labels.pviz&#34;&gt;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/knn/dating_rating_original_labels.pviz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/knn/clusterFinal-M30-C28.pviz&#34;&gt;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/knn/clusterFinal-M30-C28.pviz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/plotviz/clusterfinal_m3_c3dating_reclustered.pviz&#34;&gt;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/plotviz/clusterfinal_m3_c3dating_reclustered.pviz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/plotviz/fungi_lsu_3_15_to_3_26_zeroidx.pviz&#34;&gt;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/plotviz/fungi_lsu_3_15_to_3_26_zeroidx.pviz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;resources-k-means&#34;&gt;Resources k-means&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/xamat/building-largescale-realworld-recommender-systems-recsys2012-tutorial&#34;&gt;http://www.slideshare.net/xamat/building-largescale-realworld-recommender-systems-recsys2012-tutorial&lt;/a&gt; [@www-slideshare-building]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ifi.uzh.ch/ce/teaching/spring2012/16-Recommender-Systems_Slides.pdf&#34;&gt;http://www.ifi.uzh.ch/ce/teaching/spring2012/16-Recommender-Systems_Slides.pdf&lt;/a&gt; [@www-ifi-teaching]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com/&#34;&gt;https://www.kaggle.com/&lt;/a&gt; [@www-kaggle]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ics.uci.edu/~welling/teaching/CS77Bwinter12/CS77B_w12.html&#34;&gt;http://www.ics.uci.edu/~welling/teaching/CS77Bwinter12/CS77B_w12.html&lt;/a&gt; [@www-ics-uci-welling]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://berkeleydatascience.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/20120117berkeley1.pdf&#34;&gt;Jeff
Hammerbacher&lt;/a&gt;[@20120117berkeley1]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.techworld.com/news/apps/netflix-foretells-house-of-cards-success-with-cassandra-big-data-engine-3437514/&#34;&gt;http://www.techworld.com/news/apps/netflix-foretells-house-of-cards-success-with-cassandra-big-data-engine-3437514/&lt;/a&gt; [@www-techworld-netflix]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A/B_testing&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A/B_testing&lt;/a&gt; [@wikipedia-ABtesting]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infoq.com/presentations/Netflix-Architecture&#34;&gt;http://www.infoq.com/presentations/Netflix-Architecture&lt;/a&gt; [@www-infoq-architec]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modules: Health Informatics</title>
      <link>/modules/bigdataapplications/2020/applications/health/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/bigdataapplications/2020/applications/health/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B6wqDMIyK2P7UGRJNmlkYkNkQk0&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/presentation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Presentation&#34;&gt; Health Informatics
(131)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section starts by discussing general aspects of Big Data and Health
including data sizes, different areas including genomics, EBI, radiology
and the Quantified Self movement. We review current state of health care
and trends associated with it including increased use of Telemedicine.
We summarize an industry survey by GE and Accenture and an impressive
exemplar Cloud-based medicine system from Potsdam. We give some details
of big data in medicine. Some remarks on Cloud computing and Health
focus on security and privacy issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We survey an April 2013 McKinsey report on the Big Data revolution in US
health care; a Microsoft report in this area and a European Union report
on how Big Data will allow patient centered care in the future. Examples
are given of the Internet of Things, which will have great impact on
health including wearables. A study looks at 4 scenarios for healthcare
in 2032. Two are positive, one middle of the road and one negative. The
final topic is Genomics, Proteomics and Information Visualization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;big-data-and-health&#34;&gt;Big Data and Health&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson starts with general aspects of Big Data and Health including
listing subareas where Big data important. Data sizes are given in
radiology, genomics, personalized medicine, and the Quantified Self
movement, with sizes and access to European Bioinformatics Institute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZkM-yZJQ1Cg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Big Data and Health
(10:02)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;status-of-healthcare-today&#34;&gt;Status of Healthcare Today&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This covers trends of costs and type of healthcare with low cost genomes
and an aging population. Social media and government Brain initiative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x9TpdMBqYrk&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Status of Healthcare Today
(16:09)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;telemedicine-virtual-health&#34;&gt;Telemedicine (Virtual Health)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This describes increasing use of telemedicine and how we tried and
failed to do this in 1994.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Pe4CVXQaL_U&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Telemedicine
(8:21)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;medical-big-data-in-the-clouds&#34;&gt;Medical Big Data in the Clouds&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An impressive exemplar Cloud-based medicine system from Potsdam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GldSVijkJcM&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Medical Big Data in the Clouds
(15:02)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;medical-image-big-data&#34;&gt;Medical image Big Data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GOcVtwx2R2k&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Medical Image Big Data
(6:33)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;clouds-and-health&#34;&gt;Clouds and Health&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/9Whkl_UPS5g&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Clouds and Health (4:35)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mckinsey-report-on-the-big-data-revolution-in-us-health-care&#34;&gt;McKinsey Report on the big-data revolution in US health care&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson covers 9 aspects of the McKinsey report. These are the
convergence of multiple positive changes has created a tipping point for&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;innovation; Primary data pools are at the heart of the big data
revolution in healthcare; Big data is changing the paradigm: these are
the value pathways; Applying early successes at scale could reduce US
healthcare costs by $300 billion to $450 billion; Most new big-data
applications target consumers and providers across pathways; Innovations
are weighted towards influencing individual decision-making levers; Big
data innovations use a range of public, acquired, and proprietary data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;types; Organizations implementing a big data transformation should
provide the leadership required for the associated cultural
transformation; Companies must develop a range of big data capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fu-TWnIk980&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; McKinsey Report
(14:53)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;microsoft-report-on-big-data-in-health&#34;&gt;Microsoft Report on Big Data in Health&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson identifies data sources as Clinical Data, Pharma &amp;amp; Life
Science Data, Patient &amp;amp; Consumer Data, Claims &amp;amp; Cost Data and
Correlational Data. Three approaches are Live data feed, Advanced
analytics and Social analytics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/PjffvVgj1PE&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Microsoft Report on Big Data in Health
(2:26)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;eu-report-on-redesigning-health-in-europe-for-2020&#34;&gt;EU Report on Redesigning health in Europe for 2020&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson summarizes an EU Report on Redesigning health in Europe for
2020. The power of data is seen as a lever for change in My Data, My
decisions; Liberate the data; Connect up everything; Revolutionize
health; and Include Everyone removing the current correlation between
health and wealth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/9mbt_ZSs0iw&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; EU Report on Redesigning health in Europe for 2020
(5:00)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;medicine-and-the-internet-of-things&#34;&gt;Medicine and the Internet of Things&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet of Things will have great impact on health including
telemedicine and wearables. Examples are given.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Jk3EeFzZnuU&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Medicine and the Internet of Things
(8:17)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;extrapolating-to-2032&#34;&gt;Extrapolating to 2032&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A study looks at 4 scenarios for healthcare in 2032. Two are positive,
one middle of the road and one negative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=a5G4HACeokg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Extrapolating to 2032
(15:13)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;genomics-proteomics-and-information-visualization&#34;&gt;Genomics, Proteomics and Information Visualization&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A study of an Azure application with an Excel frontend and a cloud BLAST
backend starts this lesson. This is followed by a big data analysis of
personal genomics and an analysis of a typical DNA sequencing analytics
pipeline. The Protein Sequence Universe is defined and used to motivate
Multi dimensional Scaling MDS. Sammon&amp;rsquo;s method is defined and its use
illustrated by a metagenomics example. Subtleties in use of MDS include
a monotonic mapping of the dissimilarity function. The application to
the COG Proteomics dataset is discussed. We note that the MDS approach
is related to the well known chisq method and some aspects of nonlinear
minimization of chisq (Least Squares) are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zGzBtxq1ZRE&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Genomics, Proteomics and Information Visualization
(6:56)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next we continue the discussion of the COG Protein Universe introduced
in the last lesson. It is shown how Proteomics clusters are clearly seen
in the Universe browser. This motivates a side remark on different
clustering methods applied to metagenomics. Then we discuss the
Generative Topographic Map GTM method that can be used in dimension
reduction when original data is in a metric space and is in this case
faster than MDS as GTM computational complexity scales like N not N
squared as seen in MDS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples are given of GTM including an application to topic models in
Information Retrieval. Indiana University has developed a deterministic
annealing improvement of GTM. 3 separate clusterings are projected for
visualization and show very different structure emphasizing the
importance of visualizing results of data analytics. The final slide
shows an application of MDS to generate and visualize phylogenetic
trees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\TODO{These two videos need to be uploaded to youtube}
&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B5plU-u0wqMobXdEQWRHWl95UTA/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Genomics, Proteomics and Information Visualization I
(10:33)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B5plU-u0wqModlhmdVUwdGlQNTA/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Genomics, Proteomics and Information Visualization: II
(7:41)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B8936_ytjfjmX0lEMWhMX2kwRHc&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/presentation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Presentation&#34;&gt; Proteomics and Information Visualization
(131)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.nci.nih.gov/display/CIP/CIP+Survey+of+Biomedical+Imaging+Archives&#34;&gt;https://wiki.nci.nih.gov/display/CIP/CIP+Survey+of+Biomedical+Imaging+Archives&lt;/a&gt; [@wiki-nih-cip-survey]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grids.ucs.indiana.edu/ptliupages/publications/Where%20does%20all%20the%20data%20come%20from%20v7.pdf&#34;&gt;http://grids.ucs.indiana.edu/ptliupages/publications/Where\%20does\%20all\%20the\%20data\%20come\%20from\%20v7.pdf&lt;/a&gt; [@fox2011does]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ieee-icsc.org/ICSC2010/Tony%20Hey%20-%2020100923.pdf&#34;&gt;http://www.ieee-icsc.org/ICSC2010/Tony\%20Hey\%20-\%2020100923.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt;(this link does not exist any longer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://quantifiedself.com/larry-smarr/&#34;&gt;http://quantifiedself.com/larry-smarr/&lt;/a&gt; [@smarr13self]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ebi.ac.uk/Information/Brochures/&#34;&gt;http://www.ebi.ac.uk/Information/Brochures/&lt;/a&gt; [@www-ebi-aboutus]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kpcb.com/internet-trends&#34;&gt;http://www.kpcb.com/internet-trends&lt;/a&gt; [@www-kleinerperkins-internet-trends]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/drsteventucker/wearable-health-fitness-trackers-and-the-quantified-self&#34;&gt;http://www.slideshare.net/drsteventucker/wearable-health-fitness-trackers-and-the-quantified-self&lt;/a&gt; [@www-slideshare-wearable-quantified-self]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.siam.org/meetings/sdm13/sun.pdf&#34;&gt;http://www.siam.org/meetings/sdm13/sun.pdf&lt;/a&gt; [@archive&amp;ndash;big-data-analytics-healthcare]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Calico_%28company%29&#34;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Calico_\%28company\%29&lt;/a&gt; [@www-wiki-calico]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/GSW_Worldwide/2015-health-trends&#34;&gt;http://www.slideshare.net/GSW_Worldwide/2015-health-trends&lt;/a&gt; [@www-slideshare-2015-health trends]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.accenture.com/SiteCollectionDocuments/PDF/Accenture-Industrial-Internet-Changing-Competitive-Landscape-Industries.pdf&#34;&gt;http://www.accenture.com/SiteCollectionDocuments/PDF/Accenture-Industrial-Internet-Changing-Competitive-Landscape-Industries.pdf&lt;/a&gt; [@www-accenture-insight-industrial-internet]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/schappy/how-realtime-analysis-turns-big-medical-data-into-precision-medicine&#34;&gt;http://www.slideshare.net/schappy/how-realtime-analysis-turns-big-medical-data-into-precision-medicine&lt;/a&gt; [@www-slideshare-big-medical-data-medicine]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://medcitynews.com/2013/03/the-body-in-bytes-medical-images-as-a-source-of-healthcare-big-data-infographic/&#34;&gt;http://medcitynews.com/2013/03/the-body-in-bytes-medical-images-as-a-source-of-healthcare-big-data-infographic/&lt;/a&gt; [@medcitynews-bytes-medical-images]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://healthinformatics.wikispaces.com/file/view/cloud_computing.ppt&#34;&gt;http://healthinformatics.wikispaces.com/file/view/cloud_computing.ppt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt; (this link does not exist any longer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/mckinsey/industries/healthcare%20systems%20and%20services/our%20insights/the%20big%20data%20revolution%20in%20us%20health%20care/the_big_data_revolution_in_healthcare.ashx&#34;&gt;https://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/mckinsey/industries/healthcare%20systems%20and%20services/our%20insights/the%20big%20data%20revolution%20in%20us%20health%20care/the_big_data_revolution_in_healthcare.ashx&lt;/a&gt; [@www-mckinsey-industries-healthcare]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://partner.microsoft.com/download/global/40193764&#34;&gt;https://partner.microsoft.com/download/global/40193764&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt; (this link does not exist any longer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ec.europa.eu/eip/ageing/file/353/download_en?token=8gECi1RO&#34;&gt;https://ec.europa.eu/eip/ageing/file/353/download_en?token=8gECi1RO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.liveathos.com/apparel/app&#34;&gt;http://www.liveathos.com/apparel/app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://debategraph.org/Poster.aspx?aID=77&#34;&gt;http://debategraph.org/Poster.aspx?aID=77&lt;/a&gt; [@debategraph-poster]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oerc.ox.ac.uk/downloads/presentations-from-events/microsoftworkshop/gannon&#34;&gt;http://www.oerc.ox.ac.uk/downloads/presentations-from-events/microsoftworkshop/gannon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt;(this link does not exist any longer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.delsall.org&#34;&gt;http://www.delsall.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt; (this link does not exist any longer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://salsahpc.indiana.edu/millionseq/mina/16SrRNA_index.html&#34;&gt;http://salsahpc.indiana.edu/millionseq/mina/16SrRNA_index.html&lt;/a&gt; [@www-salsahpc-millionseq]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.geatbx.com/docu/fcnindex-01.html&#34;&gt;http://www.geatbx.com/docu/fcnindex-01.html&lt;/a&gt; [@www-geatbx-parametric-optimization]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modules: Overview of Data Science</title>
      <link>/modules/bigdataapplications/2020/applications/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/bigdataapplications/2020/applications/overview/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is Big Data, Data Analytics and X-Informatics?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We start with X-Informatics and its rallying cry. The growing number of
jobs in data science is highlighted. The first unit offers a look at the
phenomenon described as the Data Deluge starting with its broad
features. Data science and the famous DIKW (Data to Information to
Knowledge to Wisdom) pipeline are covered. Then more detail is given on
the flood of data from Internet and Industry applications with eBay and
General Electric discussed in most detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next unit, we continue the discussion of the data deluge with a
focus on scientific research. He takes a first peek at data from the
Large Hadron Collider considered later as physics Informatics and gives
some biology examples. He discusses the implication of data for the
scientific method which is changing with the data-intensive methodology
joining observation, theory and simulation as basic methods. Two broad
classes of data are the long tail of sciences: many users with
individually modest data adding up to a lot; and a myriad of Internet
connected devices &amp;ndash; the Internet of Things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We give an initial technical overview of cloud computing as pioneered by
companies like Amazon, Google and Microsoft with new centers holding up
to a million servers. The benefits of Clouds in terms of power
consumption and the environment are also touched upon, followed by a
list of the most critical features of Cloud computing with a comparison
to supercomputing. Features of the data deluge are discussed with a
salutary example where more data did better than more thought. Then
comes Data science and one part of it ~~ data analytics ~~ the large
algorithms that crunch the big data to give big wisdom. There are many
ways to describe data science and several are discussed to give a good
composite picture of this emerging field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-science-generics-and-commercial-data-deluge&#34;&gt;Data Science generics and Commercial Data Deluge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We start with X-Informatics and its rallying cry. The growing number of
jobs in data science is highlighted. This unit offers a look at the
phenomenon described as the Data Deluge starting with its broad
features. Then he discusses data science and the famous DIKW (Data to
Information to Knowledge to Wisdom) pipeline. Then more detail is given
on the flood of data from Internet and Industry applications with eBay
and General Electric discussed in most detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B88HKpainTSfenJ4dEZQOUxZSmM&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/presentation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Presentation&#34;&gt; Commercial Data Deluge
(45)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-x-informatics-and-its-motto&#34;&gt;What is X-Informatics and its Motto&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This discusses trends that are driven by and accompany Big data. We give
some key terms including data, information, knowledge, wisdom, data
analytics and data science. We discuss how clouds running Data Analytics
Collaboratively processing Big Data can solve problems in X-Informatics.
We list many values of X you can defined in various activities across
the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8T0OtdR9Bp4&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; X Informatics
(9:49)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;jobs&#34;&gt;Jobs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big data is especially important as there are some many related jobs. We
illustrate this for both cloud computing and data science from reports
by Microsoft and the McKinsey institute respectively. We show a plot
from LinkedIn showing rapid increase in the number of data science and
analytics jobs as a function of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/pRlfEigUJAc&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Jobs (2:58)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-deluge-general-structure&#34;&gt;Data Deluge: General Structure&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look at some broad features of the data deluge starting with the size
of data in various areas especially in science research. We give
examples from real world of the importance of big data and illustrate
how it is integrated into an enterprise IT architecture. We give some
views as to what characterizes Big data and why data science is a
science that is needed to interpret all the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/mPJ9twAFRQU&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Data Deluge (13:04)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-science-process&#34;&gt;Data Science: Process&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stress the DIKW pipeline: Data becomes information that becomes
knowledge and then wisdom, policy and decisions. This pipeline is
illustrated with Google maps and we show how complex the ecosystem of
data, transformations (filters) and its derived forms is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/ydH34L-z0Rk&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Data Science Process (4:27)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-deluge-internet&#34;&gt;Data Deluge: Internet&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We give examples of Big data from the Internet with Tweets, uploaded
photos and an illustration of the vitality and size of many commodity
applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/rtuq5y2Bx2g&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Internet (3:42)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-deluge-business&#34;&gt;Data Deluge: Business&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We give examples including the Big data that enables wind farms, city
transportation, telephone operations, machines with health monitors, the
banking, manufacturing and retail industries both online and offline in
shopping malls. We give examples from ebay showing how analytics
allowing them to refine and improve the customer experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/PJz38t6yn_s&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Business I (6:00)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/fESm-2Vox9M&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Business II (7:34)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/fcvn-IxPO00&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Business III (9:37)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/news/features/2012/mar12/03-05CloudComputingJobs.aspx&#34;&gt;http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/news/features/2012/mar12/03-05CloudComputingJobs.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mckinsey.com/mgi/publications/big_data/index.asp&#34;&gt;http://www.mckinsey.com/mgi/publications/big_data/index.asp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fisheritcenter.haas.berkeley.edu/Big_Data/index.html&#34;&gt;Tom
Davenport&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fisheritcenter.haas.berkeley.edu/Big_Data/index.html&#34;&gt;Anjul
Bhambhri&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://berkeleydatascience.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/20120117berkeley1.pdf&#34;&gt;Jeff
Hammerbacher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.economist.com/node/15579717&#34;&gt;http://www.economist.com/node/15579717&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cs.metrostate.edu/~sbd/slides/Sun.pdf&#34;&gt;http://cs.metrostate.edu/~sbd/slides/Sun.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jess3.com/geosocial-universe-2/&#34;&gt;http://jess3.com/geosocial-universe-2/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fisheritcenter.haas.berkeley.edu/Big_Data/index.html&#34;&gt;Bill
Ruh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hsph.harvard.edu/ncb2011/files/ncb2011-z03-rodriguez.pptx&#34;&gt;http://www.hsph.harvard.edu/ncb2011/files/ncb2011-z03-rodriguez.pptx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fisheritcenter.haas.berkeley.edu/Big_Data/index.html&#34;&gt;Hugh
Williams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-deluge-and-scientific-applications-and-methodology&#34;&gt;Data Deluge and Scientific Applications and Methodology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;overview-of-data-science&#34;&gt;Overview of Data Science&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We continue the discussion of the data deluge with a focus on scientific
research. He takes a first peek at data from the Large Hadron Collider
considered later as physics Informatics and gives some biology examples.
He discusses the implication of data for the scientific method which is
changing with the data-intensive methodology joining observation, theory
and simulation as basic methods. We discuss the long tail of sciences;
many users with individually modest data adding up to a lot. The last
lesson emphasizes how everyday devices ~~ the Internet of Things ~~
are being used to create a wealth of data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B88HKpainTSfZzhqZHVKbllZcTA&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/presentation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Presentation&#34;&gt; Methodology
(22)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;science-and-research&#34;&gt;Science and Research&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look into more big data examples with a focus on science and
research. We give astronomy, genomics, radiology, particle physics and
discovery of Higgs particle (Covered in more detail in later lessons),
European Bioinformatics Institute and contrast to Facebook and Walmart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/u1h6bAkuWQ8&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Science and Research
(11:27)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/_JfcUg2cheg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Science and Research
(11:49)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;implications-for-scientific-method&#34;&gt;Implications for Scientific Method&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We discuss the emergencies of a new fourth methodology for scientific
research based on data driven inquiry. We contrast this with third ~~
computation or simulation based discovery - methodology which emerged
itself some 25 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/srEbOAmU_g8&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Scientific Methods (5:07)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;long-tail-of-science&#34;&gt;Long Tail of Science&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is big science such as particle physics where a single experiment
has 3000 people collaborate!.Then there are individual investigators who
do not generate a lot of data each but together they add up to Big data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/dwzEKEGYhqE&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Long Tail of Science (2:10)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;internet-of-things&#34;&gt;Internet of Things&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A final category of Big data comes from the Internet of Things where
lots of small devices ~~ smart phones, web cams, video games collect
and disseminate data and are controlled and coordinated in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/K2anbyxX48w&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Internet of Things (5:45)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;resources-1&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.economist.com/node/15579717&#34;&gt;http://www.economist.com/node/15579717&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Geoffrey Fox and Dennis Gannon Using Clouds for Technical Computing
To be published in Proceedings of HPC 2012 Conference at Cetraro,
Italy June 28 2012&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grids.ucs.indiana.edu/ptliupages/publications/Clouds_Technical_Computing_FoxGannonv2.pdf&#34;&gt;http://grids.ucs.indiana.edu/ptliupages/publications/Clouds_Technical_Computing_FoxGannonv2.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grids.ucs.indiana.edu/ptliupages/publications/Where%20does%20all%20the%20data%20come%20from%20v7.pdf&#34;&gt;http://grids.ucs.indiana.edu/ptliupages/publications/Where%20does%20all%20the%20data%20come%20from%20v7.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.genome.gov/sequencingcosts/&#34;&gt;http://www.genome.gov/sequencingcosts/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.quantumdiaries.org/2012/09/07/why-particle-detectors-need-a-trigger/atlasmgg&#34;&gt;http://www.quantumdiaries.org/2012/09/07/why-particle-detectors-need-a-trigger/atlasmgg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://salsahpc.indiana.edu/dlib/articles/00001935/&#34;&gt;http://salsahpc.indiana.edu/dlib/articles/00001935/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Simple_linear_regression&#34;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Simple_linear_regression&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ebi.ac.uk/Information/Brochures/&#34;&gt;http://www.ebi.ac.uk/Information/Brochures/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wired.com/wired/issue/16-07&#34;&gt;http://www.wired.com/wired/issue/16-07&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://research.microsoft.com/en-us/collaboration/fourthparadigm/&#34;&gt;http://research.microsoft.com/en-us/collaboration/fourthparadigm/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/site/opensourceiotcloud/&#34;&gt;CSTI General Assembly 2012, Washington, D.C., USA Technical
Activities Coordinating Committee (TACC) Meeting, Data Management,
Cloud Computing and the Long Tail of Science October 2012 Dennis
Gannon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;clouds-and-big-data-processing-data-science-process-and-analytics&#34;&gt;Clouds and Big Data Processing; Data Science Process and Analytics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;overview-of-data-science-1&#34;&gt;Overview of Data Science&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We give an initial technical overview of cloud computing as pioneered by
companies like Amazon, Google and Microsoft with new centers holding up
to a million servers. The benefits of Clouds in terms of power
consumption and the environment are also touched upon, followed by a
list of the most critical features of Cloud computing with a comparison
to supercomputing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He discusses features of the data deluge with a salutary example where
more data did better than more thought. He introduces data science and
one part of it ~~ data analytics ~~ the large algorithms that crunch
the big data to give big wisdom. There are many ways to describe data
science and several are discussed to give a good composite picture of
this emerging field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B88HKpainTSfV1FwdktnbTl3T1k&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/presentation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Presentation&#34;&gt; Clouds
(35)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;clouds&#34;&gt;Clouds&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We describe cloud data centers with their staggering size with up to a
million servers in a single data center and centers built modularly from
shipping containers full of racks. The benefits of Clouds in terms of
power consumption and the environment are also touched upon, followed by
a list of the most critical features of Cloud computing and a comparison
to supercomputing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=trIFW-rucgM&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Clouds
(16:04)&lt;/a&gt;{MP4}&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;aspect-of-data-deluge&#34;&gt;Aspect of Data Deluge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data, Information, intelligence algorithms, infrastructure, data
structure, semantics and knowledge are related. The semantic web and Big
data are compared. We give an example where &amp;ldquo;More data usually beats
better algorithms&amp;rdquo;. We discuss examples of intelligent big data and list
8 different types of data deluge&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/FMktnTQGyrw&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Data Deluge (8:02)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/QNVZobXHiZw&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Data Deluge (6:24)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-science-process-1&#34;&gt;Data Science Process&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We describe and critique one view of the work of a data scientists. Then
we discuss and contrast 7 views of the process needed to speed data
through the DIKW pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/lpQ-Q9ZidR4&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Scientific Process (11:28)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-analytics&#34;&gt;Data Analytics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://archive2.cra.org/ccc/files/docs/nitrdsymposium/keyes.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/presentation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Presentation&#34;&gt; Data Analytics
(30)&lt;/a&gt;
We stress the importance of data analytics givi ng examples from several
fields. We note that better analytics is as important as better
computing and storage capability. In the second video we look at High
Performance Computing in Science and Engineering: the Tree and the
Fruit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/RPVojR8jrb8&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Data Analytics (7:28)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/wOSgywqdJDY&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Data Analytics (6:51)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;resources-2&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CSTI General Assembly 2012, Washington, D.C., USA Technical
Activities Coordinating Committee (TACC) Meeting, Data Management,
Cloud Computing and the Long Tail of Science October 2012 Dennis
Gannon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dan Reed Roger Barga Dennis Gannon Rich
Wolski
&lt;a href=&#34;http://research.microsoft.com/en-us/people/barga/sc09%5C_cloudcomp_tutorial.pdf&#34;&gt;http://research.microsoft.com/en-us/people/barga/sc09\_cloudcomp_tutorial.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.datacenterknowledge.com/archives/2011/05/10/uptime-institute-the-average-pue-is-1-8/&#34;&gt;http://www.datacenterknowledge.com/archives/2011/05/10/uptime-institute-the-average-pue-is-1-8/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://loosebolts.wordpress.com/2008/12/02/our-vision-for-generation-4-modular-data-centers-one-way-of-getting-it-just-right/&#34;&gt;http://loosebolts.wordpress.com/2008/12/02/our-vision-for-generation-4-modular-data-centers-one-way-of-getting-it-just-right/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mediafire.com/file/zzqna34282frr2f/koomeydatacenterelectuse2011finalversion.pdf&#34;&gt;http://www.mediafire.com/file/zzqna34282frr2f/koomeydatacenterelectuse2011finalversion.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cse.buffalo.edu/~bina/cse487/fall2011/&#34;&gt;Bina Ramamurthy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://berkeleydatascience.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/20120117berkeley1.pdf&#34;&gt;Jeff
Hammerbacher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://berkeleydatascience.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/20120119berkeley.pdf&#34;&gt;Jeff
Hammerbacher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fisheritcenter.haas.berkeley.edu/Big_Data/index.html&#34;&gt;Anjul
Bhambhri&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cs.metrostate.edu/~sbd/slides/Sun.pdf&#34;&gt;http://cs.metrostate.edu/~sbd/slides/Sun.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fisheritcenter.haas.berkeley.edu/Big_Data/index.html&#34;&gt;Hugh
Williams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fisheritcenter.haas.berkeley.edu/Big_Data/index.html&#34;&gt;Tom
Davenport&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mckinsey.com/mgi/publications/big_data/index.asp&#34;&gt;http://www.mckinsey.com/mgi/publications/big_data/index.asp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cra.org/ccc/docs/nitrdsymposium/pdfs/keyes.pdf&#34;&gt;http://cra.org/ccc/docs/nitrdsymposium/pdfs/keyes.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modules: Physics</title>
      <link>/modules/bigdataapplications/2020/applications/physics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/bigdataapplications/2020/applications/physics/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;This section starts by describing the LHC accelerator at CERN and
evidence found by the experiments suggesting existence of a Higgs Boson.
The huge number of authors on a paper, remarks on histograms and Feynman
diagrams is followed by an accelerator picture gallery. The next unit is
devoted to Python experiments looking at histograms of Higgs Boson
production with various forms of shape of signal and various background
and with various event totals. Then random variables and some simple
principles of statistics are introduced with explanation as to why they
are relevant to Physics counting experiments. The unit introduces
Gaussian (normal) distributions and explains why they seen so often in
natural phenomena. Several Python illustrations are given. Random
Numbers with their Generators and Seeds lead to a discussion of Binomial
and Poisson Distribution. Monte-Carlo and accept-reject methods. The
Central Limit Theorem concludes discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;looking-for-higgs-particles&#34;&gt;Looking for Higgs Particles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bumps-in-histograms-experiments-and-accelerators&#34;&gt;Bumps in Histograms, Experiments and Accelerators&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This unit is devoted to Python and Java experiments looking at
histograms of Higgs Boson production with various forms of shape of
signal and various background and with various event totals. The
lectures use Python but use of Java is described.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B8936_ytjfjmYXNoM3ZadGR6QlE&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/presentation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Presentation&#34;&gt;
Higgs (20)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;{gitcode}/physics/mr-higgs/higgs-classI-sloping.py&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;particle-counting&#34;&gt;Particle Counting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We return to particle case with slides used in introduction and stress
that particles often manifested as bumps in histograms and those bumps
need to be large enough to stand out from background in a statistically
significant fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iaypHlgFyuU&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Discovery of Higgs Particle
(13:49)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We give a few details on one LHC experiment ATLAS. Experimental physics
papers have a staggering number of authors and quite big budgets.
Feynman diagrams describe processes in a fundamental fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/UAMzmOgjj7I&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Looking for Higgs Particle and Counting Introduction II
(7:38)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;experimental-facilities&#34;&gt;Experimental Facilities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We give a few details on one LHC experiment ATLAS. Experimental physics
papers have a staggering number of authors and quite big budgets.
Feynman diagrams describe processes in a fundamental fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/BW12d780qT8&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Looking for Higgs Particle Experiments
(9:29)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;accelerator-picture-gallery-of-big-science&#34;&gt;Accelerator Picture Gallery of Big Science&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson gives a small picture gallery of accelerators. Accelerators,
detection chambers and magnets in tunnels and a large underground
laboratory used fpr experiments where you need to be shielded from
background like cosmic rays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/WLJIxWWMYi8&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Accelerator Picture Gallery of Big Science
(11:21)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grids.ucs.indiana.edu/ptliupages/publications/Where%20does%20all%20the%20data%20come%20from%20v7.pdf&#34;&gt;http://grids.ucs.indiana.edu/ptliupages/publications/Where%20does%20all%20the%20data%20come%20from%20v7.pdf&lt;/a&gt; [@fox2011does]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S037026931200857X&#34;&gt;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S037026931200857X&lt;/a&gt; [@aad2012observation]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nature.com/news/specials/lhc/interactive.html&#34;&gt;http://www.nature.com/news/specials/lhc/interactive.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking for Higgs Particles: Python Event Counting for Signal and
Background (Part 2)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This unit is devoted to Python experiments looking at histograms of
Higgs Boson production with various forms of shape of signal and various
background and with various event totals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B8936_ytjfjmUHRpV2g2V28walE&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/presentation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Presentation&#34;&gt; Higgs II
(29)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Files:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;lt;{gitcode}/physics/mr-higgs/higgs-classI-sloping.py&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;lt;{gitcode}/physics/number-theory/higgs-classIII.py&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;lt;{gitcode}/physics/mr-higgs/higgs-classII-uniform.py&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;event-counting&#34;&gt;Event Counting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We define &lt;em&gt;event counting&lt;/em&gt; data collection environments. We discuss the
python and Java code to generate events according to a particular
scenario (the important idea of Monte Carlo data). Here a sloping
background plus either a Higgs particle generated similarly to LHC
observation or one observed with better resolution (smaller measurement
error).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/h8-szCeFugQ&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Event Counting (7:02)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;monte-carlo&#34;&gt;Monte Carlo&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This uses Monte Carlo data both to generate data like the experimental
observations and explore effect of changing amount of data and changing
measurement resolution for Higgs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/bl2f0tAzLj4&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; With Python examples of Signal plus Background
(7:33)&lt;/a&gt; This lesson continues the
examination of Monte Carlo data looking at effect of change in
number of Higgs particles produced and in change in shape of
background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/bw3fd5cfQhk&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Change shape of background &amp;amp; num of Higgs Particles
(7:01)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;resources-1&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python for Data Analysis: Agile Tools for Real World Data By Wes
McKinney, Publisher: O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Media, Released: October 2012,
Pages: 472. [@mckinney-python]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jwork.org/scavis/api/&#34;&gt;http://jwork.org/scavis/api/&lt;/a&gt; [@jwork-api]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DataMelt&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DataMelt&lt;/a&gt; [@wikipedia-datamelt]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;random-variables-physics-and-normal-distributions&#34;&gt;Random Variables, Physics and Normal Distributions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We introduce random variables and some simple principles of statistics
and explains why they are relevant to Physics counting experiments. The
unit introduces Gaussian (normal) distributions and explains why they
seen so often in natural phenomena. Several Python illustrations are
given. Java is currently not available in this unit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B8936_ytjfjmNWhrS0xadk16SWM&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/presentation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Presentation&#34;&gt;
Higgs (39)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;lt;{gitcode}/physics/number-theory/higgs-classIII.py&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;statistics-overview-and-fundamental-idea-random-variables&#34;&gt;Statistics Overview and Fundamental Idea: Random Variables&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We go through the many different areas of statistics covered in the
Physics unit. We define the statistics concept of a random variable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_sLGyt4qWWk&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Random variables and normal distributions
(8:19)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;physics-and-random-variables&#34;&gt;Physics and Random Variables&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We describe the DIKW pipeline for the analysis of this type of physics
experiment and go through details of analysis pipeline for the LHC ATLAS
experiment. We give examples of event displays showing the final state
particles seen in a few events. We illustrate how physicists decide
whats going on with a plot of expected Higgs production experimental
cross sections (probabilities) for signal and background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/Tn3GBxgplxg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Physics and Random Variables I
(8:34)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/qWEjp0OtvdA&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Physics and Random Variables II
(5:50)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;statistics-of-events-with-normal-distributions&#34;&gt;Statistics of Events with Normal Distributions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We introduce Poisson and Binomial distributions and define independent
identically distributed (IID) random variables. We give the law of large
numbers defining the errors in counting and leading to Gaussian
distributions for many things. We demonstrate this in Python
experiments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/LMBtpWOOQLo&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Statistics of Events with Normal Distributions
(11:25)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gaussian-distributions&#34;&gt;Gaussian Distributions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We introduce the Gaussian distribution and give Python examples of the
fluctuations in counting Gaussian distributions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/LWIbPa-P5W0&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Gaussian Distributions
(9:08)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;using-statistics&#34;&gt;Using Statistics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We discuss the significance of a standard deviation and role of biases
and insufficient statistics with a Python example in getting incorrect
answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/n4jlUrGwgic&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Using Statistics (14:02)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;resources-2&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://indico.cern.ch/event/20453/session/6/contribution/15?materialId=slides&#34;&gt;http://indico.cern.ch/event/20453/session/6/contribution/15?materialId=slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.atlas.ch/photos/events.html&#34;&gt;http://www.atlas.ch/photos/events.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt; (this link is outdated)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cms.cern/&#34;&gt;https://cms.cern/&lt;/a&gt; [@cms]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;random-numbers-distributions-and-central-limit-theorem&#34;&gt;Random Numbers, Distributions and Central Limit Theorem&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We discuss Random Numbers with their Generators and Seeds. It introduces
Binomial and Poisson Distribution. Monte-Carlo and accept-reject methods
are discussed. The Central Limit Theorem and Bayes law concludes
discussion. Python and Java (for student - not reviewed in class)
examples and Physics applications are given.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B8936_ytjfjmTUxkZXVRRmlBSUk&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/presentation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Presentation&#34;&gt; Higgs
III (44)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Files:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;lt;{gitcode}/physics/calculated-dice-roll/higgs-classIV-seeds.py&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;generators-and-seeds&#34;&gt;Generators and Seeds&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We define random numbers and describe how to generate them on the
computer giving Python examples. We define the seed used to define to
specify how to start generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=de4AQ9AFt54&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Higgs Particle Counting Errors
(6:28)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/9QY5qkQj2Ag&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Generators and Seeds II
(7:10)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;binomial-distribution&#34;&gt;Binomial Distribution&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We define binomial distribution and give LHC data as an example of where
this distribution valid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/DPd-eVI_twQ&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Binomial Distribution:
(12:38)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;accept-reject&#34;&gt;Accept-Reject&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We introduce an advanced method &lt;strong&gt;accept/reject&lt;/strong&gt; for generating random
variables with arbitrary distributions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/GfshkKMKCj8&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Accept-Reject (5:54)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;monte-carlo-method&#34;&gt;Monte Carlo Method&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We define Monte Carlo method which usually uses accept/reject method in
typical case for distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/kIQ-BTyDfOQ&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Monte Carlo Method (2:23)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;poisson-distribution&#34;&gt;Poisson Distribution&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We extend the Binomial to the Poisson distribution and give a set of
amusing examples from Wikipedia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/WFvgsVo-k4s&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Poisson Distribution (4:37)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;central-limit-theorem&#34;&gt;Central Limit Theorem&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We introduce Central Limit Theorem and give examples from Wikipedia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/ZO53iKlPn7c&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Central Limit Theorem
(4:47)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;interpretation-of-probability-bayes-v-frequency&#34;&gt;Interpretation of Probability: Bayes v. Frequency&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson describes difference between Bayes and frequency views of
probability. Bayes&amp;rsquo;s law of conditional probability is derived and
applied to Higgs example to enable information about Higgs from multiple
channels and multiple experiments to be accumulated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/jzDkExAQI9M&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Interpretation of Probability
(12:39)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;resources-3&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\TODO{integrate physics-references.bib}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ska----square-kilometer-array&#34;&gt;SKA &amp;ndash; Square Kilometer Array&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professor Diamond, accompanied by Dr. Rosie Bolton from the SKA Regional
Centre Project gave a presentation at SC17 &amp;ldquo;into the deepest reaches of
the observable universe as they describe the SKA&amp;rsquo;s international
partnership that will map and study the entire sky in greater detail
than ever before.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sc17.supercomputing.org/presentation/?id=inspkr101&amp;amp;sess=sess263&#34;&gt;http://sc17.supercomputing.org/presentation/?id=inspkr101&amp;amp;sess=sess263&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A summary article about this effort is available at:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hpcwire.com/2017/11/17/sc17-keynote-hpc-powers-ska-efforts-peer-deep-cosmos/&#34;&gt;https://www.hpcwire.com/2017/11/17/sc17-keynote-hpc-powers-ska-efforts-peer-deep-cosmos/&lt;/a&gt;
The video is hosted at&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sc17.supercomputing.org/presentation/?id=inspkr101&amp;amp;sess=sess263&#34;&gt;http://sc17.supercomputing.org/presentation/?id=inspkr101&amp;amp;sess=sess263&lt;/a&gt;
Start at about 1:03:00 (e.g. the one hour mark)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modules: Plotviz</title>
      <link>/modules/bigdataapplications/2020/applications/plotviz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/bigdataapplications/2020/applications/plotviz/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE: This an legacy application this has now been replaced by WebPlotViz
which is a web browser based visualization tool which provides added
functionality&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We introduce Plotviz, a data visualization tool developed at Indiana
University to display 2 and 3 dimensional data. The motivation is that
the human eye is very good at pattern recognition and can &lt;em&gt;see&lt;/em&gt;
structure in data. Although most Big data is higher dimensional than 3,
all can be transformed by dimension reduction techniques to 3D. He gives
several examples to show how the software can be used and what kind of
data can be visualized. This includes individual plots and the
manipulation of multiple synchronized plots.Finally, he describes the
download and software dependency of Plotviz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;using-plotviz-software-for-displaying-point-distributions-in-3d&#34;&gt;Using Plotviz Software for Displaying Point Distributions in 3D&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We introduce Plotviz, a data visualization tool developed at Indiana
University to display 2 and 3 dimensional data. The motivation is that
the human eye is very good at pattern recognition and can &lt;em&gt;see&lt;/em&gt;
structure in data. Although most Big data is higher dimensional than 3,
all can be transformed by dimension reduction techniques to 3D. He gives
several examples to show how the software can be used and what kind of
data can be visualized. This includes individual plots and the
manipulation of multiple synchronized plots. Finally, he describes the
download and software dependency of Plotviz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iu.app.box.com/s/jypomnrz755xgps5e6iw&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/presentation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Presentation&#34;&gt; Plotviz (34)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Files:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/plotviz/fungi-lsu-3-15-to-3-26-zeroidx.pviz&#34;&gt;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/plotviz/fungi-lsu-3-15-to-3-26-zeroidx.pviz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/plotviz/datingrating-originallabels.pviz&#34;&gt;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/plotviz/datingrating-originallabels.pviz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/plotviz/clusterFinal-M30-C28.pviz&#34;&gt;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/plotviz/clusterFinal-M30-C28.pviz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/plotviz/clusterfinal-m3-c3dating-reclustered.pviz&#34;&gt;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/plotviz/clusterfinal-m3-c3dating-reclustered.pviz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;motivation-and-introduction-to-use&#34;&gt;Motivation and Introduction to use&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The motivation of Plotviz is that the human eye is very good at pattern
recognition and can &lt;em&gt;see&lt;/em&gt; structure in data. Although most Big data is
higher dimensional than 3, all data can be transformed by dimension
reduction techniques to 3D and one can check analysis like clustering
and/or see structure missed in a computer analysis. The motivations
shows some Cheminformatics examples. The use of Plotviz is started in
slide 4 with a discussion of input file which is either a simple text or
more features (like colors) can be specified in a rich XML syntax.
Plotviz deals with points and their classification (clustering). Next
the protein sequence browser in 3D shows the basic structure of Plotviz
interface. The next two slides explain the core 3D and 2D manipulations
respectively. Note all files used in examples are available to students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/4aQlCmQ1jfY&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/presentation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Presentation&#34;&gt; Motivation (7:58)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;example-of-use-i-cube-and-structured-dataset&#34;&gt;Example of Use I: Cube and Structured Dataset&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially we start with a simple plot of 8 points &amp;ndash; the corners of a
cube in 3 dimensions &amp;ndash; showing basic operations such as
size/color/labels and Legend of points. The second example shows a
dataset (coming from GTM dimension reduction) with significant
structure. This has .pviz and a .txt versions that are compared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/nCTT5mI_j_Q&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/presentation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Presentation&#34;&gt; Example I (9:45)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;example-of-use-ii-proteomics-and-synchronized-rotation&#34;&gt;Example of Use II: Proteomics and Synchronized Rotation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This starts with an examination of a sample of Protein Universe Browser
showing how one uses Plotviz to look at different features of this set
of Protein sequences projected to 3D. Then we show how to compare two
datasets with synchronized rotation of a dataset clustered in 2
different ways; this dataset comes from k Nearest Neighbor discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/lDbIhnLrNkk&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/presentation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Presentation&#34;&gt; Proteomics and Synchronized Rotation (9:14)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;example-of-use-iii-more-features-and-larger-proteomics-sample&#34;&gt;Example of Use III: More Features and larger Proteomics Sample&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This starts by describing use of Labels and Glyphs and the Default mode
in Plotviz. Then we illustrate sophisticated use of these ideas to view
a large Proteomics dataset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/KBkUW_QNSvs&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/presentation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Presentation&#34;&gt; Larger Proteomics Sample (8:37)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;example-of-use-iv-tools-and-examples&#34;&gt;Example of Use IV: Tools and Examples&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson starts by describing the Plotviz tools and then sets up two
examples &amp;ndash; Oil Flow and Trading &amp;ndash; described in PowerPoint. It finishes
with the Plotviz viewing of Oil Flow data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/zp_709imR40&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/presentation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Presentation&#34;&gt; Plotviz I (10:17)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;example-of-use-v-final-examples&#34;&gt;Example of Use V: Final Examples&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This starts with Plotviz looking at Trading example introduced in
previous lesson and then examines solvent data. It finishes with two
large biology examples with 446K and 100K points and each with over 100
clusters. We finish remarks on Plotviz software structure and how to
download. We also remind you that a picture is worth a 1000 words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/FKoCfTJ_cDM&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Plotviz II (14:58)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://salsahpc.indiana.edu/pviz3/&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modules: Practical K-Means, Map Reduce, and Page Rank for Big Data Applications and Analytics</title>
      <link>/modules/bigdataapplications/2020/applications/kmeans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/bigdataapplications/2020/applications/kmeans/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;We use the K-means Python code in SciPy package to show real code for
clustering. After a simple example we generate 4 clusters of distinct
centers and various choice for sizes using Matplotlib tor visualization.
We show results can sometimes be incorrect and sometimes make different
choices among comparable solutions. We discuss the &lt;em&gt;hill&lt;/em&gt; between
different solutions and rationale for running K-means many times and
choosing best answer. Then we introduce MapReduce with the basic
architecture and a homely example. The discussion of advanced topics
includes an extension to Iterative MapReduce from Indiana University
called Twister and a generalized Map Collective model. Some measurements
of parallel performance are given. The SciPy K-means code is modified to
support a MapReduce execution style. This illustrates the key ideas of
mappers and reducers. With appropriate runtime this code would run in
parallel but here the &lt;em&gt;parallel&lt;/em&gt; maps run sequentially. This simple 2
map version can be generalized to scalable parallelism. Python is used
to Calculate PageRank from Web Linkage Matrix showing several different
formulations of the basic matrix equations to finding leading
eigenvector. The unit is concluded by a calculation of PageRank for
general web pages by extracting the secret from Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I79ISV6XBbE&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; K-Means I (11:42)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Srgq9VDg4C8&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; K-Means II (11:54)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;k-means-in-practice&#34;&gt;K-means in Practice&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We introduce the k means algorithm in a gentle fashion and describes its
key features including dangers of local minima. A simple example from
Wikipedia is examined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use the K-means Python code in SciPy package to show real code for
clustering. After a simple example we generate 4 clusters of distinct
centers and various choice for sizes using Matplotlib tor visualization.
We show results can sometimes be incorrect and sometimes make different
choices among comparable solutions. We discuss the &lt;em&gt;hill&lt;/em&gt; between
different solutions and rationale for running K-means many times and
choosing best answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Files:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/kmeans/xmean.py&#34;&gt;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/kmeans/xmean.py&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/kmeans/sample.csv&#34;&gt;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/kmeans/sample.csv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/kmeans/parallel-kmeans.py&#34;&gt;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/kmeans/parallel-kmeans.py&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/kmeans/kmeans-extra.py&#34;&gt;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/kmeans/kmeans-extra.py&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;k-means-in-python&#34;&gt;K-means in Python&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use the K-means Python code in SciPy package to show real code for
clustering and applies it a set of 85 two dimensional vectors &amp;ndash;
officially sets of weights and heights to be clustered to find T-shirt
sizes. We run through Python code with Matplotlib displays to divide
into 2-5 clusters. Then we discuss Python to generate 4 clusters of
varying sizes and centered at corners of a square in two dimensions. We
formally give the K means algorithm better than before and make
definition consistent with code in SciPy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;analysis-of-4-artificial-clusters&#34;&gt;Analysis of 4 Artificial Clusters&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We present clustering results on the artificial set of 1000 2D points
described in previous lesson for 3 choices of cluster sizes &lt;em&gt;small&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;large&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;very large&lt;/em&gt;. We emphasize the SciPy always does 20
independent K means and takes the best result &amp;ndash; an approach to avoiding
local minima. We allow this number of independent runs to be changed and
in particular set to 1 to generate more interesting erratic results. We
define changes in our new K means code that also has two measures of
quality allowed. The slides give many results of clustering into 2 4 6
and 8 clusters (there were only 4 real clusters). We show that the &lt;em&gt;very
small&lt;/em&gt; case has two very different solutions when clustered into two
clusters and use this to discuss functions with multiple minima and a
hill between them. The lesson has both discussion of already produced
results in slides and interactive use of Python for new runs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;parallel-k-means&#34;&gt;Parallel K-means&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We modify the SciPy K-means code to support a MapReduce execution style
and runs it in this short unit. This illustrates the key ideas of
mappers and reducers. With appropriate runtime this code would run in
parallel but here the &lt;em&gt;parallel&lt;/em&gt; maps run sequentially. We stress that
this simple 2 map version can be generalized to scalable parallelism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Files:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/kmeans/parallel-kmeans.py&#34;&gt;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/kmeans/parallel-kmeans.py&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pagerank-in-practice&#34;&gt;PageRank in Practice&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use Python to Calculate PageRank from Web Linkage Matrix showing
several different formulations of the basic matrix equations to finding
leading eigenvector. The unit is concluded by a calculation of PageRank
for general web pages by extracting the secret from Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Files:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/page-rank/pagerank1.py&#34;&gt;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/page-rank/pagerank1.py&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/page-rank/pagerank2.py&#34;&gt;https://github.com/cloudmesh-community/book/blob/master/examples/python/page-rank/pagerank2.py&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kmeans&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kmeans&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grids.ucs.indiana.edu/ptliupages/publications/DACIDR_camera_ready_v0.3.pdf&#34;&gt;http://grids.ucs.indiana.edu/ptliupages/publications/DACIDR_camera_ready_v0.3.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://salsahpc.indiana.edu/millionseq/&#34;&gt;http://salsahpc.indiana.edu/millionseq/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://salsafungiphy.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;http://salsafungiphy.blogspot.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heuristic&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heuristic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modules: Radar</title>
      <link>/modules/bigdataapplications/2020/applications/radar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/bigdataapplications/2020/applications/radar/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The changing global climate is suspected to have long-term effects on
much of the world&amp;rsquo;s inhabitants. Among the various effects, the rising
sea level will directly affect many people living in low-lying coastal
regions. While the ocean-s thermal expansion has been the dominant
contributor to rises in sea level, the potential contribution of
discharges from the polar ice sheets in Greenland and Antarctica may
provide a more significant threat due to the unpredictable response to
the changing climate. The Radar-Informatics unit provides a glimpse in
the processes fueling global climate change and explains what methods
are used for ice data acquisitions and analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B8936_ytjfjmZ0VzZ0ZIenpUMTQ&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/presentation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Presentation&#34;&gt; Radar
(58)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson motivates radar-informatics by building on previous
discussions on why X-applications are growing in data size and why
analytics are necessary for acquiring knowledge from large data. The
lesson details three mosaics of a changing Greenland ice sheet and
provides a concise overview to subsequent lessons by detailing
explaining how other remote sensing technologies, such as the radar, can
be used to sound the polar ice sheets and what we are doing with radar
images to extract knowledge to be incorporated into numerical models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/LXOncC2AhsI&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Radar Informatics (3:31)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;remote-sensing&#34;&gt;Remote Sensing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson explains the basics of remote sensing, the characteristics
of remote sensors and remote sensing applications. Emphasis is on image
acquisition and data collection in the electromagnetic spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/TTrm9rmZySQ&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Remote Sensing (6:43)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ice-sheet-science&#34;&gt;Ice Sheet Science&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson provides a brief understanding on why melt water at the base
of the ice sheet can be detrimental and why it&amp;rsquo;s important for sensors
to sound the bedrock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/rDpjMLguVBc&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Ice Sheet Science (1:00)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;global-climate-change&#34;&gt;Global Climate Change&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson provides an understanding and the processes for the
greenhouse effect, how warming effects the Polar Regions, and the
implications of a rise in sea level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/f9hzzJX0qDs&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Global Climate Change
(2:51)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;radio-overview&#34;&gt;Radio Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson provides an elementary introduction to radar and its
importance to remote sensing, especially to acquiring information about
Greenland and Antarctica.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/PuI7F-RMKCI&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Radio Overview (4:16)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;radio-informatics&#34;&gt;Radio Informatics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson focuses on the use of sophisticated computer vision
algorithms, such as active contours and a hidden markov model to support
data analysis for extracting layers, so ice sheet models can accurately
forecast future changes in climate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/q3Pwyt49syE&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Radio Informatics (3:35)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modules: Sensors</title>
      <link>/modules/bigdataapplications/2020/applications/sensor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/bigdataapplications/2020/applications/sensor/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;We start with the Internet of Things IoT giving examples like monitors
of machine operation, QR codes, surveillance cameras, scientific
sensors, drones and self driving cars and more generally transportation
systems. We give examples of robots and drones. We introduce the
Industrial Internet of Things IIoT and summarize surveys and
expectations Industry wide. We give examples from General Electric.
Sensor clouds control the many small distributed devices of IoT and
IIoT. More detail is given for radar data gathered by sensors;
ubiquitous or smart cities and homes including U-Korea; and finally the
smart electric grid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B8936_ytjfjmVXZCUnR3TnVMMFk&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/presentation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Presentation&#34;&gt; Sensor I(31)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B8936_ytjfjmelMwSUl6Q1lLV1k&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/presentation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Presentation&#34;&gt; Sensor II(44)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;internet-of-things&#34;&gt;Internet of Things&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are predicted to be 24-50 Billion devices on the Internet by 2020;
these are typically some sort of sensor defined as any source or sink of
time series data. Sensors include smartphones, webcams, monitors of
machine operation, barcodes, surveillance cameras, scientific sensors
(especially in earth and environmental science), drones and self driving
cars and more generally transportation systems. The lesson gives many
examples of distributed sensors, which form a Grid that is controlled by
a cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0O0-mz-CWtQ&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Internet of Things (12:36)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;robotics-and-iot&#34;&gt;Robotics and IoT&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples of Robots and Drones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ABP0Yygw2Zg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Robotics and IoT Expectations (8:05)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;industrial-internet-of-things&#34;&gt;Industrial Internet of Things&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We summarize surveys and expectations Industry wide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kxKzBfd62Og&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Industrial Internet of Things (24:02)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sensor-clouds&#34;&gt;Sensor Clouds&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We describe the architecture of a Sensor Cloud control environment and
gives example of interface to an older version of it. The performance of
system is measured in terms of processing latency as a function of
number of involved sensors with each delivering data at 1.8 Mbps rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/0egT1FsVGrU&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Sensor Clouds (4:40)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;earthenvironmentpolar-science-data-gathered-by-sensors&#34;&gt;Earth/Environment/Polar Science data gathered by Sensors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson gives examples of some sensors in the
Earth/Environment/Polar Science field. It starts with material from the
CReSIS polar remote sensing project and then looks at the NSF Ocean
Observing Initiative and NASA&amp;rsquo;s MODIS or Moderate Resolution Imaging
Spectroradiometer instrument on a satellite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/CS2gX7axWfI&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Earth/Environment/Polar Science data gathered by Sensors
(4:58)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ubiquitoussmart-cities&#34;&gt;Ubiquitous/Smart Cities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Ubiquitous/Smart cities we give two examples: Iniquitous Korea and
smart electrical grids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/MFFIItQ3SOo&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Ubiquitous/Smart Cities (1:44)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;u-korea-uubiquitous&#34;&gt;U-Korea (U=Ubiquitous)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Korea has an interesting positioning where it is first worldwide in
broadband access per capita, e-government, scientific literacy and total
working hours. However it is far down in measures like quality of life
and GDP. U-Korea aims to improve the latter by Pervasive computing,
everywhere, anytime i.e. by spreading sensors everywhere. The example of
a &amp;lsquo;High-Tech Utopia&amp;rsquo; New Songdo is given.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U38zWbSI2n4&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; U-Korea (U=Ubiquitous) (2:49)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;smart-grid&#34;&gt;Smart Grid&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The electrical Smart Grid aims to enhance USA&amp;rsquo;s aging electrical
infrastructure by pervasive deployment of sensors and the integration of
their measurement in a cloud or equivalent server infrastructure. A
variety of new instruments include smart meters, power monitors, and
measures of solar irradiance, wind speed, and temperature. One goal is
autonomous local power units where good use is made of waste heat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UfEiIzaZzI8&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Smart Grid (6:04)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\TODO{These resources have not all been checked to see if they still
exist this is currently in progress}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.accenture.com/SiteCollectionDocuments/PDF/Accenture-Industrial-Internet-Changing-Competitive-Landscape-Industries.pdf&#34;&gt;http://www.accenture.com/SiteCollectionDocuments/PDF/Accenture-Industrial-Internet-Changing-Competitive-Landscape-Industries.pdf&lt;/a&gt; [@www-accenture-insight-industrial]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gesoftware.com/ge-predictivity-infographic&#34;&gt;http://www.gesoftware.com/ge-predictivity-infographic&lt;/a&gt; [@www-predix-ge-Industrial]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.getransportation.com/railconnect360/rail-landscape&#34;&gt;http://www.getransportation.com/railconnect360/rail-landscape&lt;/a&gt; [@www-getransportation-digital]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gesoftware.com/sites/default/files/GE-Software-Modernizing-Machine-to-Machine-Interactions.pdf&#34;&gt;http://www.gesoftware.com/sites/default/files/GE-Software-Modernizing-Machine-to-Machine-Interactions.pdf&lt;/a&gt; [@www-ge-digital-software]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These resources do not exsit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gesoftware.com/minds-and-machines&#34;&gt;https://www.gesoftware.com/minds-and-machines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gesoftware.com/predix&#34;&gt;https://www.gesoftware.com/predix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gesoftware.com/sites/default/files/the-industrial-internet/index.html&#34;&gt;https://www.gesoftware.com/sites/default/files/the-industrial-internet/index.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.cisco.com/site/eiot/discover/overview/&#34;&gt;https://developer.cisco.com/site/eiot/discover/overview/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modules: Sports</title>
      <link>/modules/bigdataapplications/2020/applications/sport/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/bigdataapplications/2020/applications/sport/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Sports sees significant growth in analytics with pervasive statistics
shifting to more sophisticated measures. We start with baseball as game
is built around segments dominated by individuals where detailed
(video/image) achievement measures including PITCHf/x and FIELDf/x are
moving field into big data arena. There are interesting relationships
between the economics of sports and big data analytics. We look at
Wearables and consumer sports/recreation. The importance of spatial
visualization is discussed. We look at other Sports: Soccer, Olympics,
NFL Football, Basketball, Tennis and Horse Racing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;basic-sabermetrics&#34;&gt;Basic Sabermetrics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This unit discusses baseball starting with the movie Moneyball and the
2002-2003 Oakland Athletics. Unlike sports like basketball and soccer,
most baseball action is built around individuals often interacting in
pairs. This is much easier to quantify than many player phenomena in
other sports. We discuss Performance-Dollar relationship including new
stadiums and media/advertising. We look at classic baseball averages and
sophisticated measures like Wins Above Replacement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B8936_ytjfjmbWt6bGZuTFJ4TFE&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/presentation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Presentation&#34;&gt; Overview
(40)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction-and-sabermetrics-baseball-informatics-lesson&#34;&gt;Introduction and Sabermetrics (Baseball Informatics) Lesson&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduction to all Sports Informatics, Moneyball The 2002-2003 Oakland
Athletics, Diamond Dollars economic model of baseball, Performance -
Dollar relationship, Value of a Win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Dd4zV__G5Q8&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Introduction and Sabermetrics (Baseball Informatics) Lesson
(31:4)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;basic-sabermetrics-1&#34;&gt;Basic Sabermetrics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Different Types of Baseball Data, Sabermetrics, Overview of all data,
Details of some statistics based on basic data, OPS, wOBA, ERA, ERC,
FIP, UZR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=L0X-RQJZKrs&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Basic Sabermetrics
(26:53)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;wins-above-replacement&#34;&gt;Wins Above Replacement&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wins above Replacement WAR, Discussion of Calculation, Examples,
Comparisons of different methods, Coefficient of Determination, Another,
Sabermetrics Example, Summary of Sabermetrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=D6PHqPor4LA&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Wins Above Replacement
(30:43)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;advanced-sabermetrics&#34;&gt;Advanced Sabermetrics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This unit discusses &amp;lsquo;advanced sabermetrics&amp;rsquo; covering advances possible
from using video from PITCHf/X, FIELDf/X, HITf/X, COMMANDf/X and MLBAM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B8936_ytjfjmUDh0Y01GbW9tWnc&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/presentation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Presentation&#34;&gt; Sporta II
(41)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pitching-clustering&#34;&gt;Pitching Clustering&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Big Data Pitcher Clustering method introduced by Vince Gennaro, Data
from Blog and video at 2013 SABR conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rZ9-b54aEvw&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Pitching Clustering
(20:59)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pitcher-quality&#34;&gt;Pitcher Quality&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results of optimizing match ups, Data from video at 2013 SABR
conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OkkUaySvXOY&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Pitcher Quality
(10:02)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pitchfx&#34;&gt;PITCHf/X&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples of use of PITCHf/X.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=m7IXhsHgQmE&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; PITCHf/X
(10:39)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-video-data-gathering-in-baseball&#34;&gt;Other Video Data Gathering in Baseball&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FIELDf/X, MLBAM, HITf/X, COMMANDf/X.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nKZiOOGccms&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Other Video Data Gathering in Baseball
(18:5)&lt;/a&gt; Other Sports&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look at Wearables and consumer sports/recreation. The importance of
spatial visualization is discussed. We look at other Sports: Soccer,
Olympics, NFL Football, Basketball, Tennis and Horse Racing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B8936_ytjfjmUGdpUzFaRzhyWXM&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/presentation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Presentation&#34;&gt; Sport Sports III
(44)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;wearables&#34;&gt;Wearables&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consumer Sports, Stake Holders, and Multiple Factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=F_cPq6xIXw0&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Wearables
(22:2)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;soccer-and-the-olympics&#34;&gt;Soccer and the Olympics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soccer, Tracking Players and Balls, Olympics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AiZneaLJMTs&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Soccer and the Olympics
(8:28)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;spatial-visualization-in-nfl-and-nba&#34;&gt;Spatial Visualization in NFL and NBA&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NFL, NBA, and Spatial Visualization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Uorh3RJLC1s&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Spatial Visualization in NFL and NBA
(15:19)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tennis-and-horse-racing&#34;&gt;Tennis and Horse Racing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tennis, Horse Racing, and Continued Emphasis on Spatial Visualization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2P-pismFSrI&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Tennis and Horse Racing
(8:52)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\TODO{These resources have not all been checked to see if they still
exist this is currently in progress}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/Tricon_Infotech/big-data-for-big-sports&#34;&gt;http://www.slideshare.net/Tricon_Infotech/big-data-for-big-sports&lt;/a&gt; [@www-slideshare-tricon-infotech]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/BrandEmotivity/sports-analytics-innovation-summit-data-powered-storytelling&#34;&gt;http://www.slideshare.net/BrandEmotivity/sports-analytics-innovation-summit-data-powered-storytelling&lt;/a&gt; [@www-slideshare-sports]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/elew/sport-analytics-innovation&#34;&gt;http://www.slideshare.net/elew/sport-analytics-innovation&lt;/a&gt; [@www-slideshare-elew-sport-analytics]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wired.com/2013/02/catapault-smartball/&#34;&gt;http://www.wired.com/2013/02/catapault-smartball/&lt;/a&gt; [@www-wired-smartball]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sloansportsconference.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/Automated_Playbook_Generation.pdf&#34;&gt;http://www.sloansportsconference.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/Automated_Playbook_Generation.pdf&lt;/a&gt; [@www-sloansportsconference-automated-playbook]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://autoscout.adsc.illinois.edu/publications/football-trajectory-dataset/&#34;&gt;http://autoscout.adsc.illinois.edu/publications/football-trajectory-dataset/&lt;/a&gt; [@www-autoscout-illinois-football-trajectory]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sloansportsconference.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/Goldsberry_Sloan_Submission.pdf&#34;&gt;http://www.sloansportsconference.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/Goldsberry_Sloan_Submission.pdf&lt;/a&gt; [@sloansportconference-goldsberry]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gamesetmap.com/&#34;&gt;http://gamesetmap.com/&lt;/a&gt; [@gamesetmap]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/BrandEmotivity/sports-analytics-innovation-summit-data-powered-storytelling&#34;&gt;http://www.slideshare.net/BrandEmotivity/sports-analytics-innovation-summit-data-powered-storytelling&lt;/a&gt; [@www-slideshare-sports-datapowered]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sloansportsconference.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.sloansportsconference.com/&lt;/a&gt; [@www-sloansportsconferences]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sabr.org/&#34;&gt;http://sabr.org/&lt;/a&gt; [@www-sabr]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sabermetrics&#34;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sabermetrics&lt;/a&gt; [@wikipedia-Sabermetrics]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baseball_statistics&#34;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baseball_statistics&lt;/a&gt; [@www-wikipedia-baseball-statistics]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://m.mlb.com/news/article/68514514/mlbam-introduces-new-way-to-analyze-every-play&#34;&gt;http://m.mlb.com/news/article/68514514/mlbam-introduces-new-way-to-analyze-every-play&lt;/a&gt; [@www-mlb-mlbam-new-way-play]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fangraphs.com/library/offense/offensive-statistics-list/&#34;&gt;http://www.fangraphs.com/library/offense/offensive-statistics-list/&lt;/a&gt; [@www-fangraphs-offensive-statistics]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Component_ERA&#34;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Component_ERA&lt;/a&gt; [@www-wiki-component-era]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fangraphs.com/library/pitching/fip/&#34;&gt;http://www.fangraphs.com/library/pitching/fip/&lt;/a&gt; [@www-fangraphs-pitching-fip]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wins_Above_Replacement&#34;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wins_Above_Replacement&lt;/a&gt; [@www-wiki-wins-above-replacement]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fangraphs.com/library/misc/war/&#34;&gt;http://www.fangraphs.com/library/misc/war/&lt;/a&gt; [@www-fangraphs-library-war]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.baseball-reference.com/about/war_explained.shtml&#34;&gt;http://www.baseball-reference.com/about/war_explained.shtml&lt;/a&gt; [@www-baseball-references-war-explained]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.baseball-reference.com/about/war_explained_comparison.shtml&#34;&gt;http://www.baseball-reference.com/about/war_explained_comparison.shtml&lt;/a&gt; [@www-baseball-references-war-explained-comparison]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.baseball-reference.com/about/war_explained_position.shtml&#34;&gt;http://www.baseball-reference.com/about/war_explained_position.shtml&lt;/a&gt; [@www-baseball-reference-war-explained-position]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.baseball-reference.com/about/war_explained_pitch.shtml&#34;&gt;http://www.baseball-reference.com/about/war_explained_pitch.shtml&lt;/a&gt; [@www-baseball-reference-war-explained-pitch]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fangraphs.com/leaders.aspx?pos=all&amp;amp;stats=bat&amp;amp;lg=all&amp;amp;qual=y&amp;amp;type=8&amp;amp;season=2014&amp;amp;month=0&amp;amp;season1=1871&amp;amp;ind=0&#34;&gt;http://www.fangraphs.com/leaders.aspx?pos=all&amp;amp;stats=bat&amp;amp;lg=all&amp;amp;qual=y&amp;amp;type=8&amp;amp;season=2014&amp;amp;month=0&amp;amp;season1=1871&amp;amp;ind=0&lt;/a&gt; [@www-fangraphs-leaders-pose-qual]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://battingleadoff.com/2014/01/08/comparing-the-three-war-measures-part-ii/&#34;&gt;http://battingleadoff.com/2014/01/08/comparing-the-three-war-measures-part-ii/&lt;/a&gt; [@battingleadoff-baseball-player]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coefficient_of_determination&#34;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coefficient_of_determination&lt;/a&gt; [@www-wiki-coefficient-of-determination]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sloansportsconference.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/2014_SSAC_Data-driven-Method-for-In-game-Decision-Making.pdf&#34;&gt;http://www.sloansportsconference.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/2014_SSAC_Data-driven-Method-for-In-game-Decision-Making.pdf&lt;/a&gt; [@ganeshapillai2014data]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://courses.edx.org/courses/BUx/SABR101x/2T2014/courseware/10e616fc7649469ab4457ae18df92b20/&#34;&gt;https://courses.edx.org/courses/BUx/SABR101x/2T2014/courseware/10e616fc7649469ab4457ae18df92b20/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vincegennaro.mlblogs.com/&#34;&gt;http://vincegennaro.mlblogs.com/&lt;/a&gt; [@www-vincegennaro-mlblogs]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=H-kx-x_d0Mk&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=H-kx-x_d0Mk&lt;/a&gt; [@www-youtube-watch]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.baseballprospectus.com/article.php?articleid=13109&#34;&gt;http://www.baseballprospectus.com/article.php?articleid=13109&lt;/a&gt; [@www-baseball-prospectus-spinning-yarn]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://baseball.physics.illinois.edu/FastPFXGuide.pdf&#34;&gt;http://baseball.physics.illinois.edu/FastPFXGuide.pdf&lt;/a&gt; [@baseball-physics-PITCHf]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://baseball.physics.illinois.edu/FieldFX-TDR-GregR.pdf&#34;&gt;http://baseball.physics.illinois.edu/FieldFX-TDR-GregR.pdf&lt;/a&gt; [@baseball-physics-fieldfx]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://regressing.deadspin.com/mlb-announces-revolutionary-new-fielding-tracking-syste-1534200504&#34;&gt;http://regressing.deadspin.com/mlb-announces-revolutionary-new-fielding-tracking-syste-1534200504&lt;/a&gt; [@www-deadspin-field-tracking-syste]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grantland.com/the-triangle/mlb-advanced-media-play-tracking-bob-bowman-interview/&#34;&gt;http://grantland.com/the-triangle/mlb-advanced-media-play-tracking-bob-bowman-interview/&lt;/a&gt; [@grantland-mlb-bob-bowman]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YkjtnuNmK74&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YkjtnuNmK74&lt;/a&gt; [@www-youtube-science-home-run]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These resources do not exsit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sportvision.com/baseball&#34;&gt;http://www.sportvision.com/baseball&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sportvision.com/media/pitchfx-how-it-works&#34;&gt;http://www.sportvision.com/media/pitchfx-how-it-works&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sportvision.com/baseball/fieldfx&#34;&gt;http://www.sportvision.com/baseball/fieldfx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sportvision.com/baseball/hitfx&#34;&gt;http://www.sportvision.com/baseball/hitfx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.trakus.com/technology.asp#tNetText&#34;&gt;http://www.trakus.com/technology.asp#tNetText&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sloansportsconference.com/?page_id=481&amp;amp;sort_cate=Research%20Paper&#34;&gt;http://www.sloansportsconference.com/?page_id=481&amp;amp;sort_cate=Research%20Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.liveathos.com/apparel/app&#34;&gt;http://www.liveathos.com/apparel/app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modules: Statistics</title>
      <link>/modules/bigdataapplications/2020/applications/statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/bigdataapplications/2020/applications/statistics/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;We assume that you are familiar with elementary statistics including&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mean, minimum, maximum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;standard deviation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;probability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;distribution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;frequency distribution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gaussian distribution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bell curve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;standard normal probabilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tables (z table)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Correlation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of these terms are explained in various sections throughout our
application discussion. This includes especially the Physics section.
However these terms are so elementary that any undergraduate or highschool
book will provide you with a good introduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is expected from you to identify these terms and you can contribute
to this section with non plagiarized subsections explaining these topics
for credit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/no.png&#34; alt=&#34;No&#34;&gt; Topics identified by a :?: can be contributed by students. If you are interested,
use piazza for announcing your willingness to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Mean, minimum, maximum:&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/no.png&#34; alt=&#34;No&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;images/question.png&#34; alt=&#34;Question&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Standard deviation:&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/no.png&#34; alt=&#34;No&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;images/question.png&#34; alt=&#34;Question&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Probability:&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/no.png&#34; alt=&#34;No&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;images/question.png&#34; alt=&#34;Question&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Distribution:&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/no.png&#34; alt=&#34;No&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;images/question.png&#34; alt=&#34;Question&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Frequency distribution:&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/no.png&#34; alt=&#34;No&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;images/question.png&#34; alt=&#34;Question&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Gaussian distribution:&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/no.png&#34; alt=&#34;No&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;images/question.png&#34; alt=&#34;Question&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Bell curve:&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/no.png&#34; alt=&#34;No&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;images/question.png&#34; alt=&#34;Question&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Standard normal probabilities:&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/no.png&#34; alt=&#34;No&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;images/question.png&#34; alt=&#34;Question&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Tables (z-table):&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/no.png&#34; alt=&#34;No&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;images/question.png&#34; alt=&#34;Question&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Regression:&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/no.png&#34; alt=&#34;No&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;images/question.png&#34; alt=&#34;Question&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Correlation:&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/no.png&#34; alt=&#34;No&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;images/question.png&#34; alt=&#34;Question&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;exercise&#34;&gt;Exercise&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;E.Statistics.1:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pick a term from the previous list and define it while not plagiarizing. Create a pull request.
Coordinate on piazza as to not duplicate someone else&amp;rsquo;s contribution. Also
look into outstanding pull requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;E.Statistics.2:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pick a term from the previous list and develop a python program demonstrating it and create a pull
request for a contribution into the examples directory. Make links to the github location.
Coordinate on piazza as to not duplicate someone else&amp;rsquo;s contribution. Also
look into outstanding pull requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modules: Web Search and Text Mining</title>
      <link>/modules/bigdataapplications/2020/applications/web/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/bigdataapplications/2020/applications/web/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;This section starts with an overview of data mining and puts our study
of classification, clustering and exploration methods in context. We
examine the problem to be solved in web and text search and note the
relevance of history with libraries, catalogs and concordances. An
overview of web search is given describing the continued evolution of
search engines and the relation to the field of Information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The importance of recall, precision and diversity is discussed. The
important Bag of Words model is introduced and both Boolean queries and
the more general fuzzy indices. The important vector space model and
revisiting the Cosine Similarity as a distance in this bag follows. The
basic TF-IDF approach is dis cussed. Relevance is discussed with a
probabilistic model while the distinction between Bayesian and frequency
views of probability distribution completes this unit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We start with an overview of the different steps (data analytics) in web
search and then goes key steps in detail starting with document
preparation. An inverted index is described and then how it is prepared
for web search. The Boolean and Vector Space approach to query
processing follow. This is followed by Link Structure Analysis including
Hubs, Authorities and PageRank. The application of PageRank ideas as
reputation outside web search is covered. The web graph structure,
crawling it and issues in web advertising and search follow. The use of
clustering and topic models completes the section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;web-search-and-text-mining&#34;&gt;Web Search and Text Mining&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unit starts with the web with its size, shape (coming from the
mutual linkage of pages by URL&amp;rsquo;s) and universal power laws for number of
pages with particular number of URL&amp;rsquo;s linking out or in to page.
Information retrieval is introduced and compared to web search. A
comparison is given between semantic searches as in databases and the
full text search that is base of Web search. The origin of web search in
libraries, catalogs and concordances is summarized. DIKW &amp;ndash; Data
Information Knowledge Wisdom &amp;ndash; model for web search is discussed. Then
features of documents, collections and the important Bag of Words
representation. Queries are presented in context of an Information
Retrieval architecture. The method of judging quality of results
including recall, precision and diversity is described. A time line for
evolution of search engines is given.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boolean and Vector Space models for query including the cosine
similarity are introduced. Web Crawlers are discussed and then the steps
needed to analyze data from Web and produce a set of terms. Building and
accessing an inverted index is followed by the importance of term
specificity and how it is captured in TF-IDF. We note how frequencies
are converted into belief and relevance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B8936_ytjfjmeWVSYk9RVXcyOFk&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/presentation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Presentation&#34;&gt; Web Search and Text Mining (56)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-problem&#34;&gt;The Problem&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RFBeAWBkUsI&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Text Mining (9:56)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson starts with the web with its size, shape (coming from the
mutual linkage of pages by URL&amp;rsquo;s) and universal power laws for number of
pages with particular number of URL&amp;rsquo;s linking out or in to page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;information-retrieval&#34;&gt;Information Retrieval&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/KtWhk2cdRa4&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Information Retrieval (6:06)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Information retrieval is introduced A comparison is given between
semantic searches as in databases and the full text search that is base
of Web search. The ACM classification illustrates potential complexity
of ontologies. Some differences between web search and information
retrieval are given.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/J7D61uH5gVM&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Web Search History (5:48)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The origin of web search in libraries, catalogs and concordances is
summarized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-fundamental-principles&#34;&gt;Key Fundamental Principles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/yPFi6xFnDHE&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Principles (9:30)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson describes the DIKW &amp;ndash; Data Information Knowledge Wisdom &amp;ndash;
model for web search. Then it discusses documents, collections and the
important Bag of Words representation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;information-retrieval-web-search-components&#34;&gt;Information Retrieval (Web Search) Components&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/EGsnonXgb3Y&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Fundamental Principals of Web Search (5:06)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This describes queries in context of an Information Retrieval
architecture. The method of judging quality of results including recall,
precision and diversity is described.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;search-engines&#34;&gt;Search Engines&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/kBV-99N6f7k&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Search Engines (3:08)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This short lesson describes a time line for evolution of search engines.
The first web search approaches were directly built on Information
retrieval but in 1998 the field was changed when Google was founded and
showed the importance of URL structure as exemplified by PageRank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;boolean-and-vector-space-models&#34;&gt;Boolean and Vector Space Models&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/JzGBA0OhsIk&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Boolean and Vector Space Model (6:17)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson describes the Boolean and Vector Space models for query
including the cosine similarity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;web-crawling-and-document-preparation&#34;&gt;Web crawling and Document Preparation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/Wv-r-PJ9lro&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Web crawling and Document Preparation (4:55)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This describes a Web Crawler and then the steps needed to analyze data
from Web and produce a set of terms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;indices&#34;&gt;Indices&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/NY2SmrHoBVM&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Indices (5:44)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson describes both building and accessing an inverted index. It
describes how phrases are treated and gives details of query structure
from some early logs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tf-idf-and-probabilistic-models&#34;&gt;TF-IDF and Probabilistic Models&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/9P_HUmpselU&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; TF-IDF and Probabilistic Models (3:57)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It describes the importance of term specificity and how it is captured
in TF-IDF. It notes how frequencies are converted into belief and
relevance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;topics-in-web-search-and-text-mining&#34;&gt;Topics in Web Search and Text Mining&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B6wqDMIyK2P7YmpLbzQ0X2xpbDg%7D%7BPDF&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/presentation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Presentation&#34;&gt; Text Mining (33)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We start with an overview of the different steps (data analytics) in web
search. This is followed by Link Structure Analysis including Hubs,
Authorities and PageRank. The application of PageRank ideas as
reputation outside web search is covered. Issues in web advertising and
search follow. his leads to emerging field of computational advertising.
The use of clustering and topic models completes unit with Google News
as an example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-analytics-for-web-search&#34;&gt;Data Analytics for Web Search&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kHEFxhWwhx0&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Web Search and Text Mining II (6:11)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This short lesson describes the different steps needed in web search
including: Get the digital data (from web or from scanning); Crawl web;
Preprocess data to get searchable things (words, positions); Form
Inverted Index mapping words to documents; Rank relevance of documents
with potentially sophisticated techniques; and integrate technology to
support advertising and ways to allow or stop pages artificially
enhancing relevance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;link-structure-analysis-including-pagerank&#34;&gt;Link Structure Analysis including PageRank&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ApDu-7_1LYk&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Related Applications (17:24)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The value of links and the concepts of Hubs and Authorities are
discussed. This leads to definition of PageRank with examples.
Extensions of PageRank viewed as a reputation are discussed with journal
rankings and university department rankings as examples. There are many
extension of these ideas which are not discussed here although topic
models are covered briefly in a later lesson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;web-advertising-and-search&#34;&gt;Web Advertising and Search&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=375sY1YMk5U&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Web Advertising and Search (9:02)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internet and mobile advertising is growing fast and can be personalized
more than for traditional media. There are several advertising types
Sponsored search, Contextual ads, Display ads and different models: Cost
per viewing, cost per clicking and cost per action. This leads to
emerging field of computational advertising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;clustering-and-topic-models&#34;&gt;Clustering and Topic Models&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/95cHMyZ-TUs&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/video.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video&#34;&gt; Clustering and Topic Models (6:21)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We discuss briefly approaches to defining groups of documents. We
illustrate this for Google News and give an example that this can give
different answers from word-based analyses. We mention some work at
Indiana University on a Latent Semantic Indexing model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All resources accessed March 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://saedsayad.com/data_mining_map.htm&#34;&gt;http://saedsayad.com/data_mining_map.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://webcourse.cs.technion.ac.il/236621/Winter2011-2012/en/ho_Lectures.html&#34;&gt;http://webcourse.cs.technion.ac.il/236621/Winter2011-2012/en/ho_Lectures.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yPFi6xFnDHE&#34;&gt;The Web Graph: an
Overviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hal.archives-ouvertes.fr/file/index/docid/54458/filename/webgraph.pdf&#34;&gt;Jean-Loup Guillaume and Matthieu
Latapy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0167923612001844&#34;&gt;Constructing a reliable Web graph with information on browsing
behavior, Yiqun Liu, Yufei Xue, Danqing Xu, Rongwei Cen, Min Zhang,
Shaoping Ma, Liyun
Ru&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ifis.cs.tu-bs.de/teaching/ss-11/irws&#34;&gt;http://www.ifis.cs.tu-bs.de/teaching/ss-11/irws&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PageRank&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PageRank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/kleinerperkins/kpcb-internet-trends-2013&#34;&gt;Meeker/Wu May 29 2013 Internet Trends D11
Conference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modules: WebPlotViz</title>
      <link>/modules/bigdataapplications/2020/applications/webplotviz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/bigdataapplications/2020/applications/webplotviz/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;WebPlotViz is a browser based visualization tool developed at Indiana University.
This tool allows user to visualize 2D and 3D data points in the web browser.
WebPlotViz was developed as a succesor to the previous visualization tool PlotViz
which was a application which needed to be installed on your machine to be used.
You can find more information about PlotViz at the &lt;a href=&#34;plotviz.md&#34;&gt;PlotViz Section&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;motivation&#34;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The motivation of WebPlotViz is similar to PlotViz which is that the human eye
is very good at pattern recognition and can see structure in data. Although
most Big data is higher dimensional than 3, all data can be transformed by
dimension reduction techniques to 3D and one can check analysis like clustering
and/or see structure missed in a computer analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-use&#34;&gt;How to use&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to use WebPlotViz you need to host the application as a server, this
can be done on you local machine or a application server. The source code for
WebPlotViz can be found at the git hub repo &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/DSC-SPIDAL/WebPViz&#34;&gt;WebPlotViz git Repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However there is a online version that is hosted on Indiana university servers
that you can access and use. The online version is available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://spidal-gw.dsc.soic.indiana.edu/&#34;&gt;WebPlotViz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to use the services of WebPlotViz you would need to first create a
simple account by providing your email and a password. Once the account is
created you can login and upload files to WebPlotViz to be visualized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;uploading-files-to-webplotviz&#34;&gt;Uploading files to WebPlotViz&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While WebPlotViz does accept several file formats as inputs, we will look at the
most simple and easy to use format that users can use. Files are uploaded as
&amp;ldquo;.txt&amp;rdquo; files with the following structure. Each value is separated by a space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Index x_val y_val z_val cluster_id label&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0  0.155117377  0.011486086  -0.078151964  1  l1&lt;br&gt;
1  0.148366394  0.010782429  -0.076370584  2  l2&lt;br&gt;
2  0.170597667  -0.025115137  -0.082946074  2  l2&lt;br&gt;
3  0.136063907  -0.006670781  -0.082583441  3  l3&lt;br&gt;
4  0.158259943  0.015187686  -0.073592601  5  l5&lt;br&gt;
5  0.162483279  0.014387166  -0.085987414  5  l5&lt;br&gt;
6  0.138651632  0.013358333  -0.062633719  5  l5&lt;br&gt;
7  0.168020213  0.010742307  -0.090281011  5  l5&lt;br&gt;
8  0.15810229  0.007551404  -0.083311109  4  l4&lt;br&gt;
9  0.146878082  0.003858649  -0.071298345  4  l4&lt;br&gt;
10  0.151487542  0.011896318  -0.074281645  4  l4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have the data file properly formatted you can upload the file through
the WebPlotViz GUI. Once you login to your account you should see a Green
&amp;ldquo;Upload&amp;rdquo; button on the top left corner. Once you press it you would see a
form that would allow you to choose the file, provide a description and select a
group to which the file needs to be categorized into. If you do not want to
assign a group you can simply use the default group which is picked by default&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have uploaded the file the file should appear in the list of plots
under the heading &amp;ldquo;Artifacts&amp;rdquo;. Then you can click on the name or the &amp;ldquo;View&amp;rdquo;
link to view the plot. Clicking on &amp;ldquo;View&amp;rdquo; will directly take you to the full
view of the plot while clicking on the name will show and summary of the plot
with a smaller view of the plot (Plot controls are not available in the smaller
view). You can view how the sample dataset looks like after uploading at the
following link. @fig:webpviz-11 shows a screen shot of the plot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://spidal-gw.dsc.soic.indiana.edu/public/resultsets/2083856374&#34;&gt;11 Points WebPlotViz plot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/11_poitns_example.png&#34; alt=&#34;11 Points Plot&#34;&gt;{#fig:webpviz-11}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users can apply colors to clusters manually or choose one of the color schemes
that are provided. All the controls for the clusters are made available once
your clock on the &amp;ldquo;Cluster List&amp;rdquo; button that is located on the bottom left
corner of the plot (Third button from the left). This will pop up a window that
will allow you to control all the settings of the clusters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WebPlotViz has many features that allows the users to control and customize
the plots, Other than simple 2D/3D plots, WebPlotViz also supports time series
plots and Tree structures. The examples section will show case examples for each
of these. The data formats required for these plots are not covered here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/webplotviz_label.png&#34; alt=&#34;WebPlotViz Features labeled&#34;&gt;{#fig:webpviz-labled}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the features are labeled in @fig:webpviz-labled. Please note that @fig:webpviz-labled
shows an time series plot so the controls for playback shown in the figure are not
available in single plots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the features are descibed in the short video that is linked in the home
page of the hosted WebPlotViz site &lt;a href=&#34;https://spidal-gw.dsc.soic.indiana.edu/&#34;&gt;WebPlotViz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;examples&#34;&gt;Examples&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we will take a look at a couple of examples that were visualized using
WebPlotViz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fungi-gene-sequence-clustering-example&#34;&gt;Fungi gene sequence clustering example&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following example is a plot from clustering done on a set on fungi gene
sequence data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://spidal-gw.dsc.soic.indiana.edu/public/resultsets/703979151&#34;&gt;Fungi Gene Sequence Plot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/webplotviz_fungi.png&#34; alt=&#34;Fungi Gene Sequence&#34;&gt;{#fig:webpviz-fungi}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;stock-market-time-series-data&#34;&gt;Stock market time series data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This example shows a time series plot, the plot were created from stock market
data so certain patterns can be followed with companies with passing years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://spidal-gw.dsc.soic.indiana.edu/public/timeseriesview/685408334&#34;&gt;Stock market data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/webplotviz_stock.png&#34; alt=&#34;Stock market data&#34;&gt;{#fig:webpviz-stock}&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
